<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		EP0675495A2
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		EP1995104321
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		A2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Detecting scene changes in encoded video sequences
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Encoded video sequences are processed prior to complete decoding. Scene changes are readily detected using DCT coefficients in JPEG and MPEG encoded video sequences. Within each 8x8 block, the distribution of the DCT coefficients is used to classify the block as either type O (contains no high frequency components) or type 1 (contains high frequency components) The changes in the distributions of O's and 1's from one frame to next is captured using eigenvectors and used to represent scene changes. The frames in between two consecutive scene changes form a video shot. Video shots may be thought of as the building blocks of video sequences, and are used in browsing, database indexing, or any other operations that essentially form an abstraction of the video. To visualize each video shot, the contents are abstracted in a meaningful manner such that it is the representative of the contents of the shot; this is achieved using representative frames or Rframes.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		EP | EPA | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		1995-03-23
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		1995
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		1995-03
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		1995-10-04
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		1995
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		1995-10
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		H04N5/262 | G11B27/28 | G06F17/30
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		H04N5/262
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		H
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		H04
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		H04N
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		H04N5
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		EP0675495A3 | EP0675495B1 | DE69527457T2 | DE69527457D1 | EP0675495A2
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		5
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		PROCEEDINGS OF FIRST ACM INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON MULTIMEDIA, 2-6 AUGUST 1993, ANAHEIM, CA, US, 1 August 1993, pages 267-272, XP000571991 ARMAN F ET AL: &quot;IMAGE PROCESSING ON COMPRESSED DATA FOR LARGE VIDEO DATABASES&quot; | STORAGE AND RETRIEVAL FOR IMAGE AND VIDEO DATABASES, SAN JOSE, CA, USA, 23 FEB. 1993, vol. 1908, ISSN 0277-786X, PROCEEDINGS OF THE SPIE - THE INTERNATIONAL SOCIETY FOR OPTICAL ENGINEERING, 1993, USA, pages 2-12, XP000670811 ARMAN F ET AL: &quot;Feature management for large video databases&quot; | PROCEEDINGS OF THE SPIE, vol. 2182, 1 January 1994, pages 142-149, XP000571809 HONGJIANG ZHANG ET AL: &quot;VIDEO PARSING USING COMPRESSED DATA&quot; | DIGITAL VIDEO COMPRESSION ON PERSONAL COMPUTERS: ALGORITHMS AND TECHNOLOGIES, SAN JOSE, CA, USA, 6-10 FEB. 1994, vol. 2187, ISSN 0277-786X, PROCEEDINGS OF THE SPIE - THE INTERNATIONAL SOCIETY FOR OPTICAL ENGINEERING, 1994, USA, pages 44-55, XP000670946 DEARDORFF E ET AL: &quot;Video scene decomposition with the Motion Picture Parser&quot;
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		221227
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		1994-03-31
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		SIEMENS CORPORATE RESEARCH, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		SIEMENS CORPORATE RESEARCH, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address"/>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address"/>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		ARMAN, FARSHID | HSU, ARDING | CHIU, MING-YEE
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		ARMAN, FARSHID
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address"/>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address"/>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

