<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US20040085781A1
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US10408768
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		A1
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		LED products: flashing LED display and decorative LEDs for autos and trucks
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		An eye grabber flashing LED store display adaptable to a standard store display peg is a flashing LED device to be used in stores to draw attention to the products the display is intended for. It uses an LED or LEDs, an electronic circuit, and an energy source such as batteries or solar panels or both. The invention is housed or secured by paper, polymer, composite, metal or other material and may optionally double as a sign displaying any means of graphics. The invention is adaptable to many store display methods including the standard peg display for carded products. The LED is preferably positioned either directly on the housing or at the tip of the peg the products hang on where it can be easily seen by anyone within the perimeter. A malleable wire LED light device and means of controlling lighting effects is a lighting device designed to provide white and/or colored illumination and lighting effects in and on various structures and machinery including tight places to reach. The malleable wire light uses one or more LEDs, a current limiting resistor or resistors, lengths of wire, and insulation to form a very small lamp suitable for routing through tight places with low clearance. The malleable wire light is preferably waterproof for exterior or interior use. It is adaptable for AC or DC operation. Typical application is interior and exterior of automobiles. Another is in college dorm rooms. The malleable wire light will not only work anywhere neon lighting will work, but it will also fit and work where neon will not because of its extremely small size. The malleable wire light is vibration resistant and virtually indestructible by direct blow of rock where neon is relatively fragile. The malleable wire light is more energy efficient and is cooler operating compared to neon. Multiple malleable wire lights can be controlled by circuitry to strobe, flash, chase, respond to music, change colors, and random flash to provide dazzling lighting effects.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USA | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2003-04-07
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2003
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2003-04
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2004-05-06
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2004
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2004-05
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		H01K7/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		H01K7/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		H
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		H01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		H01K
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		H01K7
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		362/555
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		362/555
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		362
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US20040085781A1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		40876803 | 37031902
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2003-04-07 | 2002-04-05
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		BRUCE WESSON
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		BRUCE WESSON
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Newton,MS,US
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Newton,MS,US
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		GARVEY SMITH NEHRBASS &amp; DOODY, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

