<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US20080114756A1
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12008148
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		A1
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Authomatic, personalized online information and product services
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A method for providing automatic, personalized information services to a computer user includes the following steps: transparently monitoring user interactions with data during normal use of the computer; updating user-specific data files including a set of user-related documents; estimating parameters of a learning machine that define a User Model specific to the user, using the user-specific data files; analyzing a document to identify its properties; estimating the probability that the user is interested in the document by applying the document properties to the parameters of the User Model; and providing personalized services based on the estimated probability. Personalized services include personalized searches that return only documents of interest to the user, personalized crawling for maintaining an index of documents of interest to the user; personalized navigation that recommends interesting documents that are hyperlinked to documents currently being viewed; and personalized news, in which a third party server customized its interaction with the user. The User Model includes continually-updated measures of user interest in words or phrases, web sites, topics, products, and product features. The measures are updated based on both positive examples, such as documents the user bookmarks, and negative examples, such as search results that the user does not follow. Users are clustered into groups of similar users by calculating the distance between User Models.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USA | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2008-01-08
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2008-01
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2008-05-15
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2008-05
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		G06F17/30
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		G06F17/30
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		G
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		G06
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		G06F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		G06F17
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		707/5
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		707/5
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		707
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US20080114756A1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US | US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		814808 | 31678505 | 59797500 | 17339299
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2008-01-08 | 2005-12-22 | 2000-06-20 | 1999-12-28
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		LEVINO | PERSONALIZED USER MODEL (PUM)
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		LEVINO
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address"/>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address"/>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		KONIG YOCHAI | TWERSKY ROY | BERTHOLD MICHAEL
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		KONIG YOCHAI
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		San Francisco,CA,US
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		San Francisco,CA,US | San Francisco,CA,US | Berkeley,CA,US
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

