<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US20100308725A1
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12793684
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		A1
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Aesthetic Device for Providing of Electrical Power to External Electronic Devices
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A novel aesthetic device is disclosed for providing of electrical power to external electronic devices. The aesthetic device is formed from an elongated band having a first end and a second end at opposites ends thereof and an engagement mechanism disposed proximate the second end of the elongated band for engaging of the elongated band proximate the first end. A plurality of rechargeable battery cells embedded within the elongated band for at least one of providing of electrical energy therefrom and for storing of electrical energy therein. A control circuit coupled with the plurality of rechargeable battery cells and a device connector coupled with the control circuit and the plurality of rechargeable battery cells for at least one of providing of electrical energy to an external electronic device for powering thereof and for receiving of electrical from an external electronic device for recharging of the plurality of rechargeable battery cells. Optionally, a plurality of light emitting diodes are disposed about the elongated band and coupled with the control circuit for having their intensity and color varied for aesthetic purposes.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USA
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2010-06-04
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2010-06
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-12-09
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-12
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		A41F9/00 | H01M6/42 | H05B37/02 | H02J7/00 | H01K1/62
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		A41F9/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		A
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		A41
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		A41F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		A41F9
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		315/32 | 315/294 | 320/116 | 429/149 | 2/322
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		315/32
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		315
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		TRZECIESKI MICHAEL
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		TRZECIESKI MICHAEL
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Hong Kong,HK
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Hong Kong,HK
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		MICHAEL TRZECIESKI
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

