<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US3977606
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US05574326
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		A
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Diffuser device
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A diffuser device for use in disseminating air or other gaseous fluid under pressure characterized by wall structure at least a portion of which is formed of impermeable material having a multitude of normally sealed microscopic ruptures. Said wall structure, at least in the area of said ruptures, is characterized by the ability to flex when the interior wall surface thereof, which defines the diffuser chamber, is filled with air or other gaseous fluid under a predetermined level of pressure. Said ruptures are so designed that as long as the required air pressure is maintained they form a multitude of jet-like flow passages each of which has an exceedingly small diameter. Consequently, as long as the pressure level is maintained, the air will move from the diffuser chamber, by way of said microscopic ruptures, in the form of a multitude of very fine, relatively minute, air jets which on entry to a surrounding body of liquid, for example, will form air bubbles which are correspondingly of extremely small, relatively micro-miniature size. The material of the diffuser wall structure is such that, when the air pressure falls below the required level, the microscopic ruptures will automatically reseal. Preferred embodiments of the invention are distinguished by the diffuser wall structure being comprised in part by an integrated frame the respective end portions of which form end walls and are spaced by a relatively narrow integrally connected strip which is apertured and has a trough-like form.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		1975-05-05
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		1975
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		1975-05
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		1976-08-31
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		1976
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		1976-08
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		A01G27/00 | B05B1/30
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		A01G27/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		A
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		A01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		A01G
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		A01G27
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		239/145 | 239/533.13 | 261/122.2 | 239/547
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		239/145
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		239
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US3977606
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		15
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		GB2223752B | US8241549 | US4193545 | US5606868 | US4243616 | US4248707 | US4256461 | US4764314 | US6502414 | US7600349 | USR33812 | US7934706 | US7674514 | US8128044 | EP0463062B1
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		15
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US3293861 | US1187533 | US3642260 | US3677936 | US3186644 | US3857910 | US2771320 | US3880965 | DD558462 | UK638185
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		10
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		57432675
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		1975-05-05
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		WYSS, ROBERT, J.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		WYSS, ROBERT, J.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		5858, N., Main, St., Dayton, OH, 45405
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		5858, N., Main, St., Dayton, OH, 45405
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		BLOOM, JEROME P.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		WARD, JR., ROBERT S.
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		4
	</str>
</doc>

