<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US4889620
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US06698973
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		A
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		In place gas cleaning of diffusion elements
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Cleaning of multi-pore diffusion elements in place with cleaning gases while submerged in liquid media by applying said cleaning gases intermittently or continuously to said diffusion elements between predetermined limits of operating pressure and flow through flow regulation means and plenums for the respective diffusion elements.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		1985-02-06
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		1985
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		1985-02
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		1989-12-26
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		1989
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		1989-12
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B08B3/00 | C10J1/08 | C02F3/20
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B08B3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B08
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B08B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B08B3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/199 | 261/122.1 | 210/137 | 210/205 | 134/171 | 210/220 | 134/170
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/199
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US4889620
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		14
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Roe, Frank C., The Installation and Servicing of Porous Air Diffuser Mediums, Water Works and Sewerage, Apr. 1934. | Gibbon, Donald L., Aeration of Activated Sludge in Sewage Treatment Pergammon, pp. 1-24, 65 &amp; 80, Table 8, 89-90, Tables 1A-4D, pp. 115-118 (Appendix A), 1974. | Hardie, Michael G., Zimpro, Inc., Letter to L. Ewing, Ewing Engineering Company, Marox Open Tank Oxygenation Process, Undated. | Houck, Daniel, &quot;Survey and Evaluation of Porous Polyethylene Media Fine Bubble Tube and Disk Aerators,&quot; ASCE/EPA Aeration Project, Mar. 3, 1988, Cover, Contents, Figures, Tables, pp. 1-68. | Hawker-Siddeley, Fine Bubble Dome Diffuser-Construction and Fittings, (Nokia, JRF-1). | Journal of WPCF, vol. 46 (1974), pp. 895-910; (cited in official search report). | Gregory, M. H., et al., Evaluation of a Fine Bubble Dome Diffusion Aeration System in Paper Mill Waste, TAPPI Proceedings, 1985, Environmental Conference, Mobile, Alabama, Apr. 22-24, 1985. | Nokia Metal Products, Operation and Maintenance of Nopol Diffusers, Undated (possibly Sep. 1978; published in Finnish at earlier date). | Annex 1, &quot;Facts and Arguments&quot;. | EPO Official Letter of 31 Jan. 1986. | Statement of James A. Tarbell, executed Mar. 27, 1989, with Exhibits A-Z. | Houck, Daniel F., et al., Survey and Evaluation of Fine Bubble Dome Diffuser Aeration Equipment, in Fulfillment of Grant From Assn. of Metro, Sewerage Agencies &amp; British Water Research Centre Under Partial sponsorship of U.S. EPA, 1981, pp. 5, 41-49, 72, 74, 91-93, 103, 105, 110, 157, 159, 161, 162, 164, 168-169, 171, 173-174. | Thayer, P. M., Ser. No. 140,533, filed Apr. 14, 1980, Abandoned, Specification and drawings. | EPO Application 81 304 493 0-Official Search Report Apr. 7, 1982. | Stenstrom, Michael K., Letter dated Apr. 11, 1988 to Jerome D. Wren, w/copies of overhead slides &quot;The Los Angeles Studies&quot;, exhibited to Steering Committee of. | Boyle et al., Biological Fouling of Fine Bubble Diffusers: State-of-Art, pp. 991-1005; 10/83. | EPO Office Action of 9 Aug. 1983. | The ASCE Committee on Oxygen Transfer, Phoenix, Arizona. | Associate's Covering Letter and response of 14 Mar. 1984. | EPO Office Action of 14 Sep. 1984. | Manual of Practice No. 5, Federation of Sewage and Industrial Waste Associations, 1952, pp. 48-62. | Claims from EPO Patent 0 049 154, Claims 1-50, pp. 1-11. | MOP 5-71; Water Pollution Control Federation, Aeration in Wastewater Treatment, WPCF Manual of Practice No. 5, pp. 9-13, 29-42, 63-74, 1971. | Barnes, F. B., Statutory Declaration, pp. 1-20, 20 May 1987. | Office Action dated Jan. 3, 1985 (from file of Bretscher et al. U.S.S.N. 588,070). | Hobbs, M.F., Serial No. 186,085, filed Sep. 11, 1980, Abandoned (Copies of specification, claims &amp; drawings). | Lagoon Aeration Corporation, The Lasaire System, Operation &amp; Maintenance, pp. 8-1-8-11, Undated. | Garnard, A., Project Manager City of Albuquerque, Letter to McMaha &amp; Associates, Inc., Albuquerque Southside Water Reclamation Plant Fine Bubble Aeration System, Jan. 16, 1986. | Barnes, F. B., Resume (Nokia, FB-1) Hinde Engr. Co., O&amp;M Instruction for Air-Aqua Oxidation System, 2 pp. text, 2 pp. drgs, undated (Nokia, FB-5). | Airam Oy Opposition Document, Notice of Opposition Against a European Patent, dated Mar. 14, 1988. | Lewis, Lonnie D., The Eyes of Texas are on U.S. Gypsum, Water and Wastes Engineering, (Nokia, FB-7), Jul. 1972, vol. 9, No. 7. | Melbourne and Metropoliton Bd. of Works, South Eastern Purification Plant (Drwngs) (Nokia, FB-11). | Associate's Covering Letter and response of 15 May 1985. | Shapiro, N., Memorandum to Hinde Engineering Company Sales Representatives, Centralized Gas Cleaning Equipment, The Air-Aqua Feederline, No. 207, 19 Mar. 1980. | Hinde Engineer Company, Operation and Maintenance Instruction Manual for Air-Aqua Aeration Systems, OM-474, Undated. | Hinde Engineering Company, Waste Treatment System Meets O-Discharge Goal and Fertilizes Farmland at Low Cost, Construction Digest, Nov. 27, 1975 (reprint of article). | Schade, Willard F., et al., Diffuser Plate Cleaning Versus Compressed Air Cost, Presented at Ohio Conference on Sewage Treatment, Mansfield, Ohio, Sep., 18-19, 1941, Sewage Works Journal, vol. 14, No. 1, Jan., 1942. | DuBois, Richard E., Induced Air Aeration Lagoon in Hinesburg, Vermont, Water &amp; Sewerage Works, Apr. 1972. | Morgan, &quot;Clogging Studies of Fine Bubble Diffuser Media,&quot; Sewage and Industrial Wastes, Feb. 1959, pp. 153-163. | Garnard, A., Project Manager for City of Albuquerque, Letter to Water Pollution Control Corporation, Fine Bubble Aeration System at Albuquerque's Southside Water Reclamation Plant, Mar. 26, 1985. | WPCF, MOP 5 (71), pp.: Cover, v.vi, 24, 26, 63, 65, 67-70, (Nokia FB-10). | Response to 14 Aug. 1985 Office Action, translation. | Aberley et al., Air Diffusion Unit, Journal WPCF, vol. 46, No. 5, May 1974, pp. 895-910. | Chasick, A. H. Plant Test of Sparger and Tube Types of Diffusers, Conference on Biological Waste Treatment, Manhattan College, Apr. 20-22, 1960. | Franklin, &quot;Purging Diffuser Plates with Chlorine&quot;, Water Works and Sewerage, Jun. 1939, pp. 232-233. | Associate's Covering Letter and response of 7 Jul. 1986. | Fulton, J. F., Statutory Declaration, pp. 1 &amp; 2, 19 May 1987. | Laukkarinen, T., Nokia Metal Products, Ltr. To Water Pollution Control Corporation, Jul. 1, 1983 w/enclosures, Nokia Diffusers for Waste Water Aeration (in English); Nokia Micro-Bubble Aerators HKP 600 and HKL 210, Printed in Finland (in English), 9. 73; Nokian Ratkaisut Jateveden Ilmastukssen (in Finnish), 00. 2.77. U. | Kuhn, John, Low-Pressure Lagoon Aeration System Reduces BOD 93.5%, Food Processing, Apr. 1978. | Office Action of 14 Aug. 1985 issued in Finnish Appln. 833,316 of Bretscher et al. (translation). | EPO Letter of 11 Sep. 1986 and Advance Rule 51 Communication. | Setter et al., &quot;Experimental Laundering of Air Diffuser Plates,&quot; Sewage Works Journal, Sep. 1945, pp. 867-877. | Vik, Thomas E., et al., Full Scale Operating Experience Utilizing Fine Bubble Ceramic Aeration With in Place Gas Cleaning at Seymour, Wisconsin, Presented at 57th Annual Meeting Central States Water Pollution Control Association, Inc., May 1984. | Goodnow, W. E., Aerated Lagoons Solve Town's Site Problems, Water &amp; Wastes Engineering, Jan. 1976, vol. 13, No. 1 (Nokia, FB-8. | Setter, &quot;Air Diffusion Problems at Activated Sludge Plants&quot; Water and Sewage Works, Dec. 1948, pp. 450-456. | EPO Examiner's Record of Interview of 24 Jun. 1985. | Allbaugh, Thomas A., et al, Aeration System Design Using Offgas Oxygen Transfer Testing, City of Lansing, Michigan, undated. | MOP 5-52; Federation of Sewage and Industrial Wastes Associations, Air Diffusion in Sewage Works, Manual of Practice No. 5, pp. 1-48, 1952. | Brenner, R. C. et al., &quot;Status of Fine Pore Aeration in the United States&quot;, 11th U.S./Japan Conference on Sewage Treatment Technology, Tokyo, Japan, Oct. 12-14, 1987. | Associate's Letter of 3 Feb. 1986, re additional art. | Associate's Covering Letter and response of 31 Oct. 1985. | Jackson, &quot;Maintaining Open Diffuser Plates with Chlorine,&quot; Water Works and Sewerage, Sep. 1942, pp. 380-382. | Roe, Frank C., Servicing of Porous Air Diffusers, Water Works and Sewerage Reference and Data Section, 1939. | Bretscher, U., et al., The Cleaning of Wastewater Aerators GWF-Wasser/Abwasser, vol. 6, No. 124, pp. 273-277, Water and Wastewater, 1983. | Rushton, Geo. H., et al., Norton Company, Aeration/Filtration Systems, Industrial Ceramics, Bio-Fouling: Causes, Effects and Remedies, Presented at 57th Annual Meeting of N.Y. Water Pollution Control Assoc., Jan. 22, 1985. | Hydroceramic Co. literature carrying a 1978 copyright date; p. 1, Forward; p. 42, Appendix; Cover sheet identified as Hydroceramic &amp; G. A. Boulier, Appexdix A. | English translation of Finnish Pat. Appln. 833,316 by Bretscher et al., assignors to Oy Nokia AB, Helsinki, Finland, filed Sep. 16, 1983. | Office Action dated Mar. 13, 1984 (from file of Bretscher et al. U.S.S.N. 532,564). | The Lasaire System Diffuser Maintenance, pp. 1-7. | Lamb, &quot;Designing and Maintaining Porous Tube Diffusers,&quot; Wastes Engineering, Sep. 1954, pp. 405-411. | Annex 2, Items 6-11 of Documentary Prior Art (listing). | Marx, James J. et al., &quot;Full Scale Comparison of Ceramic Disk and Flexible Membrane Tube Diffusers,&quot; 60th Annual Conference of the Water Pollution Control Federation, Philadelphia, Oct. 7, 1987. | Beck, &quot;Diffuser Plate Studies,&quot; Sewage Works Journal, Jan., 1936, pp. 22-37. | Hinde Engineering Company, Air-Aqua Controlled Aeration Systems, Engineers Design Manual, p. 26, 1980. | Long, S., M. S., P. E., Low-Pressure Aeration Reduces Odor, COD of Complex Mixture, Chemical Processing, May 1978 (reprint). | MOP 5-51, pp. 44-47 (cited in official search report). | Associate's Additional Ltr. of 5 Apr. 1984, re error in claim 42.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		77
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US5204028 | US7600349 | US8348247 | US8132794 | US8128044 | US8186655 | US6523552 | US7766292 | US7748175 | US7434362 | US5328601 | US7260918 | US6200468 | US5478507
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		14
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US3881872 | US2771416 | US2318728 | US4402758 | US3711072 | US2774585 | US2689714 | US3293861 | US4046845 | US3532272 | US4132637 | US4007240 | US3416776 | US3522093 | US1975002 | US2815943 | US2947525 | US3837629 | US3315895 | US2826209 | US3880965 | US3970731 | US2346367 | US4451373 | US4261933 | US3911068 | US4288394 | US3983031 | US4288395 | US4261932 | US2684330 | US2686138 | US3206178 | US2686139
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		34
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		69897385 | 19197480 | 42604182
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		1985-02-06 | 1980-09-29 | 1982-09-28
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		WATER POLLUTION CONTROL CORPORATION
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		WATER POLLUTION CONTROL CORPORATION
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Milwaukee, WI
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Milwaukee, WI
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		SCHMIT, FRANK, L. | REDMON, DAVID, T. | EWING, LLOYD
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		SCHMIT, FRANK, L.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Port, Washington, WI
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Port, Washington, WI | Racine, WI | Bayside, WI
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		WYSE, TOM
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		3
	</str>
</doc>

