<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7384558
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US10899194
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Compositions capable of inhibiting reactive oxygen and carbonyl species
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Therapeutic compositions are provided. The compositions include a single molecule that can display both antioxidant and carbonyl trapping properties. This can effectively reduce inflammation, oxidative stress and carbonyl stress, such as to prevent and/or treat cardiovascular disease and inflammatory diseases in kidney disease patients.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2004-07-26
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2004
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2004-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2008-06-10
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2008-06
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		514/1 | 514/458 | 604/29 | 549/412 | 549/418 | 549/410 | 210/645 | 210/647 | 210/646
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		514/1
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		514
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		EP1771168A1 | JP2008507580A | US20060016752A1 | US7384558 | WO2006019855A1 | AR050358A1 | MX2007000742A
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		7
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Sevanian et al., &quot;Low Density Lipoprotein (LDL) Modification: Basic Concepts and Relationship to Atherosclerosis,&quot; Blood Purif., vol. 17 (1999) pp. 66-78. cited by other . | Galli et al., &quot;Biological Effects of Oxidant Street in Haemodialysis: The Possible Roles of Vitamin E,&quot; Blood Purif., vol. 17 (1999) pp. 79-94. cited by other . | Kuroda et al., &quot;Serum Antioxidant Activity in Uremic Patients,&quot; Nephron, vol. 41 (1985) pp. 293-298. cited by other . | Canaud et al., &quot;Imbalance of Oxidants and Antioxidants in Haemodialysis Patients,&quot; Blood Purif., vol. 17 (1999) pp. 99-106. cited by other . | Lameire et al., &quot;Blood Purification,&quot; Blood Purif., vol. 17 (1999) pp. 55-57. cited by other . | Witowski et al., &quot;Prolonged Exposure to Glucose Degradation Products Impairs Viability and Function of Human Peritoneal Mesothelial Cells,&quot; J. Am. Soc. Nephrol., vol. 12 (2001) pp. 2434-2441. cited by other . | Nilsson-Thorell et al., &quot;Heat sterilization of fluids for peritoneal dialysis gives rise to aldehydes,&quot; Peritoneal Dialysis International, vol. 13 (1993) pp. 208-213. cited by other . | Memoli et al., &quot;Cytokine Production in Haemodialysis,&quot; Blood Purif., vol. 17 (1999) pp. 149-158. cited by other . | Aoyagi et al., &quot;Artificial kidney for the treatment of redox state abnormality in renal failure,&quot; J. Artif. Organs, vol. 4 (2001) pp. 1-2. cited by other . | Linden et al., &quot;3,4-Dideoxyglucosone-3-ene (3,4-DGE): A cytotoxic glucose degradation product in fluids for peritoneal dialysis,&quot; Kidney International, vol. 62 (2002) pp. 697-703. cited by other . | Wratten et al., &quot;Haemolopodialysis,&quot; Blood Purif., vol. 17 (1999) pp. 127-133. cited by other . | Ronco et al., &quot;New Perspectivies in the Treatment of Acute Renal Failure,&quot; Blood Purif., vol. 17 (1999) pp. 166-172. cited by other . | Witowski et al., &quot;Effect of Glucose Degradation Products on Human Peritoneal Mesothelial Cell Function,&quot; J. Am. Soc. Nephrol., vol. 11 (2002) pp. 729-739. cited by other . | Tetta et al., &quot;An Overview of Haemodialysis and Oxidant Stress,&quot; Blood Purif., vol. 17 (1999) pp. 118-126. cited by other . | Movilli et al. &quot;Adequacy, Nutrition, and Biocompatibility: Their Relevance on Clinical Outcome in Haemodialysis Patients,&quot; Blood Purif., vol. 17 (1999) pp. 159-165. cited by other . | Foley et al., &quot;Cardiovascular disease in chronic renal disease,&quot; American Journal of Kidney Diseases, vol. 32, No. 5, Suppl. 3 (Nov. 1998), pp. S112-S119. cited by other . | Haugen et al., &quot;The Involvement of Oxidative Stress in the Progression of Renal Injury,&quot; Blood Purif., vol. 17 (1999) pp. 58-65. cited by other . | Aoyagi et al., &quot;Role of active oxygen on methylguanidine synthesis in isolated rap hepatocytes,&quot; Kidney International, vol. 32, Suppl. 22 (1987) pp. S-229-S-233. cited by other . | Panichi et al., &quot;Plasma C-Reactive Protein in Haemodialysis,&quot; Blood Purif., vol. 17 (1999) pp. 142-148. cited by other . | Nicoletta et al., &quot;Antioxidant Activity Applying an Improved ABTS Radical Cation Decolorization Assay,&quot; Free Radical Biology &amp; Medicine, vol. 26, Nos. 9/10 (1999) pp. 1231-1237. cited by other. | Vitamin E web article, pp. 1-6 (Mar. 2007). cited by examiner . | Smith et al., &quot;Improved high-performance liquid chromatographic method for artifact-free measurements of aldehydes in the presence of ozone using 2,4-dinitrophenylhydrazine,&quot; Journal of Chromatography, 483 (1989) pp. 431-436. cited by other . | Inagi et al., &quot;Oxidative Protein Damage with Carbonhydrates and Lipids in Uremia: `Carbonyl Stress,`&quot; Blood Purif., vol. 17 (1999) pp. 95-98. cited by other . | Wratten et al., &quot;Uremic Ultrafiltrate Inhibits Platelet-Activating Factor Synthesis,&quot; Blood Purif., vol. 17 (1999) pp. 134-141. cited by other . | Bonomini et al., &quot;Surface Antigen Expression and Platelet Neutrophil Interactions in Haemodialysis,&quot; Blood Purif., vol. 17 (1999) pp. 107-117. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		25
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		USD645157
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6319243 | US5120849 | US20030065292 | US6277337 | US20030017995 | US20030007961 | US4344886 | US6610852 | US5891341 | US5668117 | US20010051658 | US20020119957 | US6342500 | US20030004105 | US20030138501 | US5055598 | US5508450 | US6436969 | US6309673 | US6919326 | US5527272 | US20020037329 | US5431496 | US7029906 | US20040058850 | US6258577 | US20050020507 | US6475434 | US5954958 | WO2000033895 | JP1991204874 | WO2002094179 | WO2002047677 | EP0667140 | JP1999071273 | WO2002100455 | WO2003057226 | WO2003045448 | WO2003047567 | JP1992308586 | WO2001004930 | EP0387771 | WO2000051987 | WO2002053094 | JP1996337590 | WO2001002004 | EP1108434
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		47
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		89919404
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2004-07-26
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		BAXTER INTERNATIONAL INC. (DEERFIELD, IL), BAXTER HEALTHCARE S.A.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		BAXTER INTERNATIONAL INC. (DEERFIELD, IL), BAXTER HEALTHCARE S.A.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Zurich, CH
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Zurich, CH
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		HAI, TON, THAT | NORDHAUS, MARK | SANDERS, PAUL | JIANG, CONG | KAROOR, SUJATHA | MELNICK, BEN | MARTIS, LEO
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		HAI, TON, THAT
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		7
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Round, Lake, IL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Round, Lake, IL | Antioch, IL | Greendale, WI | Gurnee, IL | Lake, Bluff, IL | Chicago, IL | Long, Grove, IL
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		KELLY, PAULA BARRETT, ROBERT M.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		KIM, JOHN
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		1
	</str>
</doc>

