<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7390343
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11680840
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Drinking water filtration device
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The invention is a device for purifying drinking water that has at least one fibrous structure. Preferably, there is an upstream and downstream fibrous structure. Each fibrous structure is a mixture of nano alumina fibers and second fibers arranged in a matrix to create asymmetric pores and to which fine, ultrafine, or nanosize particles are attached. Preferably, the device has an upstream antimicrobial for sterilization of retained microbes. The device is substantially more efficient at removing soluble contaminants such as halogens from a fluid stream than those previously available and is also able to retain turbidity, bacteria, and virus.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2007-03-01
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2007
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2007-03
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2008-06-24
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2008-06
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F1/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F1/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/500.1 | 55/DIG.39 | 210/505 | 210/660 | 95/273 | 436/177 | 95/285 | 423/627 | 55/523 | 423/629 | 210/510.1 | 55/528 | 55/527
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/500.1
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US20070175196A1 | US7390343
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		6
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Raynor, P.C. et al., The Long-Term Performance of Electrically Charged Filters in a Ventilation System, J. of Occ. and Envir. Hygiene, vol. 1(7): 463-471, Jul. 2004. cited by other . | Robinson et al., Depyrogenation by Microporous Membrane Filters, Tech Rpt No. 7, Depyrogenation, Parenteral Drug Assn, Phila, PA, 1985, TOC. cited by other . | Tien, Chi, Adsorption Calculations and Modeling, 1994 Butterworth-Heinemann (TOC provided). cited by other . | Martin, S.M. et al., Electrostatic Respirator Filter Media: Filter Efficiency and Most Penetrating Particle Size Effects, Appl. Occ. &amp; Enviro. Hygiene vol. 15(8):609-17, 2000. cited by other . | Brown, R.C. et al., Effect of Industrial Aerosols on the Performance of Electrically Charged Filter Material, Hyg. vol. 32(3): 271-94, 1988. cited by other . | Meltzer, T.H. et al., Filtration in Biopharmaceutical Industry, Marcel Dekker, NY, 262-265, 1998. cited by other . | Lukasik, J. et al., Removal of Microorganisms from Water by Columns Containing Sand Coated with Ferric and Aluminum Hydroxides, Wat Res 33(3): 769-77, 1999, Abstract. cited by other . | Lukasik, J. et al., Influence of Salts on Virus Adsorption to Microporous Filters, Appl Environ Micro, 66: 2914-20. cited by other . | Gitzen, W.H., Alumina as a Ceramic Material, American Ceramic Soc., Special Pub. 4, 1970, 13-14, TOC. cited by other . | Farrah, S.R. et al., Adsorption of Viruses by Diatomaceous Earth Coated with Metallic Oxides and Metallic Peroxides, Water Sci. Tech. 24(2): 235-40, 1991 (abstract). cited by other . | Mandaro, Charge Modified Depth Filters: Cationic-Charge Modified Nylon Membranes, in Filtration in the Pharmaceutical Industry, T.H. Meltzer Ed., Marcel Dekker, Inc., NY, 1987. cited by other . | Hou, K. et al., Capture of Latex Beads, Bacteria, Endotoxin and Viruses by Charge-Modified Filters, Appl Envir Micro, Nov. 1980, 892-96. cited by other . | Farrah, S.R. et al., Concentration of Viruses from Water by Using Cellulose Filters Modifies by In-situ Precipitation of Ferric and Aluminum Hydroxides, Appl Envir Micro, 1985. cited by other . | Sinha, D., Pretreatment Process Considerations for the Semiconductor Industry, in Ultrapure Water 7(6): 21-30, 1990. cited by other . | Wilkie, A.E. et al., Multi-Component Fiber Technology for Medical and Other Filtration Applications, 1st Inter. Conf. on Med. Filtration, DE Oct. 19, 2002. cited by other . | Dicosmo et al., Cell Immobilization by Adsorption to Glass Fibre Mats, A.A. Veliky et al., Ed., Blackie Academic &amp; Professional, 1994. cited by other . | Khalil, K., Synthesis of Short Fibrous Boehmite Suitable for Thermally Stabilized Transition Aluminas Formation, Journal of Catalysis, 1998(178): 198-206. cited by other . | Willkommen, H., Virus Validation of Filtration Procedures, PDA/FDA Viral Clearance Forum, Bethesda, MD, Oct. 2001. cited by other . | Moyer, E.S. et al., Electrostatic N-95 Respirator Filter Media Efficiency Degradation Resulting from Intermittent NaCl Aerosol Expos., Appl. Occ. &amp; Envir. Hyg. 15(8): 600-8. cited by other . | Lukasik, J. et al., Removal of Microorganisms from Water by Columns Containing Sand Coated with Ferric and Aluminum Hydroxides, Wat. Res. 33(3): 769-77, 1999. cited by other. | Blackford, D.B. et al., Alteration in the Performance of Electrostatic Filters Caused by Exposure to Aerosols, 4th World Filtration Congress, 7.27-7.33. cited by other . | Sobsey, M.D. et al., Concentration of Poliovisur from Tap Water Using Positively Charged Microporous Filters, Appl Enviro Micro, 1979: 588-595. cited by other . | Khalil, K., Synthesis of Short Fibrous Boehmite Suitable for Thermally Stabilized Transition Aluminas Formation, Journal of Catalysis, 1198 (178):198-206, Abstract. cited by other . | Henderson, D.W. et al., An Apparatus for the Study of Airborne Infection, J. Hyg. Camb. vol. 50, p. 53-67, 1952. cited by other . | Johnson, P.R., Whadaya Mean?, Filtration News vol. 20(5): 10-11, 2002. cited by other . | Ahuja, S., Handbook of Bioseparations, Academic Press, 2000, TOC. cited by other . | Tepper, F., Nanosize Powders Produced by Electro-Explosion of Wire and Their Potential Applications, Argonide Corporation, Sanford, FL, Abstract, 2000. cited by other . | Katz, J. et al., Mestastable Nanosized Aluminum Powder as Reactant in Energetic Formulations, 1-7. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		28
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US7537702 | US7473362 | US8303693
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5219577 | US6550622 | US6057488 | US5189092 | US6235388 | US5109311 | US5350443 | US2783894 | US4059119 | US20060225574 | US4523995 | US3408315 | US3947562 | US4743418 | US4282261 | US6524477 | US5562824 | US4664683 | US4366068 | US6830822 | US4305782 | US6797167 | US3852202 | US6849109 | US5855788 | US4824451 | US6321915 | US5798220 | US4536440 | US5104546 | US6955708 | US4617128 | US20060123991 | US4309247 | US6872431 | US6716218 | US6077588 | US6838005 | US5126044 | US6197515 | US4677019 | US6514413 | US6355330 | US5366636 | US5486292 | US5744236 | US4178438 | US4708803 | US6953604 | US4433697 | US4510193 | US2915475 | US6290848 | US4395332 | US4288462 | US4007113 | US4007114 | US4711793 | US4242226 | US4473474 | US4673504 | US4761323 | US20060169144 | US4331631 | US6913154 | US6464757 | US5147722 | US5307796 | US3031417 | US2773601 | US3352424 | US5759394 | US4555347 | US6630016 | US4321288 | US3242073 | US6010606 | US3234075 | US4455187 | US20050029198 | US4606823 | US6872311 | US6402819 | US4604208 | US4149549 | US20030127393 | US5225078 | US5804295 | US5085784 | US6959820 | US6716525 | US4230573 | US5865968 | US4807619 | GB2045828 | EP0958851 | WO1998002231 | DE2510467 | EP0099586 | EP1219335 | DE2410215 | WO1999047456
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		102
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US | US | US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		68084007 | 67770507 | 53110706 | 71621805 | 74404306
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2007-03-01 | 2007-02-22 | 2006-09-12 | 2005-09-12 | 2006-03-31
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		ARGONIDE CORPORATION
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		ARGONIDE CORPORATION
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Sanford, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Sanford, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		TEPPER, FREDERICK | KALEDIN, LEONID, A.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		TEPPER, FREDERICK
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Sanford, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Sanford, FL | Port, Orange, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		PASSERIN, ESQ., ALICIA M. COHEN &amp; GRISBY, P.C.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		SMITH, DUANE
	</str>
	<str name="Assistant Examiner">
		PHAM, MINH-CHAU T.
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

