<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7378021
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11740983
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Tidal vertical flow wastewater treatment system and method
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A wastewater treatment system includes a tidal, sequential vertical flow marsh cell system having at least three marsh cells in serial forward fluid communication. Incoming wastewater to be treated is channeled to at least the first and a second marsh cell, and a portion of water exiting a final marsh cell, to the first marsh cell surface. Each marsh cell is alternately flooded and drained for enhancing aeration of incoming water and marsh cell contents, which include media and plant roots having biofilms growing thereon, the biofilms including a population of nitrifying and denitrifying bacteria, for achieving substantially simultaneous nitrification and denitrification of the wastewater.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2007-04-27
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2007
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2007-04
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2008-05-27
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2008-05
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/32 | C02F3/02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/32
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/150 | 210/903 | 210/747 | 210/170.1 | 210/602 | 210/622 | 210/617
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/150
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US20070199893A1 | US7378021
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Green, Michal et al., &quot;Investigation of Alternative Method for Nitrification in Constructed Wetlands,&quot; Water Science Technology, vol. 35, No. 5, pp. 63-70, Permagon Press, Oxford, 1997. cited by other . | Jewell, William J., &quot;Anaerobic Sewage Treatment,&quot; Environmental Science &amp; Technology, vol. 21, pp. 14-21, Jan. 1987. cited by other . | Von Felde, Katrin and Kunst, Sabine, &quot;N- and Cod-Removal in Vertical-Flow Systems,&quot; Water Science Technology, vol. 35, No. 5, pp. 79-85, Permagon Press, Oxford, 1997. cited by other . | Nguyen, Long M., &quot;Organic Matter Composition, Microbial Biomass and Microbial Activity in Gravel-Bed Constructed Wetlands Treating Farm Dairy Wastewaters,&quot; Ecological Engineering 16, pp. 199-221, Elsevier Science B.V., 2000. cited by other . | Alleman, James E., &quot;The History of Fixed-Film Wastewater Treatment Systems,&quot; pp. 18, retrieved on Jul. 14, 2004. Retrieved from the Internet: &lt;URL:http://bridge.ecn.purdue.edu/.about.alleman/w3-class/45- 6/article/article-biofilmhistory.html&gt;. cited by other . | Laber, Johannes et al., &quot;Two Strategies for Advanced Nitrogen Elimination in Vertical Flow Constructed Wetlands,&quot; Water Science Technology, vol. 35, No. 5, pp. 71-77, Permagon Press, Oxford, 1997. cited by other . | Jewell, W. J. et al., &quot;Wastewater Treatment with Plants in Nutrient Films,&quot; U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, EPA-600/S2-83-067, pp. 1-5, Oct. 1983. cited by other . | McBride, Graham B. and Tanner, Chris C., &quot;Modelling Biofilm Nitrogen Transformations in Constructed Wetland Mesocosms with Fluctuating Water Levels,&quot; Ecological Engineering 14, pp. 93-106, Elsevier Science B.V., 2000. cited by other . | Reed, Sherwood and Bastian, Robert, &quot;Aquaculture Systems for Wastewater Treatment: An Engineering Assessment,&quot; U.S. Environmental Protection Agency Office of Water Program Operations Municipal Construction Division, 132 pages, Jun. 1980. cited by other . | Austin, David, &quot;Final Report on The South Burlington, Vermont Advanced Ecologically Engineered System (AEES) for Wastewater Treatment,&quot; U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, pp. i-M2, Mar. 4, 2000. cited by other . | Watson, J.T. and Danzig, A.J., &quot;Pilot-Scale Nitrification Studies Using Vertical-Flow and Shallow Horizontal-Flow Constructed Wetland Cells,&quot; Constructed Wetlands for Water Quality Improvement, pp. 301-313, CRC Press, Inc., 1993. cited by other . | Swoboda-Colberg, Norbert et al., &quot;Constructed Vertical Flow Aerated Wetlands,&quot; U.S. Department of Commerce Final Report, pp. 1-54, Dec. 1994. cited by other. | Sun et al., &quot;Treatment of Agricultural Wastewater in a Combined Tidal Flow-Downflow Reed Bed System,&quot; Water Science Technology, vol. 40, No. 3, pp. 139-146, 1999. cited by other . | Zhu, T. et al., &quot;Phosphorus Sorption and Chemical Characteristics of Lightweight Aggregates (LWA) Potential Filter Media in Treatment Wetlands,&quot; Wat. Sci. Tech., vol. 35, No. 5, pp. 103-108, 1997. cited by other . | Solar Aqua Systems, Inc. Marketing brochure, 1978. cited by other . | Lazarova, Valentina and Manem, Jacques, &quot;Innovative Biofilm Treatment Technologies for Water and Wastewater Treatment,&quot; Biofilms II: Process Analysis and Applications, pp. 159-206, 2000. cited by other . | Rakocy, James E., &quot;Integrating Tilapia Culture with Vegetable Hydroponics in Recirculating Systems,&quot; Tilapia Aquaculture in the Americas, vol. 1, pp. 163-184, World Aquaculture Society, Baton Rouge, Louisiana, 1997. cited by other . | Tanner, Chris C. et al., &quot;Effect of Water Level Fluctuation on Nitrogen Removal from Constructed Wetland Mesocosms,&quot; Ecological Engineering 12, pp. 67-92, Elsevier Science B.V., 1999. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		18
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US8287728
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5788842 | US3563888 | US5951866 | US6171480 | US3770623 | US6585886 | US5766474 | US5087353 | US6045695 | US4443337 | US4133141 | US6200469 | US20020148779 | US2822329 | US5755852 | US5078882 | US4678582 | US5078884 | US5897777 | US2486512 | US4735723 | US5906745 | US5337516 | US5904850 | US2306027 | US4008159 | US6126827 | US20040000517 | US0681884 | US4746435 | US5320663 | US5486291 | US6183642 | US5389257 | US6569321 | US4183809 | US5618413 | US6217766 | US3385786 | US4921604 | US20020185437 | US4793929 | US6086755 | US4384956 | US4839051 | US5863433 | US4331538 | US5785864 | US4415450 | US3598726 | US5393426 | US6645374 | US5863435 | US4872985 | US4039451 | US5487829 | US4267038 | US6159371 | US5626644 | US3925206 | US5259959 | US3768200 | US4997568 | US5876484 | US4482458 | US5820759 | US5126050 | US4333837 | US5948262 | US6383390 | US5893975 | US4057933 | US6692642 | US6221652 | US5733453 | US6447682 | US6447681 | US5174897 | US6277274 | US5985149 | US4620931 | US4904386 | US4284508 | US5137625 | US5565098 | US6406627 | US4277342 | US6063273 | US4959084 | US6090294 | US4169050 | US4895645 | US5518618 | SU1346588 | RU2107041 | JP1996214721 | JP246283P2000 | JP1998015586 | JP1983070891 | DE3941211 | WO1995017351 | GB1579623 | GB2182651 | DE1916044 | WO2002076893 | DE300015
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		106
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US | US | US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		74098307 | 6290705 | 46319903 | 37728703 | 38939802
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2007-04-27 | 2005-02-22 | 2003-06-17 | 2003-02-28 | 2002-06-17
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		WORRELL WATER TECHNOLOGIES, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		WORRELL WATER TECHNOLOGIES, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Charlottesville, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Charlottesville, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		AUSTIN, DAVID, C. | LOHAN, ERIC
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		AUSTIN, DAVID, C.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		St., Paul, MN
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		St., Paul, MN | Taos, NM
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		ALLEN, DYER, DOPPELT, MILBRATH &amp; GILCHRIST, P.A.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		PRINCE, FRED G.
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		1
	</str>
</doc>

