<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7455997
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US10523302
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Production of fermentation product
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A process of producing fermentation product comprising the steps of, (i) forming an acidified suspension of particulate plant derived material comprising a first polysaccharide which is more readily hydrolysable and a second polysaccharide which is more difficult to hydrolysable, (ii) allowing the first polysaccharide to undergo hydrolysis by action of the acid at a temperature of at least 50.degree. C. under conditions such that the first polysaccharide is hydrolysed and thereby forming a mixture of an aqueous liquor containing dissolved sugar and a solid residue containing the second polysaccharide, (iii) subjecting the mixture to one or more separation stages in which the solid residue and aqueous sugar liquor are substantially separated from each other, (iv) optionally washing the residue substantially free of acid and sugar, (v) adjusting the pH of the aqueous liquor to at least 4, (vi) passing the aqueous liquor from step (iv) into a fermentation stage where the dissolved sugars arc acted upon by a microorganism in a fermentation broth to produce a fermentation product, (vii) contacting the second polysaccharide by an enzyme, said enzyme hydrolyses the second polysaccharide to the component sugars, and allowing the component sugars to be acted upon by a microorganism in the fermentation broth to produce the fermentation product, (viii) separating the fermentation product from the broth, characterised in that the separation stage(s) in step (iii) is/are assisted by flocculation of the solid by-product, employing one or more flocculating agent(s) selected from the group consisting of water soluble polymers, water swellable polymers and charged microparticulate material. Typically such fermentation products include for instance ethanol, glycerol, acetone, n-butanol, butanediol, isopropanol, butyric acid, methane, citric Acid, fumaric acid, lactic acid, propionic acid, succinic acid, itaconic acid, acetic acid, acetaldehyde, 3-hydroxypropionic acid, glyconic acid, tartaric acid and amino acids such as L-glutaric acid, L-lysine, L-aspartic acid, L-tryptophan, L-arylglycines or salts of any of these acids.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2003-07-28
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2003
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2003-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2008-11-25
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2008-11
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C12P13/20
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C12P13/20
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C12
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C12P
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C12P13
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		435/141 | 435/166 | 435/140 | 435/146 | 435/145 | 435/144 | 435/163 | 435/160 | 210/609 | 210/728 | 210/702 | 210/727 | 210/725 | 435/159 | 127/37 | 435/171 | 435/139 | 435/150 | 426/495 | 435/106 | 435/109 | 426/49 | 127/55 | 210/710 | 127/56
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		435/141
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		435
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		ZA200500272A | AU2003250185A1 | NO327342B1 | PL373121A1 | EP1530646A1 | GB0218019D0 | US20050233031A1 | AU2003250185B2 | BR0313272A | US7455997 | WO2004015145A1 | CN1325654C | CN1675379A | CA2494664A1 | MXPA05001411A | NO20050970A
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		16
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Stenberg et al., Applied Biochemistry and Biotechnology, vol. 70-72, (1998), pp. 697-708. cited by other . | Derwent Abstr. 1986-281090 [43] for JP 61204100 (1986). cited by other . | Chem. Abstr. 1985:185565 for Makromolekulare Chemie, (1985), vol. 186, No. 2, pp. 273-281. cited by other. | Tucker et al., Applied Biochemistry and Biotechnology, vol. 70-72, No. 0, (1998), pp. 25-35. cited by other . | Derwent Abstr. 1997-488205 for RU 2077594 (1997). cited by other . | Derwent Abstr. 1993-150324 for SU 1733477 (1992). cited by other . | NREL/TP-580-26157, Jul. 1999, &quot;Lignocellulosic Biomass to Ethanol Process Design and Economics Utilizing Co-Current Dilute Acid Prehydrolysis and Enzymatic Hydrolysis Current and Futuristic Scenarios&quot;. cited by other . | Derwent Abstr. 1982-79144E [38] for DE 3107950 (1982). cited by other . | Kim et al., Applied Biochemistry and Biotechnology, vol. 91-93, (2001), pp. 253-267. cited by other . | Shell et al., Applied Biochemistry and Biotechnology, vol. 70-72, No. 0, (1998), pp. 17-24. cited by other . | Y Kholkin et al., Applied Biochemistry and Biotechnology, vol. 82, No. 2, pp. 135-140 (1999). cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		11
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5628830 | US6130303 | US6071417 | US5529699 | US4525218 | US4384897 | US6132625 | US5215902 | US5705369 | US3711462 | US6967085 | US5536325 | EP0150933 | WO2001034908 | JP1986204100 | WO1994029475 | EP0102759 | DE3107950 | GB2017707 | WO1999050195
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		20
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		GB
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		0218019.8
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2002-08-05
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		CIBA SPECIALTY CHEMICALS WATER TREATMENTS LTD
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		CIBA SPECIALTY CHEMICALS WATER TREATMENTS LTD
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		West Yorkshire, Bradford, GB
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		West Yorkshire, Bradford, GB
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		HUGHES, JONATHAN
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		HUGHES, JONATHAN
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Huddersfield, GB
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Huddersfield, GB
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		LOGGINS, SHIELA A.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		HRUSKOCI, PETER A.
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

