<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7431839
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11106751
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Low oxygen biologically mediated nutrient removal
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The present invention is directed to a substantially odorless biologically mediated treatment process for solid and liquid organic wastes. The present invention also provides for a novel nutrient rich humus material produced from the biologically mediated treatment process. The bioconversion process of the present invention results from low electron acceptor concentrations and high quantities of microorganisms in a diverse microbial community.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2005-04-15
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2005
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2005-04
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2008-10-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2008-10
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/605 | 210/630 | 210/610 | 210/620 | 210/611
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/605
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		CA2503166A1 | WO200706113560A3 | US20050242026A1 | US7431839 | WO2006113560A2
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		5
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Metcalf &amp; Eddy, &quot;Wastewater Engineering--Treatment and Reuse&quot; (4.sup.th Edition), Tchobanoglous, George et al., McGraw-Hill, Inc. (2003), pp. 623-627. cited by other . | Y. Watanabe et al., &quot;Simultaneous removal of organic materials and nitrogen by micro-aerobic biofilms,&quot; Water Science and Technology V31, N1, p. 195-203 (1995). cited by other . | JR Bicudo et al., &quot;Intermittent aeration of pig slurry--farm scale experiments for carbon and nitrogen removal,&quot; Water Science and Technology, V32, N12, p. 83-90 (1995). cited by other . | Chung-Min Liao et al., &quot;Nitrification/denitrification in an intermittent aeration process for swine wastewater,&quot; Journal of Environmental Science and Health Part B Pesticides Foods Contaminants and Agricultural Wastes, 29 (5): p. 1053-1078 (1994). cited by other . | C. Collivignarelli et al., &quot;Simultaneous nitrification-denitrification processes in activated sludge plants: Performance and applicability,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 40 (4-5): p. 187-194 (Aug.-Sep. 1999). cited by other . | F. Carta et al., &quot;Aerobic purification of dairy wastewater in continuous regime; reactor with support,&quot; Process Biochemistry, V34, N6-7 (SEP), p. 613-619 (1999). cited by other . | K. Yoo et al., &quot;Nitrogen removal from synthetic wastewater by simultaneous nitrification and denitrification (SND) via nitrite in an intermittently-aerated reactor,&quot; Water Research, V33, N1 p. 145-154 (Jan. 1999). cited by other . | Anders O. Wistrom et al., &quot;Enhanced nutrient removal by limiting dissolved oxygen concentration in a continuously fed, intermittently decanted, activated sludge plant,&quot; Environmental Technology, 17 (4): p. 371-380 (1996). cited by other . | Astrid A. Van de Graaf et al., &quot;Autotrophic growth of anaerobic ammonium-oxidizing micro-organisms in a fluidized bed reactor,&quot; Microbiology (UK), 142:2187-2196 (1996). cited by other . | Chen, Y. et al., &quot;Comparison between acclimated and unacclimated biomass affecting anaerobic-aerobic transformations in the biological removal of phosphorus,&quot; Process Biochemistry, vol. 40, No. 2, pp. 723-732 (Feb. 2005). cited by other . | P. Harremoes et al., &quot;Evaluation of Methods for Nitrogen and Phosphorous Control in Sewage Effluents,&quot; Journal of the Institute of Water and Environmental Management, Supplementary European Issue, p. 50-61 (Mar. 1992). cited by other . | M. Fuerhacker et al., &quot;Approach for a novel control strategy for simultaneous nitrification/denitrification in activated sludge reactors,&quot; Water Research, 34 (9): p. 2499-2506 (Jun. 2000). cited by other . | P. J. Hirl, &quot;Wastewater treatment with zero dissolved oxygen,&quot; 1998 National Conference on Environmental Engineering (Jun. 7-10, 1998). cited by other . | International Search Report from PCT/US2006/014298, (2006). cited by other. | H. Bennemann et al., &quot;Simultaneous nitrification and denitrificaiton in a single step unit,&quot; Conference Title: DECHEMA biotechnology conferences--Lectures at the 7th DECHEMA annual meeting of biotechnologists, Frankfurt am Main, Germany, p. 1011-1014 (May 30-31, 1989). cited by other . | I. F. Svoboda et al., &quot;Nitrogen removal from pig slurry by nitrification and denitrification,&quot; American Society Agricultural Engineers Seventh International Symposium on Agric. &amp; Food Processing Wastes p. 24 (Jun. 18-20, 1995). cited by other . | &quot;Anaerobic Digester at Craven Farms,&quot; www.energy.state.or.us/biomass/digester/craven.htm downloaded Jun. 20, 2002, last modified Jun. 20, 2002. cited by other . | Shoji, T. et al., &quot;Quantitative estimation of the role of denitrifying phosphate accumulating organisms in nutrient removal,&quot; Water Science and Technology, vol. 47, No. 11, pp. 23-29 (2003). cited by other . | Hao Xiaodi, et al., &quot;Removing nitrate and ammonium from drainage water by simulation of natural biological processes&quot; Water Research v. 32 No. 3 p. 936-43 (Mar. 1998). cited by other . | Bent Halling-Sorensen et al., &quot;A model of nitrogen removal from waste water in a fixed bed reactor using simultaneous nitrification and denitrification (SND),&quot; Ecological Modelling, 87 (1-3): p. 131-141 (1996). cited by other . | C. Helmer et al., &quot;Simultaneous nitrification/denitrification in an aerobic biofilm system,&quot; Water Science and Technology, V37, N4-5, p. 183-187 (1998). cited by other . | Elisabeth V. Munch et al., &quot;Simultaneous nitrification and denitrification in bench-scale sequencing batch reactors,&quot; Water Research, 30 (2): p. 277-284 (1996). cited by other . | K. M. Ho et al., &quot;The importance of simultaneous nitrification-denitrification in Biological Nutrient Removal activated Sludge Systems with low F/M bulking control,&quot; Australian Conference on Biological Nutrient Removal from Wastewater, 1994; 2nd p. 365-374 (AWWA) (1995). cited by other . | F. Beline et al., &quot;Factors affecting nitrogen transformations and related nitrous oxide emission from aerobically treated piggery slurry,&quot; Journal of Agricultural Engineering Research, V73, N3 p. 235-243 (Jul. 1999). cited by other . | Klangduen Pochana et al., &quot;Study of factors affecting simultaneous nitrification and denitrification (SND),&quot; Water Science and Technology, 39 (6): p. 61-68 (Mar. 1999). cited by other . | Janssen, P.M.J., &quot;Biological Phosphorous Removal, Manual for Design and Operation,&quot; IWA Publishing (2002), pp. 15-20. cited by other . | Eberhard Bock et al., &quot;Nitrogen loss caused by denitrifying Nitrosomonas cells using ammonium or hydrogen as electron donors and nitrite as electron acceptor,&quot; Archives of Microbiology, 163 (1): p. 16-20 (1995). cited by other . | S. Okabe et al., &quot;Relationship between population dynamics of nitrifiers in biofilms and reactor performance at various C:N ratios,&quot; Water Research, V30, N7 p. 1563-1572 (Jul. 1996). cited by other . | H. Hvidtfeldt Rasmussen et al., &quot;Treatment of odorous nitrogen compounds in a bioscrubber comprising simultaneous nitrification and denitrification,&quot; Symp. On Biological Waste Gas Cleaning, Heidelberg, Germany, (Mar. 9-11, 1994). cited by other . | Harald Horn., &quot;Simultane Nitrifikation und Denitrifikation in einem hetero-/autotrophen Biofilm unter Berucksichtigung der Sauerstoffprofile&quot; (English Abstract Enclosed--Simultaneous nitrification and denitrification in a hetero/autotrophic biofilm in concern to the oxygen gradient GWF (DasGas--und Wasserfach) Wasser--Abwasser (Germany) v 133;6, p. 287-292 (Juni 1992). cited by other . | USEPA, Manual: Nitrogen Control (1993), Office of Research and Development, EPA/625/R-93/010, Washington, DC, p. 86-87, 101-103. cited by other . | Hong W. Zhao et al., &quot;Controlling factors for simultaneous nitrification and denitrification in a two-stage intermittent aeration process treating domestic sewage,&quot; Water Research, 33 (4): p. 961-970 (Mar. 1998). cited by other . | J. Dufay et al., &quot;Simultaneous nitrification/denitrification in constructed wetlands,&quot; Joint Conference on the Environment, p. 85-90 (Mar. 1988). cited by other . | Course Syllabus, MB302 (General Microbiology, Oregon State University, Fall 2001, http://www.orst.edu/instruct/mb302/field/Lecture7/Lecutre7.htm, downloaded Jun. 20, 2002, date of last modification (unknown). cited by other . | G. Bortone et al., &quot;Nitrification and denitrification in activated-sludge plants for pig slurry and wastewater from cheese dairies,&quot; Bioresoure Technology, 37 (3): p. 243-252 (1991). cited by other . | Ahn, J. et al., &quot;Characterization of denitrifying phosphate-accumulating organisms cultivated under different electron acceptor conditions using polymerase chain reaction-denturing gradient gel electrophoresis assay,&quot; Water Research, Elsevier, Armsterdam, NL, vol. 36, No. 2, pp. 403-412 (Jan. 2002). cited by other . | Metcalf &amp; Eddy, &quot;Wastewater Engineering--Treatment, Disposal, Reuse&quot; (Third Edition) Tchobanoglous, George, et al., McGraw-Hill (1991), p. 512-518; and p. 726. cited by other . | American Society of Agricultural Engineers, &quot;Manure production and characteristics,&quot; ASAE Standard D384.1, downloaded from http://www.manuremangement.cornell.edu/Docs/ASAEStandard.pdf on Jun. 29, 2007 (6 pages) (Feb. 2003). cited by other . | Hyungseok Yoo et al., &quot;Nitrogen removal from synthetic wastewater by simultaneous nitrification and denitrification (SND) via nitrite in an intermittently-aerated reactor,&quot; Water Research, 33 (1): p. 145-154 (Jan. 1999). cited by other . | Zeng, R. et al., &quot;Identification and comparison of aerobic and denitrifying polyphosphate-accumulating organisms,&quot; Biotechnology and Bioengineering, vol. 83, No. 2, pp. 140-148 (Jul. 20, 2003). cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		40
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US8025796 | US8034243
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5447633 | US5538529 | US4721569 | US5338452 | US6190566 | US4487697 | US6013512 | US6689274 | US6350350 | US5248422 | US5755852 | US6087159 | US5078882 | US4292328 | US20040007523 | US5906746 | US4780208 | US6106716 | US6068774 | US5506096 | US6086765 | US5472472 | US4179374 | US5783081 | US5733454 | US6312599 | US5601719 | US4540666 | US5603744 | US5700370 | US3964998 | WO1990010083 | AU712746 | WO2004092079 | GB1245434 | WO2002038508 | EP1364915
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		37
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		10675105 | 60093603 | 70917100
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2005-04-15 | 2003-06-20 | 2000-11-10
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		BION TECHNOLOGIES, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		BION TECHNOLOGIES, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		New York, NY
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		New York, NY
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		MORRIS, JAMES, W. | NORTHROP, JERE
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		MORRIS, JAMES, W.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Standish, ME
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Standish, ME | Amherst, NY
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		KENYON &amp; KENYON LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BARRY, CHESTER T.
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		2
	</str>
</doc>

