<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7442310
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11609933
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Treating liquids with pH adjuster-based system
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The invention features a system for treating liquid including a liquid treatment device comprising adsorbent media for removing a substance from liquid and a pH adjuster device located upstream of the liquid treatment device relative to a direction of flow of the liquid. The pH adjuster device contains particulate or solid state pH adjuster material capable of releasing H or OH groups into the liquid or consuming H or OH groups from the liquid effective to raise or lower the pH of the liquid while it passes through the media. The pH adjuster may include acidifier or basifier material. Also featured is a method of using the device to remove a substance from liquid by adsorption and/or ion exchange.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2006-12-13
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2006
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2006-12
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2008-10-28
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2008-10
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01D15/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01D15/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01D15
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/688 | 210/669
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/688
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US7442310 | US20070095758A1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		On the synthesis of a-zirconium phosphate, Camino Trabajo et al., Chem. Mater., 2000, vol. 12, pp. 1787-1790. cited by other . | 31P-MASNMR-Spectroscopic studies with zirconium phosphate catalysts, Koh-Ichi Segawa et al., Journal of Catalysis 101, pp. 81-98 (1986). cited by other . | Preparation and characterization of mesoporous, high-surface-area zirconium (IV) oxide, Michael J. Hudson and James A. Knowles, J. Mater. Chem., 1996, 6(1), pp. 89-95. cited by other . | Preparation and sorption of spherical polyacrylamide-zirconium phosphate ion-exchanger, Chao-Yeuh Yang et al., Separation Science and Technology, 18(1), pp. 83-91 (1983). cited by other . | The sorption of first-row transition metal ions on a zirconium phosphate gel of low crystallinity and study of the reproducibility of the gel, Sten Ahrland et al., J. Inorg, Nucl. Chem., 1970, vol. 32, pp. 2069-2078. cited by other . | P MAS NMR Investigations of crystalline and glassy NASICON--Type phosphates, K.C. Sobha et al., Journal of Solid State Chemistry, vol. 121, pp. 197-201 (1996). cited by other . | Scientific bases for the synthesis of highly dispersed framework zirconium phosphate catalysts for paraffin isomerization and selective oxidation, Sadykov et al., Kinetics and Catalysis, vol. 42, No. 3 (2001), pp. 391-398. cited by other . | Influence of precipitating agent and digestion on the morphology and microstructure of hydrous zirconia, G.K. Chuah et al., Journal of Catalysis 175, pp. 80-92 (1998) Article No. CA981980. cited by other . | Sporlan Corp Bulletin 40-10, &quot;Catch-All&quot; Liquid and Suction Line Filter-Driers, Mar. 2003, pp. 1-10 and 25 of 32 (downloaded from http://www.sporlan.com/40-10.pdf on Jan. 7, 2008). cited by examiner . | Highly ordered porous zirconia from surfactant-controlled synthesis: Zirconium oxide-sulfate and zirconium oxo phosphate, Ulrike Ciesla et al., Chem. Mater, 1999, vol. 11, No. 2, pp. 227-234. cited by other . | Zirconium deficiency in NASICON-type compounds: crystal structure of NA5Zr(PO3)3, J.P. Boilot et al., Journal of Solid State Chemistry, 50, pp. 91-99 (1983). cited by other . | Parameter control in the synthesis of ordered porous zirconium oxide, Han-Rong Chen et al., Materials Letters 51 (Nov. 2001), pp. 187-193. cited by other . | Inorganic ion exchangers, C. B. Amphlett, Elsevier Publishing Company, New York, (1964), pp. 92-95. cited by other . | Zirconium and hafnium hydroxo-orthophosphates, N.G. Chemorukov et al., Russian Journal of Inorganic Chemistry, 28(7) 1983, pp. (unknown). cited by other . | The effect of mineralizers on the crystallization of zirconia gel under hydrothermal conditions, G. Dell'Agli et al., Solid State Ionics 123 (1999) pp. 87-94. cited by other . | Synthesis and study of new compounds (M1)(NIV)2(PO4)3 with Nasicon-like structure (M=AG, Cu; N=GE H, Sn, Ti, Zr), J.M. Winand et al., Journal of Solid State Chemistry 107 (1993), pp. 356-361. cited by other . | Hydrothermal preparation of the low-expansion NZP family of materials, Sridhar Komameni, Int. J. High Technology Ceramics 4 (1988), pp. 31-39. cited by other . | P solid-state NMR studies of the structure of amine-intercalated a-zirconium phosphate, reaction of a-zirconium phosphate with excess amine, D.J. MacLachlan, J. Phys. Chem., 1990, pp. 7656-7661. cited by other . | The preparation of crystalline zirconium phosphate and some observations on its ion exchanger behavior, A. Clearfield and J.A. Stynes, J. Inorg. Nucl. Chem., vol. 26, 1964, pp. 117-129. cited by other . | Crystalline insoluable salts of polybasic metals--II, Synthesis of crystalline zirconium or titanium phosphate by direct precipitation, G. Alberti et al., J. Inorg. Chem., vol. 30, pp. 317-318, 1968. cited by other . | New crystalline phases of zirconium phosphate possessing ion-exchange properties, A. Clearfield et al., J. Inorg. Nucl. Chem., 1968, vol. 30, pp. 2249-2258. cited by other . | On the synthesis of a-zirconium phosphate, Camino Trobajo et al., Chem. Mater. 2000, 12, 1787-1790. cited by other . | Preparation of stable, high surface area zirconia, K.S. Chan et al., J. Mat. Science, 12, N21, 1579-1581 (1994). cited by other . | A novel layered zirconium phosphate Zr2O3(HPO4) synthesis and characterization of properties, Anatoly Bortun et al., Solvent Extraction and Ion Exchange, 15(2), pp. 305-328 (1997). cited by other . | Synthetic inorganic ion exchangers, Vesely, V. and Pekarek, V., Talanta, 1972, vol. 19, pp. 219-262. cited by other . | Structure of zirconium phosphate gels produced by the sol-gel method, S.G. Bogdanov et al., J. Phys.: Codens, Matter 9 (1997), pp. 4031-4039. cited by other . | Preparation of porous resin loaded with crystalline hydrous zirconium oxide and its application to the removal of arsenic, T.M. Suzuki et al., Reactive &amp; Functional Polymers 43 (2000), pp. 165-172. cited by other . | Ion exchange properties of TIN (IV) materials-1, Hydrous (TIN)IV) oxide and its cation exchange properties, J.D. Donaldson et al., J. Inorg. Nucl. Chem., 1968, vol. 30, pp. 1083-1092. cited by other . | Preparation of zirconia powder by the pyrolysis of active carbon, M. Ozawa and M. Kimura, Journal of Material Science Letters 9 (1990), pp. 446-448. cited by other . | Uptake of inorganic acids on hydrogeis of tetravalent hydroxides and its application for the preparation of some inorganic sorbents, R. Caletka et al., Journal of Radioanalytical Chemistry, vol. 30 (1976), pp. 155-172. cited by other . | Effects of chemical species on the crystallization behavior of a sol-derived zirconia precursor, C.L. Ong et al., J. Am. Ceram. Soc. 81(10), pp. 2624-2628 (1998). cited by other . | Abstract translation of attached Russian article for chemistry role in the environmental protection, V.V. Streklo, Naukova Dumka, Kiev, (1982), pp. 179-188. cited by other. | Structure of the active sites on H3PO4/ZrO2 catalysts for dimethyl carbonate synthesis from methanol and carbon dioxide, Yoshiki Ikeda et al., J. Phys. Chem. B, 2001, 105, pp. 10653-10658. cited by other . | Preparation and characterization of a new 3-dimensional zirconium hydrogen phosphate, T-Zr(HPO4)2, Determination of the complete crystal structure combining synchrotron X-ray single-crystal diffraction and neutron powder diffraction, Anne Marie Krough Anderson, Inorg. Chem. 1998, 37, pp. 876-881. cited by other . | Microwave-hydrothermal synthesis of nancrystalline zirconia powders, Federica Bondioli et al., J. Am. Ceram. Soc., 84(11), pp. 2728-2730 (2001). cited by other . | Hydrothermal synthesis and characterisation of crystalline sodium zirconium phosphates, M.K. Dongare et al., Mat. Res. Bull., vol. 27, pp. 637-645 (1992). cited by other . | Galvanic cell type humidity sensor with NASICON-based material operative at high temperature, Feng et al., Chem. Mater. 1992, vol. 4, pp. 1257-1262. cited by other . | Inorganic ion exchange materials group IV hydrous oxides-synthetic inorganic ion exchangers, Chapter 5, Abraham Clearfield, Ph.D.Ed., CRC Press, Inc., 1982, pp. 141-160. cited by other . | Proton conductivity and humidity-sensing properties at high temperature of the NASICON-based composite material HZr2P4O12ZrP2O7, Shouhua Feng et al., Chem. Mater., 1993, 5, pp. 1277-1282. cited by other . | Preparation and sorption properties of spherical polyacrylamide-zirconium phosphate ion-exchanger, Chao-Yeuh Yang et al., Separation Science and Technology, 18(1), pp. 83-91, 1983. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Oct. 2, 2003. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Oct. 30, 2003. cited by other . | Synthesis of semicrystalline materials by organic compound intercalation into amorphous titanium phosphate, Anatoly Bortun and V.V. Strelko, Chem Mater, 1995, 7. pp. 249-251. cited by other . | Solid-state nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopic study of .gamma.-zirconium phosphate, Nigel Claydon, J. Chem. Soc., Dalton Trans. (1987), pp. 1877-1881. cited by other . | Direct hydrothermal synthesis of zirconium phosphate and zirconium arsenate with a novel basic layerd structure in alkaline media, Abraham Clearfield et al., Inorganic Chemistry Communications 1 (1998) pp. 206-208. cited by other . | Sol-gel preparation of nanostructured adsorbents, Y.S. Lin and S.G. Deng, Adsorption and its Application in Industry and Environmental Protection Studies in Surface Science and Catalysts, vol. 120, pp. 653-686, 1998. cited by other . | Morphology of zirconia synthesized hydrothermally from zirconium oxychloride, Bruno Mottet et al., J. Am. Ceram Soc., 75(9), pp. 2515-2519 (1992). cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		47
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US4902426 | US4711718 | US4883599 | US4902427 | US5082568 | US4415677 | US20040050795 | US6602919 | US6143106 | US4366064 | US1993142 | US4526765 | US3416884 | US3692496 | US6264845 | US20030103888 | US4110081 | US5597489 | US5730879 | US20020179521 | US5690806 | US6077809 | US2349243 | US5002749 | US3415382 | US3056647 | US4104170 | US6475386 | US6379641 | US4212743 | US5328609 | US3056502 | US6260372 | US20020030017 | US5210363 | US6042731 | US5510029 | US3850835 | US5700371 | US5279733 | US5116499 | US6861248 | US3046819 | US6322704 | US6283308 | US6712977 | US4512905 | US4695642 | US4806517 | US5072031 | US4381289 | US6326328 | US4894149 | US3485763 | US4643836 | US3130147 | US2207725 | US3375933 | US4025608 | US6054059 | US4761232 | US4826663 | US4021339 | US20030196966 | US6613230 | US4609465 | US6391278 | US4664812 | US5885463 | US5290443 | US20030196960 | US3289847 | JP1993017112 | JP1987226807 | FR1317359
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		75
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US | US | US | US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		60993306 | 95875404 | 19563002 | 19587502 | 19587602 | 59125004
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2006-12-13 | 2004-10-05 | 2002-07-15 | 2002-07-15 | 2002-07-15 | 2004-07-26
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		MAGNESIUM ELEKTRON, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		MAGNESIUM ELEKTRON, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Flemington, NJ
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Flemington, NJ
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		BORTUN, ANATOLY, I. | BORTUN, MILA, N. | FISCHER, FRANCIS, J.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		BORTUN, ANATOLY, I.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Easton, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Easton, PA | Easton, PA | Easton, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		PEARNE &amp; GORDON LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BARRY, CHESTER T.
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

