<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7473364
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11683162
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Multivalent metal ion management for low sludge processes
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A method for managing multivalent metal ion concentrations in low-yield wastewater treatment processes. The method includes combining wastewater containing BOD with bacteria-laden sludge in a mainstream reactor to form a mixed liquor, separating the mixed liquor into a clear effluent and an activated sludge stream, returning a first portion of the activated sludge stream to the mainstream reactor, processing a second portion of the activated sludge stream in a sidestream bioreactor, returning at least a portion of the activated sludge stream in the sidestream bioreactor to the mainstream reactor, and adding multivalent metal ions to at least one of the wastewater, the mixed liquor, the activated sludge stream and combinations thereof to reduce the generation of waste activated sludge.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2007-03-07
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2007
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2007-03
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-01-06
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-01
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/631 | 210/607 | 210/610 | 210/620 | 210/623 | 210/625 | 210/626
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/631
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US20070209998A1 | US7473364
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Abu-Orf, M. M., et al., &quot;Chemical and Physical Pretreatment of ATAD Biosolids for Dewatering,&quot; Water Science Technology, 2001, vol. 44, No. 10, pp. 309-314, IWA Publishing. cited by other . | Dubois, M., et al., &quot;Colorimetric Method for Determination of Sugars and Related Substances,&quot; Analytical Chemistry, 1956, vol. 28, No. 3, pp. 350-356. cited by other . | Rader, &quot;Microrganisms and Their Role in the Activated-Sludge Process,&quot; Web page accessed Jan. 11, 2005, http://www.college.ucla.edu/webproject/micro7/studentprojects7/Rader/aslu- dge2.htm , pp. 1-19. cited by other . | Dignac, M.-F., et al., &quot;Chemical Description of Extracellular Polymers: Implication on Activated Sludge Floc Structure,&quot; Water Science Technology, 1998, vol. 38, No. 8-9, pp. 45-53, Elsevier Science Ltd. cited by other . | Urbain, V., et al., &quot;Bioflocculation in Activated Sludge: An Analytic Approach,&quot; Water Research, 1993, vol. 27, No. 5, pp. 829-838, Pergamon Press Ltd. cited by other . | Yasui, H., et al., &quot;A Full-Scale Operation of a Novel Activated Sludge Process Without Excess Sludge Production,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 1996, pp. 395-404, vol. 34, No. 3-4, Elsevier Science Ltd./Pergamon. cited by other . | Chudoba, et al., &quot;Pre-Denitrification Performance of a High-Loaded Anoxic Sludge,&quot; Degremont Research Center, France, 1999. cited by other . | Frolund, B., et al., &quot;Extraction of Extracellular Polymers from Activated Sludge Using a Cation Exchange Resin,&quot; Water Research, 1996, vol. 30, No. 8, pp. 1749-1758, Elsevier Science Ltd. cited by other . | Abu-Orf, M., et al. &quot;Adjusting Floc Cations to Improve Effluent Quality: The Case of Aluminum Addition at Sioux City Wastewater Treatment Facility,&quot; Water Environment Federation, 2004, 16 pgs. cited by other. | Van Loosdrecht, Mark C. M., and Mogens Henze, &quot;Maintenance, Endogeneous Respiration, Lysis, Decay and Predation,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 1999, pp. 107-117, vol. 39, No. 1, IAWQ/Elsevier Science Ltd./Pergamon. cited by other . | Nielsen, Per Halkj.ae butted.r, &quot;The Significance of Microbial FE (III) Reduction in the Activated Sludge Process,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 1996, pp. 129-136, vol. 34, Nos. 5-6, Elsevier Science Ltd./Pergamon. cited by other . | Lowry, O. H., et al., &quot;Protein Measurement with the Folin Phenol Reagent,&quot; J. Bio. Chem., 1951, vol. 193, pp. 265-275. cited by other . | Strand, Stuart E., et al., &quot;Activated-Sludge Yield Reduction Using Chemical Uncouplers,&quot; Water Environment Research, 1999, pp. 454-458, vol. 71, No. 4. cited by other . | Heinzmann, Bernd, and Gerd Engel, &quot;Phosphorus Recycling in Treatment Plants with Biological Phosphorus Removal,&quot; paper presented at the German Federal Environment Ministry, Feb. 6-7, 2003, pp. 1-16, Berlin, Germany. cited by other . | Low, Euan W., and Howard A. Chase, &quot;The Use of Chemical Uncouplers for Reducing Biomass Production During Biodegradation,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 1998, pp. 399-402, vol. 37, No. 4-5, Elsevier Science Ltd./Pergamon. cited by other . | Matsuo, Tomonori, et al., &quot;Metabolism of Organic Substances in Anaerobic Phase of Biological Phosphate Uptake Process,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 1992, pp. 83-92, vol. 25, No. 6, IAWPRC/Pergamon Press Ltd, Oxford. cited by other . | Bakker, E. P., Chapter IIA, &quot;Cell K.sup.+ and K.sup.+ Transport Systems in Prokaryotes,&quot; In Alkali Cation Transport Systems in Prokaryotes, Bakker, E.P., Ed., 1993, pp. 205-224, CRC Press. cited by other . | Bruus, J. H., et al., &quot;On the Stability of Activated Sludge Flocs with Implications to Dewatering,&quot; Water Research, 1992, vol. 26, No. 12 pp. 1597-1604, Pergamon Press Ltd. cited by other . | Novak, J. T., et al., &quot;Mechanisms of Floc Destruction During Anaerobic and Aerobic Digestion and the Effect on Conditioning and Dewatering of Biosolids,&quot; Water Research, 2003, vol. 37, pp. 3136-3144, Elsevier Science Ltd. cited by other . | Casey, T. G., et al., &quot;A Hypothesis for the Causes and Control of Anoxic-Aerobic (AA) Filament Bulking in Nutrient Removal Activated Sludge Systems,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 1994, pp. 203-212, vol. 29, No. 7, IAWQ/Pergamon. cited by other . | &quot;Vertical loop reactors--fine bubble power efficiency without fine bubble maintenance&quot; brochure by Envirex Inc., Jan. 1986. cited by other . | &quot;Contrashear filter solutions for waste water,&quot; for Contra Shear.TM., Jul. 29, 2005, p. 1 of 1, http://www.contrashear.co.nz/. cited by other . | Moen, G., et al., &quot;Effect of Solids Retention Time on the Performance of Thermophilic and Mesophilic Digestion of Combined Municipal Wastewater Sludges,&quot; Water Environment Research, 2003, vol. 75, No. 6, pp. 539-548. cited by other . | &quot;The Rotoscreen.TM. Escalating Fine Channel Screen Builds Pre-Coat to Provide High Solids Capture Rates with the Lowest Headloss,&quot; Jul. 29, 2005, p. 1 of 2-page screen, Parkson Corporation Web Home Page, http://www.parkson.com/Content.aspx?ntopicid=120&amp;parent=process&amp;processID- =148. cited by other . | Hong, S., et al., &quot;Biological Phosphorus and Nitrogen Removal Via the A/O Process: Recent Experience in the United States and United Kingdom,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 1984, pp. 151-172, vol. 16, Vienna, Austria. cited by other . | Metcalf &amp; Eddy, Table 8-25, &quot;Description of suspended growth processes for phosphorus removal,&quot; Wastewater Engineering Treatment and Reuse, 4.sup.th ed., 2003, pp. 810-813, McGraw Hill. cited by other . | Ekama, G. A., et al., &quot;Considerations in the Process Design of Nutrient Removal Activated Sludge Processes,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 1983, pp. 283-318, vol. 15, IAWPRC/Pergamon Press Ltd.. cited by other . | Worthen, Peter T., &quot;The Chesapeake Bay Plan: Restoring An Estuary In Distress,&quot; Water Engineering &amp; Management, Sep. 1994, pp. 18-22, vol. 141, No. 9, ABI/INFORM Global. cited by other . | Nielsen, P. H., et al., &quot;Changes in the Composition of Extracellular Polymeric Substances in Activated Sludge During Anaerobic Storage,&quot; Appl. Microbiol. Biotechnol., 1996, vol. 44, pp. 823-830, Springer-Verlag. cited by other . | Mavinic, D. S., et al., &quot;Fate of Nitrogen in Aerobic Sludge Digestion,&quot; J. Water Pollut. Control Fed., 1982, vol. 54, No. 4, pp. 352-360. cited by other . | Kim, et al., &quot;pH and Oxidation-Reduction Potential Control Strategy for Optimization of Nitrogen Removal in an Alternating Aerobic-Anoxic System,&quot; Water Environment Research, vol. 73, No. 1, 2001. cited by other . | Rasmussen, H., et al., &quot;Iron Reduction in Activated Sludge Measured with Different Extraction Techniques,&quot; Water Research, 1996, vol. 30, No. 3, pp. 551-558, Elsevier Science Ltd. cited by other . | Harrison, D. E. F., and J. E. Loveless, &quot;Transient Responses of Facultatively Anaerobic Bacteria Growing in Chemostat Culture to a Change from Anaerobic to Aerobic Conditions,&quot; Journal of General Microbiology, 1971, pp. 45-52, vol. 68. cited by other . | Caulet, et al., &quot;Modulated Aeration Management by Combined ORP and DO Control: A Guarantee of Quality and Power Savings for Carbon and Nitrogen Removal in Full Scale Wastewater Treatment Plants,&quot; Center of International Research for Water Environment, France, 1999. cited by other . | Murthy, S. N., et al., &quot;Factors Affecting Floc Properties During Aerobic Digestion: Implications for Dewatering,&quot; Water Environment Research, 1999, vol. 71, No. 2, pp. 197-202. cited by other . | Bishop, P. L., et al., &quot;Fate of Nutrients during Aerobic Digestion,&quot; Journal Environ. Eng. Div., Proc. Am. Soc. Civil Eng., 1978, vol. 104 No. EE5, pp. 967-979. cited by other . | U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, &quot;Acid Digestion of Sediments, Sludges, and Soils,&quot; U.S. EPA Method 3050B, 1996, pp. 1-12. cited by other . | Ra, et al., &quot;Biological Nutrient Removal with an Internal Organic Carbon Source in Piggery Wastwater Treatment,&quot; Water Research, vol. 34 No. 3, pp. 965-973, 2000. cited by other . | Park, C., et al., &quot;The Effect of Wastewater Cations on Activated Sludge Characteristics: Effects of Aluminum and Iron in Floc,&quot; Water Environment Research, 2006, vol. 78, No. 1, pp. 31-40. cited by other . | Higgins, M. J., et al., &quot;The Effect of Cations on the Settling and Dewatering of Activated Sludges: Laboratory Results,&quot; Water Environment Research, 1997, vol. 69, No. 2, pp. 215-224. cited by other . | Park, C., et al., &quot;The Digestibility of Waste Activated Sludges,&quot; Water Environment Research, 2006, vol. 78, No. 1, pp. 59-68. cited by other . | Chudoba, P., et al., &quot;The Aspect of Energetic Uncoupling of Microbial Growth in the Activated Sludge Process--OSA System,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 1992, pp. 2477-2480, vol. 26, No. 9-11, IAWPRC. cited by other . | Mahmoud, N., et al., &quot;Anaerobic Stabilisation and Conversion of Biopolymers in Primary Sludge--Effect of Temperature and Sludge Retention Time,&quot; Water Research, 2004, vol. 38, pp. 983-991, Elsevier Ltd. cited by other . | Chen, G-H., et al., &quot;Minimization of Activated Sludge Production by Chemically Stimulated Energy Spilling,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 2000, pp. 189-200, vol. 42, No. 12, IWA Publishing. cited by other . | Hartree, E. F., &quot;Determination of Protein: A Modification of the Lowry Method that Gives a Linear Photometric Response,&quot; Analytical Biochemistry, 1972, vol. 48, pp. 422-427, Academic Press, Inc. cited by other . | &quot;Internally-fed Rotary Wedgewire Screens&quot; brochure by Parkson Corporation for Hycor.RTM. Rotoshear.RTM. (year not provided). cited by other . | &quot;GAC Fluid Bed Efficient, economical bioremediation of BTEX groundwater&quot; brochure by Envirex Inc., Dec. 1992. cited by other . | Cecchi, F., et al., &quot;Anaerobic Digestion of Municipal Solid Waste,&quot; BioCycle, Jun. 1990, pp. 42-43, vol. 31, No. 6, The JG Press, Inc. cited by other . | Chen, Guang-Hao, et al., &quot;Effect of Sludge Fasting/Feasting on Growth of Activated Sludge Cultures,&quot; Wat. Res., 2001, pp. 1029-1037, vol. 35, No. 4, Elsevier Science Ltd./Pergamon. cited by other . | Adams, M. W. W., and Robert M. Kelly, &quot;Enzymes from Microorganisms in Extreme Environments,&quot; Chemical &amp; Engineering News, Dec. 18, 1995, pp. 32-42, vol. 73, No. 51, American Chemical Society, Washington, D.C.. cited by other . | &quot;Rex VLR/SCC System&quot; brochure by Envirex Inc., Bulletin No. 315-156, Oct. 1989. cited by other . | Yasui, H., and M. Shibata, &quot;An Innovative Approach to Reduce Excess Sludge Production in the Activated Sludge Process,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 1995, pp. 11-20, vol. 30, No. 9, IAWQ/Pergamon. cited by other . | Wentzel, M. C., et al., &quot;Processes and Modelling of Nitrification Denitrification Biological Excess Phosphorus Removal Systems--A Review,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 1992, pp. 59-82, vol. 25, No. 6, IAWPRC/Pergamon Press Ltd., Oxford. cited by other . | Higgins, M. J., et al., &quot;Characterization of Exocellular Protein and Its Role in Bioflocculation,&quot; Journal of Environmental Engineering, 1997, vol. 123, pp. 479-485. cited by other . | Westgarth, W. C., et al., &quot;Anaerobiosis in the Activated-Sludge Process,&quot; (paper presentation and formal discussions) Department of Environmental Sciences and Engineering, School of Public Health, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, pp. 43-61 (neither publication information nor year provided). cited by other . | &quot;The Rotoshear.RTM. Internally Fed Rotating Drum Screen's Wedgewire Construction Maximizes Capture for Efficient Screening with Minimal Operator Attention,&quot; Jul. 29, 2005, p. 1 of 2-page screen, Parkson Corporation Web Home Page, http://www.parkson.com/Content.aspx?ntopicid=133&amp;parent=municipal&amp;process- ID=149 . . . . cited by other . | Klopping, et al., &quot;Activated Sludge Microbiology, Filamentous and Non-Filamentous Microbiological Problems and Biological Nutrient Removal,&quot; Water Environment Federation, Plant Operations Specialty Conference, Date Unknown. cited by other . | Holbrook, R. D., et al., &quot;A Comparison of Membrane Bioreactor and Conventional-Activated-Sludge Mixed Liquor and Biosolids Characteristics,&quot; Water Environment Research, 2005, vol. 77, No. 4, pp. 323-330. cited by other . | Valentis, G., and J. Lesavre, &quot;Wastewater Treatment by Attached-Growth Micro-Organisms on a Geotextile Support,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 1990, pp. 43-51, vol. 22, Nos. 1/2, IAWPRC. cited by other . | Kakii, K., et al., &quot;Effect of Calcium Ion on Sludge Characteristics,&quot; J. Ferment. Technol., 1985, vol. 63, No. 3, pp. 263-270. cited by other . | Fukase, T., et al., &quot;Factors Affecting Biological Removal of Phosphorus,&quot;Water Science and Technology, 1985, pp. 187-198, vol. 17, Nos. 11/12, IAWPRC, London. cited by other . | Charpentier, et al., &quot;ORP Regulation and Activated Sludge 15 years of Experience,&quot; 19th Biennial Conference/AWQ of Vancouver--Jun. 1998. cited by other . | Murthy, S. N., et al., &quot;Optimizing Dewatering of Biosolids from Autothermal Thermophilic Aerobic Digesters (ATAD) Using Inorganic Conditioners,&quot; Water Environment Research, 2000, vol. 72, No. 6, pp. 714-721. cited by other . | &quot;Efficient treatment of high strength industrial and municipal wastewater&quot; brochure by Envirex Inc., Jan. 1990. cited by other . | Marais, G. v. R., et al., &quot;Observations Supporting Phosphate Removal by Biological Excess Uptake--A Review,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 1983, pp. 15-41, vol. 15, IAWPRC/Pergamon Press. Ltd. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		65
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US20050040103 | US4874519 | US6562237 | US5348655 | US5348653 | US6193889 | US5094752 | US6077430 | US3787316 | US5336290 | US6036862 | US3192155 | US5380438 | US20050045557 | US5658458 | US6783679 | US4132638 | US5254253 | US5342522 | US6787035 | US4915840 | US4705633 | US7105091 | USR32429 | US6863818 | US5151187 | US6706185 | US20040016698 | US4731185 | US5234595 | US4780198 | US5993503 | US5846424 | US5126049 | US5019266 | US5531896 | US5746919 | US5611927 | US5098567 | US6814868 | US5543051 | US6605220 | US6217768 | US3756946 | US5114587 | US4842732 | US5128040 | US5818412 | US4370233 | US6712970 | US3617540 | US20070051677 | US6454949 | US4162153 | US3259566 | US5246585 | US4141822 | US4975197 | US4790939 | US4323367 | US5288405 | US5288406 | US4279753 | US2893957 | US4643830 | US5858222 | US4568462 | US20070000836 | US5811008 | US5725772 | US4568457 | US4160724 | US4284510 | US5773526 | US5482630 | US4374730 | US5651891 | US6383387 | US6113788 | US3544476 | US6066256 | US3964998 | US6039874 | US3907672 | US3047492 | US6805806 | US5316682 | US4999111 | US4818391 | US5304308 | US5356537 | US4056465 | US4956094 | US4271026 | US5919367 | US5505862 | US6352643 | US5389258 | US6884355 | US6585895 | US5853588 | US4675114 | US6660163 | US5582734 | US7208090 | US6893567 | US5601719 | US20010045390 | US7258791 | US20060113243 | US5022993 | US4522722 | US6054044 | US6630067 | US4351729 | US5989428 | US5376242 | US4849108 | US5626755 | US4537682 | US5650069 | US4961854 | US5182021 | US4599167 | US4797212 | US5137636 | US6833074 | US4867883 | US5514278 | US5543063 | US6416668 | US5514277 | US6592762 | US4042493 | US4491522 | US5733455 | US6555002 | US5733456 | US4407717 | US4632758 | US4180459 | US6613238 | US6015496 | US4891136 | US6117323 | US6004463 | US6047768 | US5624562 | US4277342 | US5624565 | US5051191 | US6527956 | US5824222 | US4527947 | US5480548 | US5833856 | US5013442 | JP1988302996 | WO1994024055 | JP1984052597 | GB2006743 | EP0408878 | JP199086P2000 | RU1596752 | DE4444335 | EP0440996 | WO1993015026 | JP1991042019 | JP1994091285 | JP2000210542 | EP1236686 | JP1988130197 | WO2003072512 | NL9301791 | DE4238708 | JP1985084199 | JP1986192389 | JP1984032999 | EP0106043 | JP1988138986
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		180
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		68316207 | 78016906
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2007-03-07 | 2006-03-07
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		SIEMENS WATER TECHNOLOGIES CORP.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		SIEMENS WATER TECHNOLOGIES CORP.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Warrendale, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Warrendale, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		ABU-ORF, MOHAMMAD, M.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		ABU-ORF, MOHAMMAD, M.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Pittman, NJ
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Pittman, NJ
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BARRY, CHESTER T
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

