<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7445801
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US10165482
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Stable bicarbonate-based solution in a single container
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Stable single bicarbonate-based solutions are provided. The bicarbonate-based single solution of the present invention includes at least calcium and bicarbonate and is stored or packaged in a sterile manner within a container with a gas barrier. The single solutions of the present invention can remain stable for three months or more. In this regard, the stable and single bicarbonate-based solutions of the present invention can be readily and effectively used during medical therapy, such as dialysis therapy.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2002-06-07
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2002
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2002-06
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2008-11-04
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2008-11
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		A61K33/00 | A61K31/7004 | B01D61/24 | A61K31/47 | A61K31/195 | A61P7/08
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		A61K33/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		A
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		A61
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		A61K
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		A61K33
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		604/408 | 514/738 | 604/403 | 514/561 | 424/717 | 514/23 | 424/677 | 424/682 | 210/645 | 424/722 | 210/646
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		604/408
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		604
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		EP1511501A1 | US20030232093A1 | JP2009131669A | JP2009131668A | JP2005530537A | AU2003232431A1 | US7445801 | WO2003103688A1 | AU2003232431A8 | MXPA04012299A
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		10
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Heering et al., Acid-base balance and substitution fluid during continuous hemofiltration, Kidney International, vol. 56, Suppl. 72 (1999) pp. S-37-S-40. cited by other . | Richardson et al., Bicarbonate, L-Lactate, and D-Lactate Balance in Intermittent Peritoneal Dialysis, Peritoneal Dialysis Bulletin, vol. 6, No. 4, 1986, pp. 178-185. cited by other . | The Merck Index, 12.sup.th Ed., Merck Research Laboratories, Whitehouse Station, NJ, 9 1472 (1996). cited by other . | European communication dated Apr. 25, 2008 (4 pgs.). cited by other. | Zimmerman et al., Continuous veno-venous haemodialysis with a novel bicarbonate dialysis solution: prospective cross-over comparison with a lactate buffered solution, Nephrology Dialysis Transplantation, (1999) vol. 14, pp. 2387-2391. cited by other . | Barenbrock et al., Effects of bicarbonate- and lactate-buffered replacement fluids on cardiovascular outcome in CVVH patients, Kidney International, vol. 58 (2000) pp. 1751-1757. cited by other . | Manns et al., Continuous Renal Replacement Therapies: An Update, American Journal of Kidney Diseases, vol. 32, No. 2 Aug. 1998; pp. 185-207. cited by other . | Tjiang, Boen San, A Clinical Study of Factors Governing its Effectiveness, Peritoneal Dialysis, p. 76, Van Gorcum &amp; Co., Assen, The Netherlands (1959). cited by other . | Feriani et al., Short-Term Clinical Study with Bicarbonate-Containing Peritoneal Dialysis Solution, Peritoneal Dialysis International, vol. 13, pp. 296-301 (1993). cited by other . | Schambye et al., Bicarbonate-versus Lactate-Based CAPD fluids: A Biocompatibility Study in Rabbits, Peritoneal Dialysis International, vol. 12, pp. 281-286 (1992). cited by other . | Uthoff et al., Improved Correction of Acidosis in Acute Renal Failure Using a Bicarbonate Buffered Substitution Solution, Nephrology (1997), Suppl. 1, P1598. cited by other . | Manahan et al., Peritoneal Dialysis using bicarbonate-containing solution sterilized by ultrafiltration, The International Journal of Artificial Organs, vol. 14 No. 8, 1999, pp. 463-465. cited by other . | Ing., et al., Bicarbonate-Buffered Peritoneal Dialysis, The International Journal of Artificial Organ, vol. 8, No. 3, p. 121-124 (1985). cited by other . | Kierdorf et al., Lactate- or bicarbonate-buffered solutions in continuous extracorporeal renal replacement therapies, Kidney International, vol. 56, Suppl. 72 (1999) pp. S-32-S-36. cited by other . | Yatzidis, Hippocrates, A New Stable Bicarbonate Dialysis Solution for Peritoneal Dialysis: Preliminary Report, Peritoneal Dialysis International, vol. 11, pp. 224-227. cited by other . | Ing et al., Lactate-Containing Peritoneal Dialysis Solutions, International J. of Artificial Organs, vol. 16, No. 10, 1993, pp. 688-693. cited by other . | Murphy et al., Use of an Artificial Kidney, vol. 40, 1952, pp. 436-444. cited by other . | Manahan et al., Effects of Bicarbonate-Containing Versus Lactate-Containing Peritoneal Dialysis Solutions on Superoxide Production by Human Neutrophils, Artificial Organs, vol. 13, No. 6, 1989, pp. 495-497. cited by other . | Ing et al., Lactate-Containing Versus Bicarbonate-Containing Peritoneal Dialysis Solutions, Peritoneal Dialysis International, vol. 12, pp. 276-277. cited by other . | Zhou et al., Effects of an Acidic, Lactate-Based Peritoneal Dialysis Solution and its Euhydric, Bicarbonate-Based Counterpart on Neutrophilic Interacellular pH, Int. J. Artif. Organs, vol. 16, No. 12, pp. 816-819 (1993). cited by other . | Heering et al., The use of different buffers during continuous hemofiltration in critically ill patients with acute renal failure, Intensive Care Medical (1999) vol. 25, pp. 1244-1251. cited by other . | Mehta et al., Regional citrate anticoagulation for continuous arteriovenous hemodialysis in critically ill patients, Kidney International, vol. 38 (1990), pp. 976-981. cited by other . | Ing et al., Preparation of Bicarbonate-Containing Dialysate for Peritoneal Dialysis, International J. of Artificial Organs, vol. 6, No. 4, 1983, pp. 217-218. cited by other . | Feriani et al., Acid-base balance and replacement solutions in continuous renal replacement therapies, Kidney International, vol. 53, Suppl. 66 (1998), pp. S-156-S-159. cited by other . | Simonsen et al., Less Infusion Pain and Elevated Level of Cancer Antigen 125 by the Use of a New and More Biocompatible PD Fluid, Advances in Peritoneal Dialysis, vol. 12, pp. 156-160 (1996). cited by other . | van Bommel et al., Continuous Renal Replacement Therapy for Critically Ill Patients: An Update, Journal of Intensive Care Medicine, vol. 9, No. 6, Nov.-Dec. 1994, pp. 265-280. cited by other . | Thomas et al, Comparison of lactate and bicarbonate buffered haemofiltration fluids: use in critically ill patients, Nephrology Dialysis Transplantation, (1997), vol. 12, pp. 1212-1217. cited by other . | Lutkes et al., Continuous venovenous hemodialysis treatment in critically ill patients after liver transplantation, Kidney International, vol. 56 Suppl. 72 (1999) pp. S-71-S-74. cited by other . | Odel et al., Peritoneal Lavage as an Effective Means of Extraenal Excretion. A Clinical Appraisal, American Journal of Medicine, vol. 9, 63-88 (1950). cited by other . | West online, file Derwent, Acc. No. 1996-349174, JP 08164199 (1996), Abstract. cited by examiner . | American Society for Artificial Internal Organs, 1994 Abstracts, pp. 110. cited by other . | Faller et al., Loss of Ultrafiltration in Continuous Ambulatory Peritoneal Dialysis: A Role for Acetate, Peritoneal Dialysis Bulletin, Jan.-Mar. 1984, pp. 10-13. cited by other . | Schambye et al., The Cytotoxicity of Continuous Ambulatory Peritoneal Dialysis Solutions with Different Bicarbonate/Lactate Ratios, Peritoneal Dialysis International vol. 13, Suppl. 2, Oct. 1-4, pp. S116-S118 (1994). cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		33
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6232128 | US5100677 | US5827820 | US4879280 | US3878664 | US5536469 | US5945129 | US5780438 | US4959175 | US4584176 | US5039609 | US5383324 | US4372100 | US6323182 | US4396383 | US5098202 | US6020007 | US4863714 | US5211643 | US5509898 | US5092838 | US5601730 | US4489535 | US5423421 | US5431496 | US5871477 | US4761237 | US4630727 | US20030013765 | US5011826 | US5296242 | US5560403 | US5610170 | US5706937 | US4465488 | US4663166 | US5853388 | US5141492 | US4397392 | US6013294 | US5462526 | US4756838 | JP1999019178 | EP0278100 | JP1993105633 | JP1999009659 | JP3271650 | WO1991018610 | EP0437274 | JP1991195561 | JP1994105905 | WO1987003809 | JP1997301875 | WO1987003808 | EP0399549 | WO1986003407 | JP2000080033 | JP1998201821 | JP2000051348 | WO1986000239 | JP1999004872 | JP1997087182 | EP0417478 | WO1999001144 | EP0209607 | EP0457960 | EP0439061 | WO1993024108 | JP1997301860 | EP0613688 | EP0277868 | JP1997110703 | EP1166787 | EP0249667 | EP0481257 | WO1998033535 | EP0647145 | EP0165933 | DE19748290 | EP0083360 | JP1996164199 | JP1990304026 | WO1998010733 | WO1997005851 | WO1996001118 | EP0935967 | EP0086553 | JP1982056422 | FR2753099 | EP0399918 | WO1995019778 | JP1981164113 | JP1991437274 | EP0776649 | WO1999009953 | JP1996131542 | WO2001021233 | JP1995252137
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		98
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		16548202
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2002-06-07
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		BAXTER INTERNATIONAL INC. (DEERFIELD, IL), BAXTER HEALTHCARE S.A
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		BAXTER INTERNATIONAL INC. (DEERFIELD, IL), BAXTER HEALTHCARE S.A
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Zurich, CH
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Zurich, CH
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		FAICT, DIRK | DUPONCHELLE, ANNICK | TAMINNE, MICHEL | BALTEAU, PATRICK | PELUSO, FRANCESCO
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		FAICT, DIRK
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		5
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Assenede, BE
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Assenede, BE | Brussels, BE | Brussels, BE | Bothey, BE | Heverlee, BE
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		KELLY, PAULA J. BELL, BOYD &amp; LLOYD LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		RICHTER, JOHANN
	</str>
	<str name="Assistant Examiner">
		CHOI, FRANK I
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

