<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7473369
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11181681
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Methods of preparing a surface-activated titanium oxide product and of using same in water treatment processes
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A method for removing dissolved contaminants from solution using a surface-activated crystalline titanium oxide product having a high adsorptive capacity and a high rate of adsorption with respect to dissolved contaminants, in particular, arsenate and arsenite. Preferably, the titanium oxide product includes crystalline anatase having primary crystallite diameters in the range of 1-30 nm. The surface-activated titanium oxide is combined with other filter media to further improve the removal of dissolved contaminants.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2005-07-14
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2005
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2005-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-01-06
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-01
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C01G23/47 | C02F1/28
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C01G23/47
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C01G
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C01G23
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/681 | 210/665 | 423/610
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/681
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		GB2424221B | GB2424221A | US20030155302A1 | GB0601202D0 | JP2005517521A | US7473369 | GB0417808D0 | AU2003211074A1 | US20060091078A1 | US20060091079A1 | US6919029 | US7497952 | DE10392330T5 | WO2003068683A1 | MXPA04007805A | GB2400843A | GB2400843B
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		17
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		14
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Mitsuo Abe, et al.; &quot;Adsorption and Desorption Behaviour of Arsenic Compounds on Various Inorganic Ion Exchangers,&quot; Ion Exchange Advances, 326-333. cited by other . | Applicants' response to non-final Office Action dated Apr. 30, 2008, received in U.S. Appl. No. 11/176,486. cited by other . | G. R. Chumakova, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Removal of arsenic and antimony from solutions with titanium hydroxide oxide,&quot; Tsvetnye Metally (Moscow, Russian Federation) (1984) (2), 21-3. cited by other . | Qing-Hong Zhang, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Heterogeneous photocatalytic reaction of Cr(V1) reduction on nanosized titania,&quot; Gaodeng Xuexiao Huaxue Xuebao (2000), 21(10), 1547-1551. cited by other . | Dong-Seok Seo, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Preparation of TiO2 nanocrystalline powder at low temperature,&quot; Han guk Seramik Hakhoechi (2001), 384(4), 331-336. cited by other . | R. Flaig-Baumann, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Amphoteric properties of metal oxide surfaces,&quot; Fortschrittsberichte ueber Kolloide und Polymere (1971), 55 7-15. cited by other . | H. Yang, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Homogeneous and heterogeneous photocatalytic reactions involving As(III) and As(V) species in aqueous media,&quot; Journal of Photochemistry and Photobiology, A: Chemistry (1999), 123(1-3), 137-143. cited by other . | Dong-Seok Seo,e al.; Abstract of &quot;Influence of treatment conditions on crystallizaton and microstructure of TiO2 nanocrystalline powder,&quot; Advances in Technology of Materials and Materials Processing Journal (2003), 5(2), 114-118. cited by other . | Monique Bissen, et al.; &quot;TiO2-catalyzed photooxidation of arsenite to arsenate in aqueous samples,&quot; Chemosphere 44 (2001) 751-757. cited by other . | Mitsuo Abe, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Environmental Application of Hydrous Titanium Dioxide as Inorganic Ion Exchanger,&quot; 6th Symposium on Ion Exchange, Balatonfured, Hungary, Sep. 3-7, 1990. cited by other . | S. A. Onorin, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Physicochemical study of hydrated titanium dioxide and its arsenic(V) and sodium(1+) sorption products,&quot; Zhurnal Neorganicheskoi Khimii (1992), 37(6), 1223-7. cited by other . | Kemira Pigment Oy Product Data Sheet for FINNTIS 130, Jul. 2004. cited by other . | J. Takahashi, et al.; Preparations of Titania Colloids by Thermal Hydrolysis of Urea and Densification Behavior of the Colloid-Derived Monolithic Titania Gels; Journal of Sol-Gel Science and Technology 4, 15-21 (1995). cited by other . | V.V. Vol'khin, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Sorption properties of hydrated titanium dioxide and its dehydration products,&quot; Izvestiya Akademii Nauk SSSR, Neorganicheskie Materialy (1976), 12(8), 1415-18. cited by other . | S.A. Onorin, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Preparation effects on the structure and ion exchange properties of hydrated titanium dioxide,&quot; Zhurnal Neorganicheskoi Khimii (1992), 37(6), 1218-22. cited by other . | Mudanjiang Fengda Chemicals Product Data Sheet for Titanium Dioxide, Feb. 1, 2005. cited by other . | Russell Paterson, et al.; &quot;Thermodynamics of ion exchange on microcrystals of hydrous oxides,&quot; Ion Exchange Technology, Society of Chemical Industry (1984), 276-283. cited by other . | J. Sabate, et al.; &quot;Comparison of TiO2 powder suspensions and TiO2 ceramic membranes supported on glass as photocatalytic systems in the reduction of chromium (VI),&quot; Journal of Molecular Catalysis, 71 (1992), 57-68. cited by other . | Toshio Ashitani, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Composite inorganic oxide adsorbent for anions removal from polluted water and its preparation,&quot; Jpn. Kokai Tokkyo Koho (2000), 6 pp. cited by other . | Final Office Action dated Aug. 14, 2008, received in U.S. Appl. No. 11/176,586. cited by other . | R. Flaig-Baumann, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Surface chemistry of titanium dioxide. III. Surface reactions of basic hydroxyl groups,&quot; Zeitschrift fuer Anorganische und Allgemenie Chemie (1970), 372(3), 296-307. cited by other . | Applicants' response to non-final Office Action dated Aug. 14, 2008, received in U.S. Appl. No. 11/176,586. cited by other . | Michael R. Prairie, et al.; &quot;An Investigation of TiO2 Photocatalysis for the Treatment of Water Contaminated with Metals and Organic Chemicals,&quot; Environ. Sci. Technol. 1993, 27, 1776-1782. cited by other . | Kerr- McGee Chemicals LLC Product Data Sheet for TRONOX Hydrate Paste (undated). cited by other . | Heyne, Werner; Untersuchungen Zur Reinigung von Grubenwassern Des Uranbergbaus An Regenerierbaren Adsorbern, Insbesondere Titanoxidhydrat; Verein fur Kernverfahrenstechnik und Analytik Rossendorf e V.; 255-262 (1995). cited by other . | Interview Summary dated Sep. 5, 2008, received in U.S. Appl. No. 11/176,586. cited by other. | S. A. Onorin, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Granulated sorbent based on titanium hydroxide,&quot; Russian Patent No. SU 1150024, 19850415. cited by other . | Hiroshi Sato, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Removal of arsenic from mine drainage wastewater,&quot; Jpn. Kokai Tokkyo Koho (1979), 5 pp., Patent No. JP 54108463, 19790825. cited by other . | Non-final Office Action dated Apr. 30, 2008, received in U.S. Appl. No. 11/176,486. cited by other . | Jacob A. Marinsky, et al.; &quot;New Inorganic Ion Exchangers,&quot; Ion Exchange and Solvent Extraction, 92-120. cited by other . | Dong-Seok Seo, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Effect of aging agents on the formation of TiO2 nanocrystalline powder,&quot; Materials Letters (2001), 51(2), 115-119. cited by other . | Tatineni Balaji, et al.; &quot;Adsorption Characteristics of As(III) and As(V) with Titanium Dioxide Loaded Amberlite XAD-7 Resin,&quot; Analytical Sciences, Dec. 2002, vol. 18, 1345-1349. cited by other . | Dong-Seok Seo, et al.; Abstract of &quot;Synthesis of TiO2 nanocrystalline powder by aging at low temperature,&quot; Journal of Crystal Growth (2001), 233(1-2), 298-302. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		33
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6719869 | US6331351 | US5189092 | US6383273 | US6338830 | US3332737 | US4474853 | US5630995 | US5639550 | US6797167 | US5948726 | US20060091078 | US4954476 | US20040178142 | US5468463 | US5227053 | US6774147 | US4264421 | US4665050 | US6251823 | US5766784 | US6375923 | US5824145 | US6306361 | US6444608 | US5821186 | US6268307 | US6342191 | US5294315 | US20020077249 | US6653356 | US5997829 | US5973175 | US6409961 | US5277931 | US6383395 | US20010016264 | US6001326 | US6162759 | US6191067 | US5331037 | US6340433 | US4692431 | US5053139 | US6086844 | US5840111 | US4262421 | US6517804 | US4313844 | US6248217 | US5618437 | US4661282 | US6399540 | US4803064 | US6919029 | DE4216122 | JP1982150481 | WO2001049613 | WO2001083376 | GB1189746 | WO2000046154 | WO2002082463 | EP1167296 | DE10116953 | JP1978122691 | CA1122876 | WO2002053262 | EP1182169 | JP1983045705
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		69
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		18168105 | 30455002 | 35705102
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2005-07-14 | 2002-11-26 | 2002-02-14
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		THE TRUSTEES OF THE STEVENS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		THE TRUSTEES OF THE STEVENS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Hoboken, NJ
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Hoboken, NJ
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		MENG, XIAOGUANG | DADACHOV, MAZAKHIR | KORFIATIS, GEORGE, P. | CHRISTODOULATOS, CHRISTOS | MOLL, DAVID, J. | ONIFER, GEOFREY, PAUL | RICE, DANIEL, B. | REIM, ROBERT, E. | VANCE, FREDRICK, W. | GOLTZ, HARLAN, ROBERT | HAN, CHAN | HARRIS, WILLIAM, I.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		MENG, XIAOGUANG
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		12
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Highland, Park, NJ
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Highland, Park, NJ | Mahopac, NY | Basking, Ridge, NJ | Basking, Ridge, NJ | Midland, MI | Sanford, MI | Shepherd, MI | Midland, MI | Freeland, MI | Midland, MI | Midland, MI | Midland, MI
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		GREENBERG TRAURIG, LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		HOPKINS, ROBERT A
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

