<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7431832
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11368324
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Systems for reducing water contamination
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		In some embodiments, a system may reduce contaminants in water. A system may include a biofilm in a container. The biofilm may be formed from one or more bacteria coupled to one or more substrates. The bacteria may be selected to maximize the reduction of contaminants in water. The system may include one or more bacteria generators to provide bacteria to the biofilm and/or one or more air sources to provide an air bubble stream to the container and/or the bacteria generator. In some embodiments, bacteria may be preserved in a starvation phase. Bacteria may be incubated until they reach a starvation phase. The bacteria may then be preserved as beads or immobilized on a substrate. The preserved bacteria may be used in a system for the reduction of contaminants in water.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2006-03-03
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2006
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2006-03
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2008-10-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2008-10
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/150 | 435/297.1 | 435/289.1 | 435/303.1 | 210/220 | 210/616
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/150
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US20070205151A1 | US7431832
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		&quot;Aeration of Animal Wastes Newman Environmental Solutions, Inc. (NESi) Greenville, N.C.,&quot; available on the Advanced Aeration, Inc. website at http://www.advancedaeration.com. Published 1998. cited by other . | Lewandowski, Z. et al., &quot;Heavy Metals Removal from Contaminated Water Solutions,&quot; available from the HSRC The Great Plains/Rocky Mountain Hazardous Substance Research Center website at http://www.engg.ksu.edu/HSRC/heavy.html. Jan. 25, 2005. cited by other . | Co-Pending U.S. Appl. No. 11/368,319 entitled, &quot;Bacteria-Alginate Bead Systems and Methods&quot; to Jones et al., available in PAIR, 2006. cited by other . | Uemoto, Hiroaki and Hiroshi Saiki, &quot;Distribution of Nitrosomonas europaea and Paracoccus denitrificans Immobilized in Tubular Polymeric Gel for Nitrogen Removal&quot; Applied and Environmental Microbiology, Feb. 2000, p. 816-819, vol.66, No. 2. cited by other . | &quot;Bioremediation of Contaminated Soil, Groundwater, and Wastewater&quot; from the Environmental Biotechnology Laboratory website at http://www.nies.go.jp/kenko/biotech/research/biore Published 2002. cited by other . | Co-Pending U.S. Appl. No. 11/367,762 entitled, &quot;Systems and Methods of Creating a Biofilm for the Reduction of Water Contamination&quot; to Jones et al., available in PAIR, 2006. cited by other . | Roheim, Jon R., &quot;Low Cost Automated on Site Systems for Growing and Dispensing Vegetative Bacteria,&quot; available on the ECOBionics website at http://www.wateronline.com/ecommcenters/ecobionics.html. Published Jan. 20, 2005. cited by other . | &quot;Apex Innovation Test Development of Vaccum Bubble.RTM. Aerator for Remediation of Petroleum Contaminated Sites,&quot; available on the Advanced Aeration, Inc. website at http://www.advancedaeration.com. Published 2004. cited by other . | Kaprelyants, Arseny S. and Douglas B. Kell, &quot;Dormancy in Stationary-Phase Cultures of Micrococcus luteus: Flow Cytometric Analysis of Starvation and Resuscitation.&quot; Applied and Environmental Microbiology, Oct. 1993, vol. 59, No. 10, p. 3187-3196. cited by other . | Co-Pending U.S. Appl. No. 11/368,330 entitled, &quot;Systems and Methods for Preserving Bacteria in A Starvation Phase&quot; to Jones et al., available in PAIR, 2006. cited by other . | Jodra, Y. and F. Mijangos, &quot;Ion Exchange Selectives of calcium alginate gels for heavy metals,&quot; WAter Sci. Technol., vol. 43, No. 2, 2001, pp. 237-244, available on PubMed at http://www.ncbi.nim.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt- =Abstract&amp;list.sub.--uids=11380185&amp;query.sub.--h1=1. cited by other . | Co-Pending U.S. Appl. No. 11/368,282 entitled, &quot;Mobile Bioremediation Systems and Methods&quot; to Jones et al., available in PAIR, 2006. cited by other . | Hoage et al. &quot;Aeration Pretreatment for Commercial Restaurants.&quot; Advanced Aeration, Inc. website. Published 2006. cited by other. | Co-Pending U.S. Appl. No. 11/368,320 entitled, &quot;Systems and Methods of Reducing Metal Compounds From Fluids Using Alginate Beads&quot; to Jones et al., available in PAIR, 2006. cited by other . | Ogden, K. L. et al., &quot;Investigating the use of biosorption to treat copper CMP wastewater,&quot; www.micromagazine.com, Jul./Aug. 2001. cited by other . | Lowry &quot;Comparison of Four Treatment Methods for the Removal of Lipids and Food Waste in a Grease Trap Environment.&quot; Advanced Aeration, Inc. website. Published 2004. cited by other . | Hoage et al. &quot;Innovation Aeration Retrofit of Existing Failed Septic Systems around Lake Livingston, Texas.&quot; Advanced Aeration, Inc. website. Published 2004. cited by other . | Ibanez et al. &quot;Hydrometallugry&quot;, 2002, vol. 64, pp. 89-99. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		18
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US8347960
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US7022234 | US6921477 | US6989102 | US6039875 | US6335191 | US6849445 | US5599451 | US7175766 | US6841515 | US6758633 | US5756304 | US6719902 | US6790365 | US5217616 | US6790355
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		15
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		36832406
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2006-03-03
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		SAM HOUSTON STATE UNIVERSITY
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		SAM HOUSTON STATE UNIVERSITY
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Huntsville, TX
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Huntsville, TX
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		PLISHKER, GORDON, ALF | JONES, ROBERT, GAVIN | HOLM, RALPH, EDWARD | QUINN, JOSHUA, RICHARD
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		PLISHKER, GORDON, ALF
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		The, Woodlands, TX
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		The, Woodlands, TX | Huntsville, TX | Texas, City, TX | Huntsville, TX
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		MEYERTONS, HOOD, KIVLIN, KOWERT &amp; GOETZEL, P.C. MEYERTONS, ERIC B.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BARRY, CHESTER T.
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		1
	</str>
</doc>

