<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7476324
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US10997333
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Methods of synthesizing a ferrate oxidant and its use in ballast water
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Novel devices for synthesizing ferrate and uses thereof are described. One aspect of the invention relates to devices and systems for synthesizing ferrate at a site proximal to the site of use.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2004-11-24
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2004
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2004-11
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-01-13
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-01
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C01G49/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C01G49/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C01G
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C01G49
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/758 | 210/717 | 210/716
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/758
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US20050271575A1 | US7476324
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		U.S. Appl. No. 10/047,460, Ciampi, et al., filed Jan. 14, 2002. cited by other . | Licht, S., et al., &quot;Energetic iron(VI) chemistry: The super-iron battery&quot;, Science, vol. 285, pp. 1039-1042, (Aug. 13, 1999). cited by other . | Aubertin, N., et al., &quot;Synthesis of potassium sulfatoferrate and its use in wastewater treatment&quot;, Revue des Sciences de L'Eau, vol. 9, No. 1, pp. 17-30 (1996). cited by other . | Bouzek, K., et al., &quot;The cyclic voltammetric study of ferrate(VI) production&quot;, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry, vol. 425, pp. 125-137, (1997). cited by other . | Powell Fabrication and Manufacturing Inc, drawing of Batch Bleach System, Apr. 25, 2002. cited by other . | Stupine, D.Y., et al., &quot;Coprecipitation of .sup.152Eu with iron(III) hydroxide formed upon reduction of sodium ferrate(VI) in aqueous medium&quot;, Radiochemistry, vol. 37, No. 4, pp. 329-332 (1995). cited by other . | Kiselev, Y.K., et al., &quot;The preparation of alkali metal ferrate(VI)&quot;, Russian Journal of Inorganic Chemistry., vol. 34, No. 9, pp. 1250-1253, (1989). cited by other . | Stoupine, D., et al., &quot;The peculiarities of the iron oxides/hydroxides sediment formed in sodium ferrate(VI) use as coagulant in water treatment&quot;, Proceedings Of The International Conference On Environmental Engineering And Chemical Engineering, (ICEECE'97) (eds. Qian, Y. and Huanqin, C), South China University of Technology Press, Guangzhou, pp. 29-32, (1997). cited by other . | Licht, S., et al., &quot;Solid phase modifiers of the Fe(VI) cathode: effects on the super-iron battery&quot;, Electrochemistry Communications, vol. 1, pp. 527-531, (1999). cited by other . | Lescuras-Darrou, et al., Electrochemical ferrate generation for waste water treatment using cast irons with high silicon contents, Journal of Applied Electrochemistry 32: 57-63, 2002. cited by other . | Licht, S., et al., &quot;Chemical synthesis of battery grade super-iron barium and potassium Fe(VI) ferrate compounds&quot;, Journal of Power Sources, vol. 99, pp. 7-14, (2001). cited by other . | Bouzek, K., et al., &quot;Electrochemical production of ferrate(VI) using sinusoidal alternating current superimposed on direct current: grey and white cast iron electrodes&quot;, Electrochimica Acta, vol. 44, pp. 547-557 (1998). cited by other . | Ozemoi, M.I., et al., &quot;Sulfide ion oxidation by sodium ferrate(VI) in water&quot;, Ecol. Chem., vol. 4, No. 3, pp. 208-212, (1995). cited by other . | Neveux, N., et al., &quot;Synthesis of stabilized potassium ferrate and its applications in water treatment&quot;, EPD Congress, (Ed. B. Mishra), pp. 215-224, (1999). cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 10/246,575, Ciampi, et al., filed Sep. 17, 2002. cited by other. | Deininger, J.P, et al., &quot;Developments in transurancic element polishing from radioactive wastewaters using ferrate(FEO.sub.4.sup.-2) chemical technology&quot;, Waste Manage. '90, vol. 1, pp. 789-795 (1990). cited by other . | Wood, R. H., &quot;The heat, free engergy and entropy of the ferrate (VI) ion&quot;, J. Am. Chem. Soc., vol. 80, pp. 2038-2041 (1957). cited by other . | Scholder, R., &quot;Recent investigations on oxometallates and double oxides&quot;, Angew. Chem. Internat. Edit., vol. 1, No. 4, pp. 220, (1962). cited by other . | International Search Report and Written Opinion dated Jun. 30, 2006 in connection with PCT/US2005/013689. cited by other . | Bouzek, K., et al., &quot;Influence of electrolyte hydrodynamics on current yield in ferrate(VI) production by anodic iron dissolution&quot;, Collect. Czech. Chem. Commun., vol. 65, pp. 133-140, (2000). cited by other . | Bartzatt, R., et al., &quot;Removal of nitrosamines from waste water by potassium ferrate oxidation&quot;, Archives of Environmental Health, vol. 46, No. 5, pp. 313-315 (1991). cited by other . | CiCi, M., et al., &quot;Production of some coagulant materials from galvanizing workshop waste&quot;, Waste Management, vol. 17, No. 7, pp. 407-410, (1997). cited by other . | Licht, S., et al., &quot;SrFeO.sub.4 synthesis, Fe(VI) characterization and the strontium super-iron battery&quot;, Electrochemistry Communications, vol. 3, pp. 340-345, (2001). cited by other . | Jiang, et al., Progress in the development and use of ferrate(VI) salt as an oxidant and coagulant for water and wastewater treatment, Water Research 36 (2002) 1397-1408. cited by other . | Bartzatt, R., et al., &quot;The kinetics of oxidation of low molecular weight aldehydes by potassium ferrate&quot;, Transition Met. Chem., vol. 11, pp. 414-416 (1986). cited by other . | Kazama, F., et al., &quot;Oxidative changes of organic characters in the waters by ferrate (VI) treatment&quot;, Department of Environmental Engineering, vol. 35, pp. 117-122 (1984). cited by other . | Bouzek, K., et al. &quot;Influence of anode material on current yields during ferrate(VI) production by anodic iron dissolution Part I: Current efficiency during anodic dissolution of grey cast iron to ferrate(VI) in concentrated alkali hydroxide solutions&quot;, Journal of Applied Electrochemistry, vol. 26, pp. 919-923, (1996). cited by other . | Carr,J. D., et al., &quot;Properties of ferrate (VI) in aquenous solution: an alternative oxidant in wastewater treatment&quot;, Proceedings of the Conference on Water Chlorination and Chemical Environmental Impact Health Effects, (ED. Lewis Chelsea), pp. 1285-1298 (1985). cited by other . | Kazama, F., et al., Oxidation of organic matters in waste waters and fluvic acid by potassium ferrate (VI), Department of Environmental Engineering, vol. 34, pp. 100-104 (1984). cited by other . | Audette, R. J. et al., &quot;Ferrate (VI) ion, a novel oxidizing agent&quot;, Tetrahedron Letters, No. 3, pp. 279-282 (1971). cited by other . | Denvir, A., et al. &quot;Electrochemical generation of ferrate, Part I: Dissolution of an iron wool bed anode&quot; Journal of Applied Electrochemistry, vol. 26, pp. 815-822, (1996). cited by other . | Sylvester, P., et al., &quot;Ferrate treatment for removing chromium from high-level radioactive tank waste&quot;. Environmental Science and Technology, vol. 35, No. 1, pp. 216-221, (2001). cited by other . | Gilbert, M., et al., &quot;Analytical Notes-An investigation of the applicability of ferrate ion for disinfection&quot;, Water Technology/Quality, pp. 495-497, (Sep. 1976). cited by other . | Jihui Qu et al., &quot;Removal of Algae from Drinking Water by Ferrate,&quot; Annual lecture book of Japan Society on Water Environment, Mar. 15, 2000, Vo. 34.sup.th, p. 185. cited by other . | Stoupine, D., et al., &quot;The simulation of heavy metals removal from wastewaters by the sodium ferrate(VI) treatment&quot;, Proceedings of the International Conference on Environmental Engineering and Chemical Engineering, (ICEECE'97) (eds. Qian, Y. and Huanqin, C), South China University of Technology Press, Guangzhou, pp. 33-36, (1997). cited by other . | Kazama, F., &quot;Viral inactiviation by potassium ferrate&quot;, Wat. Sci. Tech. , vol. 31, No. 5-6, pp. 165-168 (1995). cited by other . | Williams, D. et al., &quot;Preparation and alcohol oxidation studies of the ferrate (VI) ion, FeO.sub.4.sup.2&quot;, Inorganica Chimica Acta, vol. 8, pp. 177-183, (1974). cited by other . | Goff, H., et al., &quot;Studies on the mechanism of isotopic oxygen exchange and reduction of ferrate (VI) ion (FeO.sub.4.sup.2-).sup.1&quot;, Journal of the American Chemical Society, vol. 93, No. 23, (Nov. 17, 1971). cited by other . | Schreyer, J.M., et al. &quot;Stability of the ferrate(VI) ion in aqueous solution&quot;, Analytical Chemistry, vol. 23, No. 9, pp. 1312-1314, (1951). cited by other . | Thompson, G., et al., J. Am. Chem. Soc., &quot;New derivative of dinaphthylethane&quot;, vol. 73, pp. 1379-1381 (1951). cited by other . | de Luca, S.J., et al., &quot;Quality improvement of biosolids by ferrate(VI) oxidation of offensive odour compounds&quot;, Wat. Sci. Tech. vol. 33(3), pp 119-130, (1996). cited by other . | Wagner, W.F., et al., &quot;Factors affecting the stability of aqueous potassium ferrate(VI) solutions&quot;, Analytical Chemistry, vol. 24, pp. 1947-1948, (1952). cited by other . | Kazama, F., &quot;Respiratory inhibition of Sphaerotilus by potassium ferrate&quot; Journal of Fermentation and Bioengineering, vol. 67, No. 6, pp. 369-373, (1989). cited by other . | Powell Fabrication and Manufacturing Inc, Guide to Powell Products &amp; Services, 30 pp. undated. cited by other . | Potts, M.E., et al., &quot;Removal of radionuclides in wastewaters utilizing potassium ferrate(VI)&quot;, Water Environment Research, vol. 66, No. 2, pp. 107-109, (1994). cited by other . | White, D.A., et al. &quot;A preliminary investigation into the use of sodium ferrate in water treatment&quot;, Environmental Technology, vol. 19, pp. 1157-1161, (1998). cited by other . | Bartzatt, R., et al., &quot;Removal of toxic metals and nonmetals from contaminated water&quot;, Journal of Toxicaology and Environmental Health, vol. 35, pp. 205-210, (1992). cited by other . | Bouzek, K. et al., &quot;Influence of anode material composition on the stability of electrochemically-prepared ferrate(VI) solutions&quot;, Journal of Chemical Technology and Biotechnology, vol. 74, pp. 1188-1194, (1999). cited by other . | Licht, S., et al., &quot;Insoluble Fe(VI) compounds: effects on the super-iron battery&quot;, Electrochemistry Communications, vol. 1, pp. 522-526, (1999). cited by other . | BeMiller, J.N., et al., &quot;Oxidation of carbohydrates with the ferrate (VI) ion&quot;, Tetrahedron Letters, No. 40, pp. 4143-4146, (1972). cited by other . | International Preliminary Report on Patentability and Written Opinion of the International Searching Authority dated Oct. 26, 2006 from PCT/US2005/013689. cited by other . | Fagan, J., et al., &quot;Biofouling control with ferrate (VI)&quot;, Environ. Sci. Technol., vol. 17, pp. 123-125 (1983). cited by other . | Grube, G., et al., &quot;The electrolytic formation of the alkali salts of ferrous oxide and of ferric oxide&quot;, Z. Elektrochem., vol. 26, pp. 459-471, (1920). cited by other . | Venkatadri, A.S., et al., &quot;Ferrate(VI) analysis by cyclic voltammetry&quot;, Analytical Chemistry, vol. 43, No. 8, pp. 1115-1119, (Jul. 1971). cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		54
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US7694432 | US8293196 | US8124036
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6471788 | US4983306 | US4304760 | US4198296 | US5284642 | US5380443 | US6187347 | US4435257 | US5997812 | US5370857 | US4545974 | US2758084 | US4385045 | US4405573 | US4451338 | US2536703 | US2835553 | US5217584 | US5234603 | US5746994 | US5202108 | US4435265 | US3985770 | US4551326 | US4991497 | US4500499 | US2758090 | WO2002006160 | WO1999029628 | JP1994171953 | JP1980075925 | WO1997033833 | JP1993504506 | JP1983110435
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		34
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US | US | US | US | US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		99733304 | 82426804 | 24657502 | 4746002 | 90516501 | 21840900 | 29988401
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2004-11-24 | 2004-04-14 | 2002-09-17 | 2002-01-14 | 2001-07-12 | 2000-07-14 | 2001-06-21
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		FERRATE TREATMENT TECHNOLOGIES, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		FERRATE TREATMENT TECHNOLOGIES, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Belle Isle, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Belle Isle, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		CIAMPI, LEE, EDWARD | DALY, LUKE, J.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		CIAMPI, LEE, EDWARD
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		St., Paul, MN
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		St., Paul, MN | Belle, Isle, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		KNOBBE MARTENS OLSON &amp; BEAR LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BOS, STEVEN
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		1
	</str>
</doc>

