<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7498163
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11005815
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Process for reducing solid waste volume and landfill mass
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The present invention is related to a process for reducing solid waste volume and landfill mass. More particularly, the process of the present invention is directed to reducing organic waste with or without production and collection of a useful product. The process of the present invention involves supplying at least one oxidizing agent in the presence of an aqueous medium into organic materials. The oxidizing agent oxidizes and breaks down a portion of these materials. After addition of the oxidizing agent, at least one species of microorganism may be supplied into the channel and the microorganism consumes the oxidized organic material.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2004-12-07
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2004
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2004-12
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-03-03
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-03
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/34 | B09B3/00 | C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/34
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		405/129.25 | 405/129.15 | 405/129.95 | 405/129.65 | 435/262 | 435/42 | 405/129.27
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		405/129.25
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		405
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		EP1444058A4 | US20030077770A1 | EP1444058A1 | WO2003033181A1 | US6835560 | US7498163 | US20050141966A1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		7
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		13
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		McKenzie, et al., Aflatoxicosis in Turkey Poults is Prevented by Treatment of Naturally Contaminated Corn with Ozone Generated by Electrolysis, Environment and Health, 1094-1102, 1998. cited by other . | B.A. Meiners, R.E. Peters and J.B. Mudd, Effects of Ozone on Indole Compounds and Rat Lung Monoamine Oxidase, p. 99-112, 1977, Environmental Research. cited by other . | I.R. Komanapalli and B.H.S. Lau, Inactivation of bacteriophage .lamda., Escherichia coli, and Candida albicans by ozone, Appl Microbiol Biotechnol, 49:766-769, 1998. cited by other . | Finch, et al., Comparison of Giardia lamblia and Giardia muris Cyst Inactivation by Ozone, p. 3674-3680, Nov. 1993, Applied and Environmental Microbiology. cited by other . | Finch, et al., Ozone Inactivation of Cryptosporidium parvum in Demand-Free Phosphate Buffer Determined by In Vitro Excystation and Animal Infectivity, p. 4203-4210, Dec. 1993, Applied and Environmental Microbiology. cited by other . | William A. Feder, Bioassaying for Ozone With Pollen Systems, vol. 37:117-123, Jan. 1981, Environmental Health Prospectives. cited by other . | Klare, et al., Degradation of Nitrogen Containing Organic Compounds by Combined Photocatalysis and Ozonation, Chemosphere, 38:2013-2027, 1999. cited by other . | Evan, III., Environmental Protection Agency, Cincinnati, Ohio, editor: Ozone In Water And Wastewater Treatment, Ann Arbor Science Publishers, Inc., Ann Arbor, Michigan; Copyright 1972. cited by other. | Muela, et al., Discharge of disinfected wastewater in recipient aquatic systems: fate of allochthonous bacterial and autochthonous protozoa populations, Journal of Applied Microbiology, 85:263-270, 1998. cited by other . | Byun, et al., Gamma Irradiation and Ozone Treatment for Inactivation of Escherichia coli O157:H7 in Culture Media, Journal of Food Protection, 61:728-730, 1998. cited by other . | I.Arana, P.Santorum, A.Muela and I.Barcina, Chlorination and ozonation of waste-water:comparative analysis of efficacy through the effect on Escherichia coli membranes, p. 883-888, 1999, Journal of Applied Microbiology. cited by other . | Watkins, et al., Ozonation of Swine Manure Wastes to Control Odors And Reduce the Concentrations of Pathogens And Toxic Fermentation Metabolites, Ozone Science &amp; Engineering, 19:425-437, 1997. cited by other . | Finch, et al., Recovery of a Marker Strain of Escherichia coli from Ozonated Water by Membrane Filtration, p. 2894-2896, Dec. 1987, Applied and Environmental Microbiology. cited by other . | Restaino, et al., Efficacy of Ozonated Water against Various Food-Related Microorganisms, p. 3471-3475, Sep. 1995, Applied and Environmental Microbiology. cited by other . | Serge Chiron, Antonio Rodriguez and Amadeo Fernandez-Alba, Application of gas and liquid chromatography-mass spectrometry to the evaluation of pirimiphos methyl degradation products in industrial water under ozone treatment, Journal of Chromatography A, 823:97-107, 1998. cited by other . | Y.H. Chang and B.W. Sheldon, Application of Ozone with Physical Wastewater Treatments to Recondition Poultry Process Waters, p. 1078-1087, Jun. 6, 1988, Journal Series of the North Carolina Agriculture Research Series, Raleigh, NC 27695-7601. cited by other . | E. Smet &amp; H. Van Langenhove, Abatement of volatile organic sulfur compounds in odorous emissions from bio-industry, Biodegration 9:273-284,1998. cited by other . | Yu, et al., Pretreatment and Biodegradability Enhancement of DSD Acid Manufacturing Wastewater, Chemosphere, 37:487-494, 1998. cited by other . | Duane L. Peavy and Edward J. Fairchild II, Toxicologic Interactions between Ozone and Bacterial Exdotoxin, p. 63-71, 1987, Environmental Research. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		19
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US8153006
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6423229 | US4404110 | US6056885 | US4608338 | US4178239 | US4752316 | US3846292 | US4256574 | US20020192774 | US5688685 | US6835560 | US4132637 | US5633163 | US3838199 | US3591491 | US5342522 | US3825494 | US2477815 | US3232434 | US4915842 | US4003790 | US6303034 | US5447850 | US3459303 | US3660277 | US5424195 | US5466367 | US3806448 | US5641679 | US3709364 | US2178818 | US3577341 | US5520888 | USR22444 | US5679257 | US5897785 | US3638793 | US5011599 | US6500333 | US3982499 | US5078965 | US5773283 | US20020061270 | US3918404 | US6077548 | US5753494 | US4042458 | US3607737 | US5070016 | US5707856 | US2209613 | US4214887 | US6117324 | US6340581 | US3617537 | US5854061 | US3996105 | US3803029 | US3485750 | US4451567 | JP2000189103 | JP199810225694 | JP2001025789
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		63
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		581504 | 98301201
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2004-12-07 | 2001-10-18
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		CLEMSON UNIVERSITY
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		CLEMSON UNIVERSITY
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Clemson, SC
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Clemson, SC
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		GREENE, ANNEL, K.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		GREENE, ANNEL, K.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Clemson, SC
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Clemson, SC
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		DORITY &amp; MANNING, P.A.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		LILLING, HERBERT J.
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		1
	</str>
</doc>

