<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7445715
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11284792
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		System for treating wastewater and a controlled reaction-volume module usable therein
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A wastewater treatment system including a biological reactor is disclosed. At least one controlled-reaction-volume module is provided to the biological reactor. The at least one controlled-reaction-volume module includes a fixed-film media for supporting a biological growth. At least one mixer, such as, for example, a high momentum mixer, for communicate a fluid to the at least one controlled-reaction-volume module so that wastewater and the biological growth communicate to thereby treat the wastewater.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2005-11-22
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2005
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2005-11
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2008-11-04
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2008-11
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/242.2 | 210/263 | 210/264 | 210/242.1 | 210/618 | 210/617 | 210/220 | 210/615
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/242.2
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US20060124543A1 | US20090038999A1 | US7445715
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		5
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Pulsed Hydraulics, Inc., Variable &quot;Speed&quot; Tank Mixing With No In-basin Moving Parts, article, Copyright 2005, 8 pages, internet address http://phiwater.com/, Pulsed Hydraulics, Inc., Bellevue, WA. cited by other . | Entex Technologies, Inc., BioWeb fixed media system, article, Copyright 2004, pp. 1-2, Entex Technologies, Inc., Chapel Hill, NC. cited by other . | Terry L. Johnson, Andrew Shaw, Heather Phillips, Nancy Choi, Thomas Lauro, Ralph Butler, and Leah Radko, A Pilot-Scale Comparison of IFAS and MBBR to Achieve Very Low Total Nitrogen Concentrations, article, Copyrght 2007, pp. 1-14, vol. 1, No. 5, Water Environment Federation, Alexandria, VA. cited by other . | Hydroxyl Systems Inc., The Hydroxyl--F3R Process innovative biological treatment technology, article, pp. 1-2, Hydroxyl Systems Inc., Sidney, BC Canada. cited by other . | Entex Technologies, Inc., Internet website: (http://www.entexinc.com/Installations.htm), pp. 1-2, Entex Technologies, Inc., Chapel Hill, NC. cited by other . | Sarah B. Hubbell, Richard Pehrson and Wayne Flournoy of Entex Technologies Inc., Webitat Advanced IFAS System Addresses Common Fixed Media Concerns, paper, pp 1-7, Water Environment Federation Technical Exhibition and Conference (WEFTEC) 2006 (Oct. 21, 2006, Dallas, Texas), Water Environment Federation, Alexandria, VA. cited by other . | Sarah B. Hubbell, Richard Pehrson and Andrew Schuler of Entex Technologies Inc., Eight Years of Successful Cold Weather Nitrification With Integrated Fixed-Film/Activated Sludge, paper, pp. 1-11, Proceedings of the Water Environment Federation Annual Conference (WEFTEC), Dallas, Texas, Oct. 22-25, 2006. cited by other . | David Krichten and Curtis McDowell, Simultaneous Nitrification and Denitrification in Biofilms of an Engineered Integrated Fixed-Film Activated Sludge (IFAS) System, article, pp. 1-4, Brentwood Industries, Reading, PA. cited by other . | United States Environmental Protection Agency, Jeremiah J. McCarthy, Technology Assessment of Fine Bubble Aerators, report, Feb. 1982, pp. 1-48, EPA/600/2-82/003, USEPA Municipal Evironmental Research Laboratory, Cincinnati, Ohio. cited by other . | Diffuser Express a Division of Environmental Dynamics Inc., Catalog #105-2006, catalog, Date Unknown, pp 1-30, Diffuser Express, Columbia, MO. cited by other. | Water Environment &amp; Technology, David R. Jackson, Leonard E. Ripley, Tod Maurina and Sara Hubbell, Up to the Challenge IFAS Helps Growing Texas City Meet Discharge Limits, Expand Capacity, magazine, Nov. 2007, pp. 51-55, Water Environment &amp; Technology. cited by other . | Water Environment &amp; Technology, Terry L. Johnson, Cindy Wallis-Lage, Andrew R. Shaw and Jim McQuarrie, IFAS Options Which One is Right for Your Project?, magazine, Nov. 2005, pp. 18-22, Water Environment &amp; Technology. cited by other . | Brentwood Industries, Integrated Fixed Film/Activated Sludge (IFAS) Technology, article, Copyright Oct. 2001, pp. 1-6, Document 4.0, Brentwood Industries, Reading, PA. cited by other . | International Search Report &amp; Written Opinion mailed on Apr. 5, 2006 in PCT/US2005/042503. cited by other . | Sarah B. Hubbell and David J. Krichten of Brentwood Industries Inc., Demonstration and Full Scale Results of a Plant Upgrade for BNR Using Integrated Fixed-Film Activated Sludge (IFAS) Technology, article, Copyright 2004, pp. 1-8, Water Environment Federation Technical Exhibition and Conference (WEFTEC) 2004, New Orleans, Louisiana, Oct. 2-6, Water Environment Federation, Alexandria, VA. cited by other . | USFilter, Integrated Headworks Systems, article, Copyright 2000, pp. 1-12, LB-HW-BR-1000, USFilter, Chalfont, PA. cited by other . | United States Environmental Protection Agency, Fine Pore Aeration Systems, Design Manual, Sep. 1989, pp. 1-305, EPA/625/1-89-023, EPA Center for Environmental Research Information, Cincinnati, Ohio. cited by other . | United States Environmental Protection Agency, Fine Pore (Fine Bubble) Aeration Systems, Summary Report, Oct. 1985, pp. 1-50, EPA/625/8-85/010, EPA Water Engineering Research Laboratory, Cincinnati, Ohio. cited by other . | Emanuel P. Psaltakis, James Liubicich, Paul Pitt, Paul Antonio and Sole Posada of Hazen and Sawyer, P.C., Demonstration of Integrated Fixed Film Activated Sludge Process for BNR at the Mamaroneck WWTP, article, Copyright 2003, pp. 1-22, Water Environment Federation Technical Exhibition and Conference (WEFTEC) 2003, Water Environment Federation, Alexandria, VA. cited by other . | Robert Zammataro, Andrew G. Lynn, P.E., Dee, Donald E. Maurer, P.E., Dee and Roderick D. Reardon, P.E., Dee, Upgrading a Contact Stabilization Treatment Plant to a Nitrifying Activated Sludge Process by Using Integrated Fixed-Film Activated Sludge (IFFAS) Media, paper, pp. 1-9, Date Unknown. cited by other . | Hydroxyl Systems Inc., Hydroxyl Systems Advanced Water and Wastewater Treatment, article, Copyright 2003, 66 pages, internet address http://hydroxyl.com/hydroxyl.html, Hydroxyl Systems Inc., Victoria, BC Canada. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		21
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		USD672009 | US7691262 | US7854843 | US8318008
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6039873 | US20040178132 | US5585266 | US6726838 | US4267052 | US3617541 | US3864246 | US5549828 | US4296050 | US4303600 | US5458779 | US5580644 | US4279753 | US4425231 | US6173526 | US4595296 | US4431549 | US20040011737 | US4940540 | US6383373 | US4422930 | US6126829 | US4668387 | US4177147 | US4818404 | US20030192827 | US3954615 | US5771716 | US5543039 | US6464211 | US5863128 | USD465257 | US3966608 | US3785620 | US4599174 | US5468392 | US4620930 | US20040256315 | US3947532 | US4434061 | US3842804 | US4169050 | US6730214 | US6444126 | EP0110715 | WO2003051485 | EP0346013 | WO1991011396
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		48
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		28479205 | 62995504
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2005-11-22 | 2004-11-22
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		ENTEX TECHNOLOGIES INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		ENTEX TECHNOLOGIES INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Chapel Hill, NC
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Chapel Hill, NC
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		PEHRSON, RICHARD, L. | FLOURNOY, WAYNE, J. | HUBBELL, SARAH, B.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		PEHRSON, RICHARD, L.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Limerick, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Limerick, PA | Chapel, Hill, NC | Mont, Clare, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		SMITH MOORE LEATHERWOOD LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BARRY, CHESTER T
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		3
	</str>
</doc>

