<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7591949
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US10984450
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Method for the improvement of transport across adaptable semi-permeable barriers
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The invention relates to a method, a kit and a device for controlling the flux of penetrants across an adaptable semi-permeable porous barrier, the method comprising the steps of: preparing a formulation by suspending or dispersing said penetrants in a polar liquid in the form of fluid droplets surrounded by a membrane-like coating of one or several layers, said coating comprising at least two kinds of forms of amphiphilic substances with a tendency to aggregate, said penetrants being able to transport agents through the pores of said barrier or to enable agent permeation through the pores of said barrier after penetrants have entered the pores, selecting a dose amount of said penetrants to be applied on a predetermined area of said barrier to control the flux of said penetrants across said barrier, and applying the selected dose amount of said formulation containing said penetrants onto said area of said porous barrier.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2004-11-08
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2004
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2004-11
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-09-22
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-09
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01D61/00 | A61K9/127
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01D61/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01D61
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		424/94.3 | 210/650 | 210/645 | 424/450
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		424/94.3
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		424
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		AU6155700A | JP2003503442A | US20030099694A1 | EE200200008A | HR20010881A2 | MXPA02000053A | AU779765B2 | WO2001001963A8 | EP1189598A1 | CN1359288A | WO2001001963A1 | WO2001001962A1 | US7459171 | US20050123897A1 | US7591949 | AU5409699A | BR0012178A | CZ20020038A3 | CA2375157A1 | NO20020032A | NO20020032D0 | HU0201454A2 | HU0201454A3 | PL352380A1 | RU2260445C2
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		25
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		6
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Ronal d R. Burnette et al., &quot;Characterization of the Permselective Properties of Excised Human Skin During Lontophoresis&quot; on Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences vol. 76, No. 10, Oct. 1987, American Pharmaceutical Association, pp. 765-773. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/244,703, entitled &quot;NSAID Formulations, Based on Highly Adaptable Aggregates, for Improved Transport Through Barriers and Topical Drug Delivery&quot;, and Preliminary Amendment filed on Oct. 2, 2008. cited by other . | Micha el Mezei, &quot;Liposomes as a Skin Drug Delivery System&quot; 1985 Elsevier Science Publishers B.V. (Biomedical Division), pp. 345-358, non-dated. cited by other . | Office Action issued on Feb. 7, 2006, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/984,450 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2005/0123897 A1). cited by other . | Declaration of Gregor CEVC under 37 C.F.R. .sctn.1.132, filed on Oct. 20, 2006 in U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,617, now U.S. Patent No. 7,473,432, assigned to IDEA AG, which was examined at the USPTO by Examiner Kishore. cited by other . | E.C. Katoulis et al., &quot;Efficacy of a New Needeless Insuling Delivery System Monitoring of Blood Glucose Fluctuations and Free Insulin Levels&quot; on International Journal of Artificial Organs vol. 12, No. 5, 1989, pp. 333-338. cited by other . | Schreier, H. &quot;Lipos omes--A Novel Drug Carrier, I. Phospholipids; Production and Characterization of Liposomes; II. Destiny of liposomes in vivo; use in therapy&quot;, Pharmazie in unserer Zeit, No. 4 (1982). cited by other . | Carafa, M. et al. &quot;Lidocaine-loaded Non-ionic Surfactant Vesicles: Characterization and In Vitro Permeation Studies,&quot; International Journal of Pharmaceutics 231:21-32. (2002). cited by other . | Patel, H.M. et al., &quot;Oral Administration of Insulin by Encapsulation Within Liposomes&quot;, FEBS Letters, 62(1):60-63 (Feb. 1976). cited by other . | Cevc et al.: &quot;Transdermal drug carriers: basic properties, optimization and transfer efficiency in the case of epicutaneously applied peptides,&quot; J. Contr. Rel., 36, pp. 3-16, 1995. cited by other . | Ogiso, Taro et al. &quot;Membrane-Controlled Transdermal Therapeutic System Containing Clonazepam and Anticonvulsant Activity after its Application.&quot; Chem. Pharm. Bull., 37(2):446-449. (1989). cited by other . | Trotta, M. et al. &quot;Deformable liposomes for dermal administration of methotrexate.&quot; International Journal of Pharmaceutics, 270:119-125. (Feb. 11, 2004). cited by other . | Merck Index: 10th Edition. pp. 779-780. (1983). cited by other . | Lobbecke, et al,&quot;Effects of Short-Chain Alcohols on the Phase Behavior and Interdigitation of Phospatidylcholine Bilayer Membranes,&quot; Biochimiea et Biophysica Aeta 1237 (1995) 59-69. cited by other . | Office Action issued on Sep. 20, 2006, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/037,480 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2003/0099694 A1). cited by other . | Claims pending on Aug. 10, 2006 in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 09/555,986, assigned to IDEA AG, now abandoned. cited by other . | Burnham et al. The effectiveness of topical diclofenac for lateral epicondylitis. Clin J Sport Med. 1998; 8(2):78-81. cited by other . | Cevc, &quot;Transfersomes, Liposomes, and Other Lipid Suspensions on the Skin: Permeation Enhancement, Vesicle Penetration, and Transdermal Drug Delivery,&quot; Crit. Rev. Ther. Drug Carrier Syst., 13 (3&amp;4), pp. 257-388, 1996. cited by other . | Patentee's response to Opposition Request filed Apr. 21, 1997 in connection with EP 0475160B1 Opposition (in German). cited by other . | Reviews on Biomembranes, Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, vol. 415 No. 1, pp. 29-79 (1975). cited by other . | Gregor CEVC. U.S.Appl. No. 11/667,325, entitled &quot;Extended Surface Aggregates in the Treatment of Skin Conditions,&quot; filed May 8, 2007. cited by other . | J. Lasch, et al., &quot;Interactions of external lipids (lipid vesicles) with the skin&quot;, Journal of Liposome Research, vol. 5, No. 3, pp. 543-569 (1995). cited by other . | Byas-Smith et al., &quot;Transdermal clonidine compared to placebo in painful diabetic neuropathy using two stage `enriched enrollment` design,&quot; Pain, vol. 60, pp. 267-274 (1995). cited by other . | M. Foldvari, &quot;In Vitro cutaneous and Percutaneous Delivery and in Vivo Efficacy of Tetracaine from Liposomal and Conventional Vehicles&quot;, Pharmaceutical Research, vol. 11 No. 11, 1994. cited by other . | Claims pending on Jan. 9, 2008 in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/037,480, assigned to IDEA AG, under examination by Examiner Fortuna at the USPTO. cited by other . | Office Action issued May 30, 2006, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,617 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2004/0071767 A1). cited by other . | Office Action mailed Jan. 9, 2008 in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/037,480, assigned to IDEA AG, under examination by Examiner Fortuna at the USPTO. cited by other . | Amendment filed on May 19, 2008 in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,617, assigned to IDEA AG, under examination by Examiner Kishore at the USPTO. cited by other . | Castillo et al., &quot;Glucocorticoids Prolong Rat Sciatic Nerve Blockade In Vivo from Bupivacaine Microspheres,&quot; Anethesiology, vol. 85, No. 5, pp. 1157-1166 (1996). cited by other . | Serva Feinbiochemica, Katalog, pp. 201-202 (1986/1987). cited by other . | C. Beyer, &quot;Mikroemulsionen&quot;, Pharmazie in unserer Seit, pp. 55-60 (1983). cited by other . | G. Ceve et al.,Transfersomes-mediated transepidermal delivery improves the regio-specificity and biological actibity of corticosteroids in vivo, Journal of Controlled Release 45 (1997) 211-226, non dated. cited by other . | Erjavec, et al. In Vivo Study of Liposomes as Drug Carriers to Oral Mucosa using EPR Oximetry. Int. J. Pharmaceut. 2006; 307:1-8. cited by other . | M. Foldvari, et al., &quot;Dermal Drug Delivery by Liposome Encapsulation: Clinical and Electron Microscopic Studies&quot;, J. Microencapsulation, 1990, vol. 7, No. 4, 479-489. cited by other . | Claims presently pending in U.S. Appl. No. 09/890,335. cited by other . | C.E. Price, &quot;A Review of the F Actors Influencing the Penetration of Pesticides Through Plant Leaves&quot; on I.C.I. Ltd., Plant Protection Division, Jealott's Hill Research Station, Bracknell, Berkshire RG12 6EY, U.K., pp. 237-252, non-dated. cited by other . | Fieser, L.F., et al. &quot;Organische Chemie&quot; Hans Ruprecht Hensel, 2.sup.nd revised edition, Verlag Chemie GmbH, Weinheim/ Bergstr (1968). cited by other . | Attachment filed by Opponent Nov. 14, 1996 in connection with EP 0475160B1 Opposition (in German). cited by other . | Valenta, C. et al., &quot;Evalutation of Novel Soya-lecithin Formulations for Dermal use containing Ketoprofen as a Model Drug,&quot; Journal of Controlled Release 63 (2000) 165-173. cited by other . | FR1SKEN, et al. Studies of vesicle extrusion. Langmuir. 2000; 16:928-933. cited by other . | J. Schramlova, et al., &quot;The Effect of an Antiphlogistic Incorporated in Liposomes on Experimentally Induced Inflammation&quot;, Folia Biologica (Praha) 43, 195-199 (1997). cited by other . | G. Cevc, &quot;Transfersomes-mediated transepidermal delivery improves the regiospecificity and biological activity of corticosteroids in vivo&quot;, Journal of Controlled Release, vol. 45, No. 37, pp. 211-226 (Apr. 1997). cited by other . | Claims filed Feb. 26, 2007, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/984,450 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2005/0123897 a1). cited by other . | Bruce J. Aungst et al., &quot;Enhancement of Naloxone Penetration Through Human Skin in Vitro Using Fatty Acids, Fatty Alcohols, Surfactants, Sulfoxides and Amides&quot; on International Journal of Pharmaceutics, 33 (1986) pp. 225-234. cited by other . | Office Action issued Apr. 11, 2007, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/037,480 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2003/0099694 A1). cited by other . | Gregor CEVC. U.S. Appl. No. 11/929,544, entitled &quot;Method For Developing testing, And Using Associates Of Macromolecules And Complex Aggregates For Improved Payload And Controllable De/Association Rates,&quot; filed on Oct. 30, 2007. cited by other . | G. Cevc et al., Journal of Controlled Release, 36:3-16 (1995). cited by other . | Frantzen et al., &quot;Assessing the accuracy of routine Photon Correlation Sepectroscopy Analysis of Heterogeneous Size Distributions,&quot; AAPS PharmSciTech, vol. 4, No. 3, Article 36, pp. 1-9 (2003). cited by other . | Guia M. Golden et al. &quot;Role of Stratum Corneum Lipid Fluidity in Transdermal Drug Flux&quot; on Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences vol. 76, No. 1, Jan. 1987, American Pharmaceutical Association, pp. 25-28. cited by other . | Beyer, C. et al., &quot;Micro Emulsions&quot; Pharmazie in unserer Zeit, No. 2 (1983). cited by other . | Product Information, &quot;Tween 80 Pure&quot; (2004). cited by other . | A. Brendzel, et al., &quot;Effects of Lipid-Soluble substances on the Thermotropic Properties of Liposome Filtration&quot;, Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, vol. 601, pp. 260-270 (1980). cited by other . | Fluka Chemica-BioChemica, Katalog 16, pp. 204, 830 (1988/1989). cited by other . | M. Berger, &quot;Oral Insulin 1922-1992: The History of Continuous Ambition and Failure&quot;. cited by other . | Office Action mailed Aug. 10, 2006 in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 09/555,986, assigned to IDEA AG, now abandoned. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/356,381, entitled &quot;Aggregates With Increased Deformability, Comprising At Least Three Amphipats, for Improved Transport Through Semi-Permeable Barriers and for the Non-Invasive Drug Application in Vivo, Especially Through the Skin&quot;, and Preliminary Amendment filed on Jan. 20, 2009. cited by other. | A. Brendzel, et al., &quot;Effects of Lipid-Soluble Substances on the Thermotropic Properties of Liposome Filtration&quot;, Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, 601 (1980) 260-270. cited by other . | Cevc, G. et al.&quot;New, Highly Efficient Formulation of Diclofenac for the Topical, Transdermal Administration in Ultradeformable Drug Carriers, Transfersomes,&quot; Biochimica et Biophysica Acta 1514 (2001) 191-205. cited by other . | Glen et al, &quot;Skin immunization made possible by cholera toxin 'letter!&quot;, Nature, GB, MacMillan Journal Ltd., London, vol. 391, No. 6670, pp. 851 (Feb. 1998). cited by other . | Hans Schreier, &quot;Liposomen--ein neuartiger Arzneistofftrager&quot;, Pharmazie in unserer Zeit, pp. 97-108 (1982). cited by other . | Pending claims in U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,618. cited by other . | Ito, Yoshimasa et al. &quot;Percutaneous Absorption of Acemetacin from a Membrane Controlled Transdermal System and Prediction of the Disposition of the Drug in Rats.&quot; Biol. Pharm. Bull., 16(6):583-588. (1993). cited by other . | V.M. Knep P et al. &quot;Controlled Drug Release From a Novel Liposomal Delivery System II. Transdermal Delivery Characteristics&quot;, Journal of Controlled Release 12 (Mar. 1990), No. 1, Amsterdam, NL, pp. 25-30. cited by other . | Office Action mailed Sep. 21, 2007 in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,617, assigned to IDEA AG, under examination by Examiner Kishore at the USPTO. cited by other . | K. Edwards, et al., Effects of Triton X-100 on Sonicated Lecithin Vesicles, Langmuir, vol. 5, pp. 473-478 (1989). cited by other . | A. Klibanov et al., Biochimica et Biophysica Acta., 1062:142-148 (1991). cited by other . | Office Action issued on May 16, 2007, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/984,450 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2005/0123897 A1). cited by other . | K. Edwards, et al. &quot;Effects of Triton X-100 on Sonicated Lecithin Vesicles&quot;, Langmuir, vol. 5, No. 3, 1989 pp. 473-478. cited by other . | Claims pending on Mar. 19, 2008 in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,618, assigned to IDEA AG, under examination by Examiner Ghali at the USPTO. cited by other . | M. Foldvari, &quot;Effect of Vehicle on Topical Liposomal Drug Delivery: Petrolatum Bases&quot;, J. Microencapsulation, 1996, vol. 13, No. 5, 589-600. cited by other . | Appeal by Opponent - Dec. 4, 1998, in connection with EP 0475160B1 Opposition (in German). cited by other . | M. L. Jackson, et al., Solubilization of Phospatidylcholine Bilayers by Octyl Glucoside, Biochemistry, vol. 21, pp. 4576-4582 (1982). cited by other . | Office Action mailed Mar. 19, 2008 in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,618, assigned to IDEA AG, under examination by Examiner Ghali at the USPTO. cited by other . | Holzbach RT, &quot;Detection of Vesicles in native and model Biles by Morphological and other structural Techniques: applications and limitations,&quot; Hepatology, Sep. 12 (3 Pt 2), pp. 106S-112S (1990). cited by other . | Ovals Siddiqui et al., &quot;NonParenteral Administration of Peptide and Protein Drugs&quot; on CRC Critical Reviews in Therapeutic Drug Carrier Systems, vol. 3, Issue 3, pp. 195-208, date unknown. cited by other . | Patel, H.M. &quot;Liposomes as a Controlled-release System&quot; Biomedical Society Transaction 609.sup.th Meeting, Leeds, pp. 513-516, non-dated. cited by other . | Office Action issued Dec. 19, 2005, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/037,480 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2003/0099694 A1). cited by other . | Claims pending on Apr. 2, 2008 in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 09/284,683, assigned to IDEA AG, under examination by Examiner Kishore at the USPTO. cited by other . | Claims filed May 31, 2005, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/984,450 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2005/0123897 A1). cited by other . | Patentee communication to the EPO filed May 22, 1998 in connection with EP 0475160B1 Opposition (in German). cited by other . | P. Vinson, et al. &quot;Vesicle-Micelle Transition of Phosphatidylcholine and Octyl Glucoside Elucidated by Cryo-Transmission Ele Tron Microscopy&quot;, Biophys. J., Biophysical Society vol. 56 Oct. 1989 669-681. cited by other . | Claims presently pending in U.S. Appl. No. 09/890,371. cited by other . | Pending claims in U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,617. cited by other . | Trotta, M. et al. &quot;Elastic liposomes for skin delivery of dipotassium glycyrrhizinate.&quot; International Journal of Pharmaceutics, 241(2):319-327. (Jul. 25, 2002). cited by other . | Claims filed Jan. 22, 2007, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/037,480 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2003/0099694 A1). cited by other . | Adrienn Gesztes and Michael Mezei, &quot;Topical Anesthesia of the Skin by Liposome-Encapsulated Tetracaine&quot; on Anesth Analg 1988; 67: pp. 1079-1081, non dated. cited by other . | Guia M. Golden et al., &quot;Role of Stratum Corneum Lipid Fluidity Transdermal Drug Flux,&quot; on Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences vol. 76, No. 1, Jan. 1987, American Pharmaceuticals Association, pp. 25-28. cited by other . | Office Action mailed Apr. 2, 2008 in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 09/284,683, assigned to IDEA AG, under examination by Examiner Kishore at the USPTO. cited by other . | G. Cevc, et al., &quot;The skin: a pathway for systemic treatment with patches and lipid-base agent carriers&quot;, Adv. Drug Delivery Reviews, vol. 18, pp. 349-378 (1996). cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/250,980, entitled &quot;NSAID Formulations, Based on Highly Adaptable Aggregates, for Improved Transport Through Barriers and Topical Drug Delivery&quot;, and Preliminary Amendment filed on Oct. 14, 2008. cited by other . | Edwards, K. et al., &quot;Effects of Trito X-100 on Sonicated Lecithin Vesicles,&quot; Langmuir, vol. 5, No. 2, 1989 pp. 473-478. cited by other . | Third Supplemental Declaration of Gregor CEVC under 37 C.F.R. .sctn.1.132, filed on Apr. 18, 2008 in U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,617, now U.S. Patent No. 7,473,432, assigned to IDEA AG, which was examined at the USPTO by Examiner Kishore. cited by other . | Wess, L. &quot;Down, down, deeper and down.&quot; Biocentury, The Bernstein Report on BioBusiness, 12(22):A11-A12. (May 17, 2004). cited by other . | Almeida et al., &quot;Nasal delivery of vaccines,&quot; Journal of Drug Targeting, vol. 3, No. 6, pp. 455-467 (1996). cited by other . | Paul et al., &quot;Transdermal immunisation with an integral membrane component gap junction protein, by means of ultradeformable drug carriers, transfersomes,&quot; Vaccine, vol. 16, No. 2-3, pp. 188-195 (Jan. 1998). cited by other . | M.L. Jacks on, et al. &quot;Solubilization of Phosphatidylcholine Bilayers by Octyl Glucoside&quot;, biochemistry 1982, 21, 4576-4582. cited by other . | Benner, &quot;The Human Body, The Wonderwork of the Human Body, Structure, Functions, Interactions, Processes and Mechanisms&quot; Weltbild GmbH Augsburg (1995). cited by other . | Claims filed Oct. 5, 2007, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/037,480 (U.S. Appl. No. US 2003/0099694 Al), under examination by Examiner Fortuna of the USPTO. cited by other . | L. Lobbecke, et al. &quot;Effects Of Short-Chain Alcohols On The Phase Behavior And Interdigitation Of Phosphatidylcholine Bilayer Membranes&quot;, Biochimiea et Biophysica Aeta 1237 (1995) 59-69. cited by other . | Mezei, &quot;Liposomes as a Skin Drug Delivery System,&quot; 1985 Elsevier Science Publishers B.V. (Biomedical Division), pp. 345-358. cited by other . | Definition of Microbicide, Wikipedia, The Free Online encyclopedia (2007). cited by other . | H. Peters, et al., &quot;Pharmacodynamics of a Liposomal Preparation for Local Anaesthesia&quot;, Arzneim.-Forsch./Drug Res. 45 (II), Nr 12 (1995). cited by other . | Schreier, H. &quot;Liposomes--A Novel Drug Carrier, I. Phospholipids; Production and Characterization of Liposomes; II. Destiny of liposomes in vivo; use in therapy,&quot; Pharmazie in underer Zeir, No. 4 (1982). cited by other . | International Search Report for International Patent Application No. PCT/EP2005/011986. (Jul. 4, 2006). cited by other . | Cevc et al., &quot;Phospholipids handbook&quot;, Marcel Dekker, Inc., New York, Basel, Hong Kong, pp. 375-376 and 404 (1993). cited by other . | Claims filed Sep. 21, 2005, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/037,480 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2003/0099694 A1). cited by other . | G. Blu me, et al. &quot;Drug-Carrier and Stability Properties of the Long-Lived Lipid Vesicles, Cryptosomes, in Vitro and in Vivo&quot;, Journal of Liposome Research, 2(3), 355-368 (1992). cited by other . | Pending claims in U.S. Appl. No. 11/545,904. cited by other . | Office Action issued Dec. 28, 2006, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,618 (U.S. Patent Publication No. 2004/0105881 A1). cited by other . | Opponent's response filed May 22, 1998 in connection with EP 0475160B1 Opposition (in German). cited by other . | V. M. Knepp, et al., &quot;Controlled drug release from a novel liposomal deliver system. II. Transdermal deliver charateristics&quot;, Journal of Controlled Release, vol. 12, No. 1, pp. 25-30 (Mar. 1990). cited by other . | R. Singh, et al. &quot;Liposomally Encapsulated Diclofenac For Sonophoresis Induced Systemic Delivery&quot;, J. Microencapsulation, 1995, vol. 12, No. 2, 149-154. cited by other . | Claims filed May 31, 2006, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/984,450 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2005/0123897 A1). cited by other . | Claims pending on May 15, 2008 in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/984,450, assigned to IDEA AG, under examination by Examiner Fortuna at the USPTO. cited by other . | Pending claims in U.S. Appl. No. 09/555,986. cited by other . | Lichtenberg, D. et al., &quot;Solubilization of Phospholipids by Detergents Structural and Kinetic Aspects&quot; Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, 737 pp. 285-304 (1983). cited by other . | Clark, J.M., Jr., &quot;Experimental Biochemistry&quot; Biochemistry Division, Department of Chemistry, University of Illinois, pp. 47-48, non dated. cited by other . | Claims filed Oct. 20, 2006, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,617 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2004/0071767 A1). cited by other . | Friedrich, et al., &quot;Physicochemical Characterization of a Reverse Micellar Solution after Loading with Different Drugs,&quot; Pharmazie 55 (2000) 10, 755-758. cited by other . | Supplemental Declaration of Gregor CEVC under 37 C.F.R. .sctn.1.132, filed on Jul. 18, 2007, in U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,617, now U.S. Patent No. 7,473,432, assigned to IDEA AG, which was examined at the USPTO by Examiner Kishore. cited by other . | Office Action mailed May 15, 2008 in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/984,450, assigned to IDEA AG, under examination by Examiner Fortuna at the USPTO. cited by other . | Decision of EP Opposition Division Jul. 30, 1998 in connection with EP 0475160B1 Opposition (in German). cited by other . | P. K. Vinson, et al., &quot;Vesicle-micelle transition of phosphatidylcholine and octyl glucoside elucidated by cryo-transmission electron microscopy&quot;, Biophysical Journal, vol. 56, pp. 669-681 (1989). cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/250,823, entitled &quot;NSAID Formulations, Based on Highly Adaptable Aggregates, for Improved Transport Through Barriers and Topical Drug Delivery&quot;, and Preliminary Amendment filed on Oct. 14, 2008. cited by other . | Blume, et al., &quot;Drug-Carrier and Stability Properties of the Long-Lived Lipid Vesicles, Cryptosomes, In Vitro and In Vivo,&quot; Journal of Liposome Research, 2(3), 355-368 (1992). cited by other . | K. Karzel and R. K. Liedtke, &quot;Mechanismen Transkutaner Resorption&quot; on Grandlagen/Basics, pp. 1487-1491, non-dated. cited by other . | Gregor CEVC. U.S. Appl. No. 11/929,480, entitled &quot;Method For Developing Testing, And Using Associates Of Macromolecules And Complex Aggregates For Improved Payload And Controllable De/Association Rates,&quot; filed Oct. 30, 2007. cited by other . | Berger, M. &quot;Oral Insulin 1922-1992: The History of Continuous Ambition and Failure&quot; Heinrich-Heine-University, Dusseldorf, Germany. cited by other . | English translation of Patentee's response to Office Action filed Feb. 9, 1999 in connection with DE 4447287 Cl Opposition. cited by other . | Pending Claims of U.S. Appl. No. 11/634,091 (Unpublished). cited by other . | G. Cevc, &quot;Drug Delivery Across the Skin&quot;, Exp. Opin. Invest. Drugs (1997) 6(12) 1887-1937. cited by other . | Declaration of Gregor CECV under 37 C.F.R. .sctn.1.132, filed on Jan. 15, 2009 in co-pending U.S. Appl. No. 12/244,703, assigned to IDEA AG, awaiting examination at the USPTO. cited by other . | D. Lichtenberg, &quot;Solubilization of Phospholipids by Detergents Structural and Kinetic Aspects&quot;, Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, pp. 285-304 (1983). cited by other . | Office Action issued on Aug. 28, 2006, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/984,450 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2005/0123897 A1). cited by other . | Roeding, J. &quot;Liposomes and Niosomes in Pharmacy and Cosmetic State of the Art Prospects, Techniques of Visualizing Vesicular Systems, Interaction of Liposomes with the Skin&quot; Training Course No. 105 from May 14 to 16, 1990, Maritim Hotel Nurnberg, Frauentorgraben 11, 8500 Nurenberg. cited by other . | Hunter, et al. Effect of extrusion pressure and lipid properties on the size and polydispersity of lipid vesicles. Biophys J. 1998; 74:2996-3002. cited by other . | A. Calpena, et al., &quot;Influence of the Formulation on the In Vitro Transdermal Penetration of Sodium Diclofenac&quot;, Arzneim.-Forsch./Drug Res. 49 (II), 1012-1017 (1999). cited by other . | Product Information, &quot;Polysorbate 80 VG&quot; (2004). cited by other . | Kilbanov, et al., Activity of amphipathic poly(ethylene glycol) 5000 to prolong the circulation time of liposomes depends on the liposome size and is unfavorable for immunoliposome binding to target, BBA, 1062, pp. 141-148, 1991. cited by other . | English translation of Opposition filed Feb. 6, 1997 in connection with DE 4447287 Cl Opposition. cited by other . | Second Supplemental Declaration of Gregor CEVC under 37 C.F.R. .sctn.1.132, filed on Mar. 13, 2008 in U.S. Patent Application 10/357,617, now U.S. Patent No. 7,473,432, assigned to IDEA AG, which was examined at the USPTO by Examiner Kishore. cited by other . | Cevc, G. &quot;Material Transport Across Permeability Barriers by Means of Lipid Vesicles&quot;, Handbook of Biological Physics, vol. 1, pp. 465-490 (1995). cited by other . | English translation of Opponent's response to Office Action filed Mar. 17, 1998 in connection with DE 4447287 Cl Opposition. cited by other . | Saunders et al. A novel skin penetration enhancer: evaluation by membrane diffusion and confocal microscopy. J Pharm Pharmaceut Sci. 1999; 2(3):99-107. cited by other . | S. Yuan et al., Progress in Physiological Science, 28(2):163-165 (1997). cited by other . | Grahame R, &quot;Transdermal non-steroidal anti-inflammatory agents,&quot; BJCP, vol. 49, No. 1, pp. 33-35 (Jan.-Feb. 1995). cited by other . | J. Roeding, &quot;Visualisierungstechniken von vesikularen Systemen, Wechselwirkungen von Liposomen mit der Haut&quot;, Kurs 502 of APV, (May 14-16, 1990). cited by other . | Cevc. G. et al., &quot;The skin: a pathway for systemic treatment with patches and lipid-based agent carriers&quot; Advanced Drug Delivery Reviews 18 pp. 349-378 (1996). cited by other . | M.E. Planas, et al., &quot;Noninvasive Percutaneous Induction of Topical Analgesia by a New Type of Drug Carrier, and Prolongation of Local Pain Insensitivity by Anesthetic Liposomes&quot;, Anesth Analg 1992; 75 615-621. cited by other . | Mayer, L.D. et al., &quot;Vesicles of variables sizes produced by a rapid extrusion procedure&quot;, Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, 858 pp. 161-165 (1986). cited by other . | Phillip G. Green, et al., &quot;In Vitro and in Vivo Enhancement of Skin Permeation With Oleic and Lauric Acids&quot; on International Journal of Pharmaceutics, 48 (1988), pp. 103-111, non-dated. cited by other . | T. Henmi, et al., &quot;Application of an Oily Gel Formed by Hydrogenated Soybean Phgospholipids as a Percutaneous Absorption-Type Ointment Base&quot;, Chem. Pharm. Bull. 42(3) 651-655 (1994). cited by other . | Prof. Dr. K-U Benner, &quot;Der Korper des Menschen&quot;, p. 49 (1995). cited by other . | Cevc, G. et al., &quot;U1 traflexible vesicles, Transfersomes, have an extremely low pore penetration resistance and transport therapeutic amounts of insuling across the intact mammalian skin&quot;, Biochimica et Biophysica Acta. 1368 pp. 201-215 (1998). cited by other . | Lehmann, J. et al. &quot;Analgesic and anti-inflammatory efficacy of IDEA-070 in UVB-induced sunburn.&quot; Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology, 18(S2):167-168. (Oct. 2004). cited by other . | Office Action issued on Oct. 16, 2003, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/037,480 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2003/0099694 A1). cited by other . | Paul et al., &quot;Non Invasive administration of protein antigens: transdermal immunization with bovine serum albumin in transfersomes,&quot; Vaccine Research, vol. 4, No. 3, pp. 145-164 (1995). cited by other . | Response by Patentee filed Apr. 19, 1999 in connection with EP 0475160B1 Opposition (in German). cited by other . | Claims pending on Sep. 21, 2007 in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,617, assigned to IDEA AG, under examination by Examiner Kishore at the USPTO. cited by other . | Louis F. Fieser, Mary Fieser, &quot;Organische Chemie&quot;, p. 1250 (1968). cited by other . | Lasch, J. et al., &quot;Internactions of external lipids (lipids vesicles) with the skin&quot; Journal of Liposome Research 5(3) pp. 543-569 (1995). cited by other . | Office Action issued Jan. 19, 2007, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,617 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2004/0071767 A1). cited by other . | Cevc et al. Ultradeformable lipid vesicles can penetrate the skin and other semi- permeable barriers unfragmented. Evidence from double label CLSM experiments and direct size measurements. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta. 2002; 1564:21-30. cited by other . | Helenius, et al.: &quot;Solubilization of Membranes by Detergents,&quot; Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, 415 (1975) 29-79. cited by other . | Swenson, E. Scott and William J. Curatolo. &quot;Intestinal permeability enhancement for proteins, peptides and other polar drugs: mechanisms and potential toxicity.&quot; Advanced Drug Delivery Reviews, 8:39-92. (1992). cited by other . | Siddiqui, O. et al., &quot;Nonparenteral Administration of Peptide and Protein Drugs,&quot; CRC Critical Reviews in Therapeutic Drug Carrier Systems, vol. 3, Issue 3 p. 195-208. cited by other . | A. Helenius, et al, &quot;Solubilization of Membranes by Detergents&quot;, Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, 415 (1975) 29-79, non-dated. cited by other . | Pending claims in U.S. Appl. No. 10/037,480. cited by other . | G. Cevc et al., Critical Review in Therapeutic Drug Carrier Systems, 13(3&amp;4):257-388 (1996). cited by other . | Claims filed Mar. 20, 2006, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/037,480 (U.S. Patent publication No. US 2003/0099694 A1). cited by other . | Lasch, J. et al., &quot;Interactions of external lipids (lipids vesicles) with the skin&quot; Journal of Liposome Research 5(3) pp. 543-569 (1995). cited by other . | Office Action issued Mar. 30, 2005, in connection with the U.S. Appl. No. 10/037,480 (U.S. Patent Publication No. U.S. 2003/0099694 A1). cited by other . | Pending claims in U.S. Appl. No. 10/984,450. cited by other . | Fluka Chemika-BioChemika Catalogue 16 (1988/89). cited by other . | Claims filed Oct. 20, 2004, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/037,480 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2003/0099694 A1). cited by other . | Serva, Feinbiochemica Fur Forschung for Serva Feinbiochemica GmbH &amp; Co. (1986/1987). cited by other . | I. Stoye, et al., &quot;Transformation of a Liposomal Dispersion Containing Ibuprofen Lysinate and Phospholipids into Mixed Micelles--Physico-chemical Characterization and Influence on Drug Permeation through Excised Human Stratum Corneum,&quot; European Journal of Pharmaceutics and Biopharmaceutics 46 (1998) 191-200. cited by other . | English translation of counterstatement of Patentee filed Jul. 11, 1997 in connection with DE 4447287 Cl Opposition. cited by other . | Ranade V., &quot;Drug Delivery Systems.6. Transdermal Drug Delivery,&quot; J. Clin Pharmacol, vol. 31, pp. 401-418 (1991). cited by other . | Search Report for PCT/EP91/01596. cited by other . | Claims filed May 12, 2004, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,618 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2004/0105881 A1). cited by other . | Claims filed Feb. 4, 2003, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/357,617 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2004/0071767 A1). cited by other . | Anosov, et al. Electrical capacitance of hydrogenated egg lecithin bilayer lipid membranes in the lipid crystal to gel phase transition. Biofizika. 2003; 48(2): 240-245. (English Abstract). cited by other . | Claims filed Jan. 4, 2002, in connection with U.S. Appl. No. 10/037,480 (U.S. Patent Publication No. US 2003/0099694 A1). cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		184
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US7927622 | US7867480
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6562370 | US6797276 | US4666747 | US5985860 | US20040071767 | US4937182 | US6294192 | US6868686 | US5209720 | US20030099694 | US4849224 | US5648095 | US4731210 | US4937254 | US5741515 | US4746509 | US5510118 | US7459171 | US5607692 | US7063859 | US20070031483 | US5614178 | US5498418 | US6214386 | US20070042030 | US5681849 | US6582724 | US5585109 | US6517864 | US7175850 | US5891472 | US20020003179 | US4911928 | US20020048596 | US6835392 | US5244678 | US6645529 | US4954345 | US4897269 | US6277892 | US6165500 | US4921706 | US6645520 | US5763422 | US6045827 | US7387788 | US5837289 | US6451339 | US6069172 | US5874422 | US20070184114 | US6654337 | US20020012680 | US20010012849 | US5202125 | US5322685 | US5552160 | US5958379 | US5043165 | US6303141 | US4619794 | US5783208 | US6586000 | US7473432 | US5654337 | US4783450 | US5238613 | US5145684 | US4369182 | US6387383 | US6200598 | US6448296 | US5104661 | US20070243203 | US5154930 | US20020106345 | US20020037877 | US6193996 | US6028066 | US6726598 | US5716638 | US6248353 | US4944948 | US5498420 | US5858330 | US6577880 | US6083996 | US5874095 | US20020147238 | USR33273 | US5460820 | US20050123897 | US20020119188 | US4983395 | US4937078 | WO1998017255 | EP0704206 | EP0707847 | WO2000044350 | WO1998007414 | EP0393707 | WO1998006750 | WO1996029999 | EP0224837 | WO2002032398 | EP1140021 | DE3713494 | WO2002058670 | EP0674913 | CA1143656 | WO2000012060 | WO1995035095 | WO2006050926 | WO1987001938 | EP0102324 | EP0220797 | WO2001000962 | WO2001000963 | WO2000050007 | WO1992022292 | DE4447287 | WO2000044349 | EP0298280 | WO1998033483 | WO1991004013 | DEP4026834 | DEP4026833 | CA1289420 | HU0104424 | DE4107152 | DE4107153 | EP0995435 | WO2001000247 | WO2000013684 | EP0280492 | WO1990011065 | WO1996019205 | EP0475160 | EP0211647 | WO2004032900 | WO1993019736 | WO1990009782 | WO1993019737 | WO2002007767 | EP0088046 | WO1994026257 | WO2002011683 | AU724218 | WO1992005771 | WO1999022703 | DE3016976 | WO1990009385 | EP0582239 | WO2000024377 | WO1992004009 | HU0105400 | EP1031346 | JP1995324029 | WO1988007362 | EP1031347 | WO2005063213 | JP1986271204 | CA2067754 | WO1992003122 | EP0382716 | WO1998030215 | WO1998024407 | HU9903363 | AU1740283 | WO2000038653 | JP2006131597 | CA2160775 | WO2000000597 | CA2052164 | WO1991001146 | WO2000025822 | EP0355095 | EP0152379
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		178
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | EP | EP | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		98445004 | 9904659 | 0006367 | 3748002
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2004-11-08 | 1999-07-05 | 2000-07-05 | 2002-01-04
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		IDEA AG
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		IDEA AG
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Munich, DE
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Munich, DE
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		CEVC, GREGOR | RICHARDSEN, HOLGER | WEILAND-WAIBEL, ANDREA
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		CEVC, GREGOR
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Gauting, DE
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Gauting, DE | Munchen, DE | Hohenbrunn, DE
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		WILSON SONSINI GOODRICH &amp; ROSATI PC
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		FORTUNA, ANA
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

