<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7556735
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11/865911
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B1
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Plant biomass management system and method
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A method is provided that can amend treatment wetland soils and sediments in order to reduce pollutant export following the use of the wetland for contaminant removal. The method includes the steps of draining at least a portion of a water body and permitting the growth of vegetation on the sediments. Once grown, the resulting biomass is tilled into the soil, and the water body is permitted to re-hydrate. In some instances a portion of the vegetation can be harvested prior to tilling remaining crop residues into the soil. In another embodiment, the draining step occurs naturally.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2007-10-02
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2007
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2007-10
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-07-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-07
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/32 | B09C1/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/32
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/602 | 210/747.5 | 405/128.15
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/602
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US7556735
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Lake Apopka Water Hyacinth Demonstration Project, Second Semi-Annual Report prepared for St. Johns River Water Management District, prepared by Amasek, Inc., Apr. 4, 1991. cited by other | DeBusk et al., &quot;Effectiveness of Mechanical Aeration in Floating Aquatic Macrophyte-Based Wastewater Treatment Systems,&quot; Journal of Environmental Quality, vol. 18, No. 3, pp. 349-354, Jul.-Sep. 1989. cited by other | Clark, Mark, &quot;Biophysical Characterization of Floating Wetlands (Flotant) and Vegetative Succession of a Warm-Temperature Aquatic Ecosystem,&quot; Dissertation, University of Florida, 2000. cited by other | Wen, Li and Recknagel, Friedrich, &quot;In Situ Removal of Dissolved Phosphorus in Irrigation Drainage Water by Planted Floats: Preliminary Results from Growth Chamber Experiment,&quot; Agriculture, Ecosystems and Environment, vol. 90, pp. 9-15, Jun. 2002. cited by other | Kim, Youngchul and Kim, Wan-Joong, &quot;Roles of Water Hyacinths and Their Roots for Reducing Algal Concentration in the Effluent from Waste Stabilization Ponds,&quot; Water Research, vol. 34, No. 13, pp. 3285-3294, Sep. 1, 2002. cited by other.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		5
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US4188154 | US5282694 | US5472472 | US5520253 | US5733453 | US5766474 | USR35989 | US5863433 | US5897946 | US5993649 | US6322699 | US6413426 | US6692641 | US6893567 | US7074330
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		15
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		86591107 | 82779206
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2007-10-02 | 2006-10-02
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		DEBUSK, THOMAS, A.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		DEBUSK, THOMAS, A.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Cocoa, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Cocoa, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		HARTT, PH.D., JACQUELINE E. LOWNDES, DROSDICK, DOSTER, KANTOR &amp; REED, P.A.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		PRINCE, FRED
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

