<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7544286
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11/383708
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Method and apparatus for enhancing aquatic environments
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Submerged media useful with or without aeration and/or mixing to enhance an aquatic environment by promoting and retaining biogrowth. The media takes the form of a cluster of individual flexible elements having free ends. The media are submerged in a liquid such as a water or wastewater treatment basin or an aquaculture environment. The media are characterized by the ability to promote and retain microbial growth. The media clusters have substantial flow through thicknesses to provide a three dimensional effect along with baffling for increased contact with the liquid being treated. The media may be thin strips constructed to avoid sticking together to allow maximum exposed surface area. The media clusters can create oxic, anoxic and anaerobic environments for maximum treatment during flow through the media cluster. The flexibility of the media elements and their free ends automatically dislodges excessive biomass buildup to avoid clogging of the media.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2006-05-16
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2006
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2006-05
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-06-09
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-06
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/30 | A01K63/04 | C02F3/08
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/30
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/150 | 119/227 | 119/228 | 210/167.22 | 210/167.26 | 210/170.02
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/150
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		CA2587296A1 | US20070267344A1 | US20090211969A1 | WO200807136970A3 | WO2007136970A2 | US7544286
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		6
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		&quot;Bio-Pac SF#30 Media For Tricling Filters, Submerged Beds and Anaerobic Reactors,&quot; (3-page brochure idetnifying trickling filter media); NSW, LLC (NSW Environmental Systems; nswplastics.com), Roanoke, Virginia, (publication date unknown). cited by other | &quot;Glitsch Ballast Tray&quot; (2-page brochure identifying Random Pac-Tricling Filter); Glitsch, Inc. , (location and publication date unknown). cited by other | &quot;ABF Bio-Media Superior Fixed Growth Media for Biological Treatment&quot; (1 page brochure identifying a trickling filter), Neptune Microfloc, Inc., (location and publication date unknown). cited by other | &quot;Biodeck Applications&quot; (2-page brochure identifying a trickling filter) (publisher, location and publication date unknown). cited by other | &quot;AquaMats Engineered Aquatic Products Presents High-Performance AquaMats Substrate Technology: Application in Wastewater Treatment&quot; (22-page brochure identifying similar concept to EDI except single surface, i.e., not flow through), Meridian Aquatic Technology, LLC (1999-20001), Calverton, Maryland. cited by other | Ringlace Attached Growth Bio-Media) (3-page brochure identifying submerged media), Ringlace Products, Inc., (Apr. 21, 1998), Portland, Oregon. cited by other | &quot;The Kaldness Mo[ving bed]&quot; (2-page brochure identifying moving bed media) AnoxKaldnes; www.anoxkaldnes.com (date of publication unknown), Providence, Rhode Island. cited by other | &quot;The Colony BioWeb Project,&quot; (5-page brochure identifying submerged media), Entex Technologies, Inc. (www.entexinc.com), (publication date unknown), Chapel Hill, North Carolina. cited by other | &quot;Accu-Web Active Fabric Media&quot; (2-page brochure identifying submerged media), Brentwood Industries (printed Apr. 2001), Reading, Pennsylvania. cited by other | &quot;How it Works,&quot; (2-page brochure identifying moving bed submerged media) (publisher, publication date and location unknown). cited by other | &quot;Figure2Trickling Filter Media,&quot; &quot;Figure 1 Pilot Plant,&quot; &quot;Figure 7 Conclusions of Trickling Filter Media Study,&quot; (3-page brochure identifying typical trickling filter media) (publisher, publication date and location unknown). cited by other.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		11
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US3617541 | US4169050 | US4451362 | US5085766 | US5468392 | US6060153 | US6171686 | US6230654 | US6244218 | US20010047960 | DE3522965 | JP1994086994 | JP1996224588 | JP2000325973 | JP2001062479 | JP2002086175 | JP2003225690
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		17
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		38370806
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2006-05-16
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		ENVIRONMENTAL DYNAMICS, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		ENVIRONMENTAL DYNAMICS, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Columbia, MO
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Columbia, MO
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		THARP, CHARLES, E. | RIDDELL, PETER
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		THARP, CHARLES, E.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Columbia, MO
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Columbia, MO | Mission, Bay, Auckland, NZ
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		HUSCH BLACKWELL SANDERS LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		PRINCE, FRED
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

