<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7527733
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US10/957553
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Chelating agents for heavy metal removal
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The present invention provides for Troika acids attached to a macroporous resin and Methods of preparing the same, including direct attachment of a Troika acid, and attachment of a Troika acid precursor followed by generation of the Troika acid in situ. Methods of functionalizing a resin to facilitate attachment are also described. Multiple Troika acids, comprising a pair of Troika acids joined together are described. Synthetic routes to both microporous and macroporous resins modified by introduction of a suitable Troika-type acid have been designed and validated. In a preferred embodiment, a macroporous Troika resin removes Cu.sup.2+ and Ni.sup.2+ from aqueous solution with high affinity, and is selective against Mg.sup.2+ or Ca.sup.2+. The materials of the present invention have advantages for metal removal from power plant waste water.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2004-09-30
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2004
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2004-09
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-05-05
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-05
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F1/42
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F1/42
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/263 | 210/912 | 502/402 | 558/172 | 560/168 | 562/17
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/263
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		CA2581913A1 | BRPI0516862A | KR1020070085280A | JP2008514419A | ZA200702660A | WO2006039235A3 | AU2005292337A1 | US7527733 | EP1794092A2 | CN101065330A | US20060065604A1 | WO2006039235A2 | MX2007003681A
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		13
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Carrick, &quot;Novel Troika Acid Derivatives: Photochemistry and Metal Chelation&quot;, dissertation from University of Southern California, 2000, pp. 1-158. cited by other | Carrick, et al., &quot;Indirect Photo-Induced Phosphorylation Via a C-Ester Caged Troika Acid&quot;, Phosphorus, Sulfur, and Silicon, vol. 147, 1999, p. 65. cited by other | Carrick, et al., &quot;Indirect Photo-Induced Phosphorylation Via a Photoabile Troika Acid C-Ester: o-Nitrobenzyl (E)-(Hydroxyimino)(dihydroxyphosphinyl)acetate&quot;, Tetrahedron, vol. 56, 2000, pp. 2391-2396. cited by other | Gibson, et al. Metal Complexes of .alpha. -Hydroxyimino Phosphonic Acid Derivatives. Separation of the E and Z Isomers by Metal Chelation and the Preparation and Characterization of Copper Bis[(E)-(.alpha. -(hydroxyimino)benzel)phosphonate]-Water., Inorg. Chem., 28, 1928-1932, (1989). cited by other | Kashemirov, et al., &quot;&quot;Troika Acids&quot;: Synthesis, Structure, and Fragmentation Pathways of Novel .alpha.-(Hydroxyimino)phosphonoacetic Acids&quot;, J. Am. Chem. Soc., vol. 117, 1995, pp. 7285-7286. cited by other | Kashemirov, et al., &quot;&quot;Troika Acids&quot;: Synthesis, Structure, and Fragmentation Pathways of Novel .alpha.-(Hydroxyimino)phosphonoacetic Acids&quot;, J. Am. Chem. Soc., vol. 117, supp. 1995, pp. 1-33. cited by other | Kashemirov, et al., &quot;Troika Acid Derivatives: Multifunctional Ligands for Metal Complexation in Solution and on Solid Supports, a Novel, Linear Trinickel (&quot;Troitsa&quot;) Complex&quot;, Phosphorous, Sulfur and Silicon, vol. 177, 2002, p. 2273. cited by other | Kashemirov, et al., &quot;(E)-(Hydroxyimino)(hydroxymethoxyphosphinyl)acetic Acid: Synthesis and pH-Dependent Fragmentation&quot;, Tetrahedron Letters, vol. 36 No. 52, 1995, pp. 9437-9440. cited by other | Kashemirov, et al., &quot;Effects of Divalent Metal Ions on pH-Dependent Hydrolysis of p-Nitrophenyl (E)-(Hydroxyimino)Phosphonoacetate&quot;, Phosphorus, Sulfur, and Silicon, vol. 147, 1999, p. 153. cited by other | Khokhlov, P. S.; Kashemirov, B. A.; Strepikheev, Y. A., &quot;Nitrosation of Phosphono- and Phosphinoacetic Acid Esters&quot;, J. Gen. Chem. USSR (Engl.), 52, 2468-2469. cited by other | Luftor, et al., &quot;Extraction of Heavy Metals from Waste Water By Polymeric Chelating Resins&quot;, University of Colorado, Feb. 4, 2004. cited by other | McKenna, et al., &quot;(Hydroxyimino)phosphonoacetic Acids: Synthesis, Stereochemistry and Reactivity&quot;, Phosphorus, Sulfur, and Silicon, vol. 111, 1996, p. 158. cited by other | McKenna, et al., &quot;(E/Z) Stereoisomer Assignment by .sup.13C NMR in Trifunctional Phosphonate .alpha.-Oximes and .alpha.-Arylhydrazones&quot;, J. Chem. Soc., Chem. Commun., 1994, pp. 1211-1212. cited by other | McKenna, et al., &quot;Facile Dealkylation of Diakylphosphonates by Bromotrimethylsilane&quot;, Tetrahedron Letters, 155-158, (1977). cited by other | McKenna, et al., &quot;Functional Selectivity in Phosphonate Ester Dealkylation with Bromotrimethylsilane&quot;, J. Chem. Soc., Chem. Comm., 739, (1979)). cited by other | Wakley, J, &quot;Removal of Heavy Metals From Waste Water&quot;, Brigham Young University, Feb. 4, 2004. cited by other | International Search Report mailed Jul. 13, 2006 corresponding to PCT/US05/34420. cited by other | Written Opinion of the International Searching Authority mailed Jul. 13, 2006 corresponding to PCT/US05/34420. cited by other | Bodsworth, C., &quot;The Extraction and Refining of Metals,&quot; Department of Materials Technology, Brunel University, 1994, pp. 259-260. cited by other | Breuer, E., &quot;Acylphophonates and their derivatives,&quot; Chemistry of Organophosphorous Compounds, John Wiley &amp; Sons, 1996, p. 685. cited by other | Elkot, A. M., &quot;Solvent Extraction of Neodymium, Europium and Thulium by Di-(2-ethylhexyl)Phosphoric Acid,&quot; J. Radioanalytical and Nuclear Chemistry, 1993, vol. 170, pp. 207-214. cited by other | Farmer, M. F. et al., &quot;Complexation Properties of Phosphonocarboxylic Acids in Aqueous Solutions,&quot; Journal of Solution Chemistry, 1981, vol. 10, pp. 523-532. cited by other | Felix, A., et al., &quot;Rapid Fluorometric Detection for Completeness in Solid Phase Coupling Reactions,&quot; Analytical Biochemistry, 1973, vol. 52, pp. 377-381. cited by other | Johnson, C.R. et al., &quot;Solid Phase Synthesis of Alkenes Using the Horner-Wadsworth-Emmons Reaction and Monitoring by Gel Phase 31P NMR,&quot; Tetrahedron Letters, 1995, vol. 36, pp. 9253-9256. cited by other | Kakoi, T. et al., &quot;Separation of Cobalt and Nickel by Liquid Surfactant Membranes Containing a Synthesized Cationic Surfactant,&quot; Separation Science and Technology, 1998, vol. 33, pp. 1163-1180. cited by other | Mather, J. N. et al., &quot;Recovery of Neptunium from Highly Radioactive Waste Solutions of Purex Origin Using Tributyl Phosphate,&quot; Separation and Science Technology, 1996, vol. 31, pp. 2045-2063. cited by other | McKenna, C. E. et al., &quot;Innovative Chelating Agents for Heavy Metal Removal,&quot; Product ID # MP-2/W06530, May 2003. cited by other | Motekaitis, R. J. et al., &quot;Best--A new program for rigorous calculation of equilibrium parameters of complex multicomponent systems,&quot; Can. J. Chem, 1982, vol. 60, pp. 2403-2409. cited by other | Lockwood Greene Engineers, &quot;Power Plant Wastewater Treatment Technology Review Report,&quot; WSSI 1996, pp. A1-1 through A1-3. cited by other | Sliva, T. Y. et al., &quot;Copper(II) and nickel(II) complexes with some oxime analogs of amino acids. Potentiometric, spectroscopic and X-ray studies of complexes with 2-cyano-2-(hydroxyimino)acetic acid and its ethane-1,2-diamine derivative,&quot; J. Chem. Soc., 1998, pp. 1863-1867. cited by other | Sliva, T. Y. et al., &quot;Co-ordination ability of amino acid Oximes. Potentiometric, spectroscopic and structural studies of complexes of 2-cyano-2-(hydroxyimino)acetamide,&quot; J. Chem. Soc., 1997, pp. 273-276. cited by other | Song, B. et al., &quot;Metal-Ion-Coordinating Properties of a Viral Inhibitor, a Pyrophosphate Analogue, and a Herbicide Metabolite, a Glycinate Analogue: The Solution Properties of the Potentially Five-Membered Chelates Derived from Phosphonoformic Acid and (Aminomethyl)phosphonic Acid,&quot; Helvetica Chimica ACTA, 1994, vol. 77, pp. 1738-1756. cited by other | Stunzi, H. et al., &quot;Stability Constants of Metal Complexes of Phosphonoacetic Acid,&quot; Journal of Inorganic Biochemistry, 1979, vol. 10, 309-316. cited by other.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		33
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US7674384 | US7947130 | US7678281 | US8303839
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5182251 | US5948931 | US5980716 | US6432313 | US7083731 | WO2001023067
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		6
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		95755304
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2004-09-30
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		THE UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		THE UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Los Angeles, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Los Angeles, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		MCKENNA, CHARLES, E. | KASHEMIROV, BORIS, A | FAVIER, ISABELLE | WOLFE, THOMAS, D.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		MCKENNA, CHARLES, E.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Pacific, Palisades, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Pacific, Palisades, CA | Los, Angeles, CA | St., Thibault, des, Vignes, FR | Rough, &amp;, Ready, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		KILPATRICK STOCKTON LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		HRUSKOCI, PETER A
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		1
	</str>
</doc>

