<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7528097
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11/198006
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Non-emulsion based oil simulant
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A composition and method for a non-emulsion crude oil simulant containing biodegradable oil, and a terpene is disclosed and described. Biodegradable oils such as canola oil, cottonseed oil, and soybean oil can be particularly beneficial for use in connection with these oil simulants. Terpenes such as d-limonene can be included to provide oil simulant compositions which exhibit good oil simulant properties. Additives such as photochromic dyes, food dyes, food-grade antioxidants, microorganisms, and nutrients can also be used. These non-emulsion based oil simulants can be readily tailored and adjusted to approximate relevant properties of a specific target fluid for use in assessing oil spill response, containment, clean-up of equipment, percolation, and/or spill behavior.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2005-08-04
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2005
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2005-08
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-05-05
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-05
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C10M169/04
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C10M169/04
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C10
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C10M
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C10M169
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		508/491 | 210/922 | 210/923 | 210/924 | 210/925
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		508/491
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		508
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US20060027361A1 | US7528097
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Acaroglu, M. et al., &quot;An Investigation of the Use of Rapeseed Oil in Agricultural Tractors as Engine Oil,&quot; Energy Sources, 2001, 23 (9), pp. 823-830. cited by other | Allen, A. et al, &quot;Canola Oil as a Substitute for Crude Oil in Cold Water Spill Tests,&quot; Physical Behaviour, Jun. 14-16, 198, Section I, pp. 1-8. cited by other | United States Environmental Protection Agency, &quot;Contingency Planning,&quot; See http://ww.epa.gov/oilspill/conting.htm (printed Feb. 1, 2006), p. 1. cited by other | EPA. 40 CFR Part 796 -Chemical Fate Testing Guidelines: Subpart D -Transformation Processes: 796.31 00 Aerobic Aquatic Biodegradation, http://www.access.gpo.gov/nara/cfr/waisidx01/40cfr79601. html, accessed 2002, United States Environmental Protection Agency, pp. 91-96. cited by other | PPG's Photosol.RTM. Photochromic Dyes, Frequently Asked Questions, See http://www.ppg.com/chm.about.optical/psol/fotofaqs.htm (accessed Jul. 2003), PPG Industries, Inc., pp. 1-2. cited by other | Goodman, R.H. et al., &quot;Tracking Buoys for Oil Spills,&quot; In 1995 International Oil Spill Conference, Achieving and Maintaining Preparedness, Long Beach, CA, Feb. 7-Mar. 2, 1995/ See also American Petroleum Institute: Washington, D.C., 1995; pp. 1040. cited by other | Grierson, I.T., &quot;Use of Airborne Thermal Imagery to Detect and Monitor Inshore Oil Spill Residues During Darkness Hours,&quot; Environ. Manage., 1998, 22 (6), pp. 905-912. cited by other | Merisol Antioxidants BHT Material Safety Data Sheet, Trade Name: BHT, Version date: Sep. 9, 2005, Version 1.0, pp. 1-8. cited by other | Newtec Our Product, Microbe-PLUS, See http://www.geocities.com/myorganizations/newtec/product.html (accessed Jul. 2003), Newtec: Bio-remediation, Sewer and Water Treatment, pp. 1-2. cited by other | Park, M. et al., &quot;The Use of GPS Buoys to Calibrate Altimetric Satellites,&quot; In Proceedings of the 7th International Technical Meeting of The Satellite Division of the Institute of Navigation, Part 1, Salt Lake City, UT, Sep. 20-23, 1994. See also Inst. of Navigation, Alexandria, VA, 1994, vol. 1, pp. 221-230. cited by other | Plante, A.F.; Voroney, R.P., &quot;Biodegradation and Bioremediation: Decomposition of Land Applied Oily Food Waste and Associated Changes in Soil Aggregate Stability,&quot; J. Environ. Qual. 1998, 27 (2), pp. 395-402. cited by other | Reed, M. et al, &quot;Evaluation of Surface Drifters for Satellite Tracking of Oil on the Sea,&quot; Oceans, Sep. 1987, vol. 19, pp. 1611-1616. cited by other | Salvesen, J.; Stong, B.A.; Byers, D.G.; Smith, A.G.; Arnhart, R.; Gaudet, S.; Tomblin, T.G.; Teichman, K.M., &quot;Establishing Optimal Response Strategies Using Real-Time Current Observations: A Local, Cooperative Approach,&quot; 1995 International Oil Spill Conference: Achieving and Maintaining Preparedness, Long Beach, CA, Feb. 27-Mar. 2, 1995, pp. 755-759. See also American Petroleum Institute, 1995. cited by other | Sraj, R. et al., &quot;Rapidly Biodegradable Hydraulic Fluids on the Basis of Rapeseed Oil,&quot; Lubrication Engineering 2000, pp. 34-39. cited by other | Sigma-Aldrich MSDS, Brand: Supelco Inc., Product Name: Canola Oil, 1000 MG, NEAT, Version 1.0, Date Updated: Dec. 19, 2003, pp. 1-4. cited by other | Fisher Scientific MSDS d-Limonene, Purity 98% (gc), ACC#54537, MSDS Creation Date: Jan. 9, 1998, Revision #6 date: Nov. 17, 2004, MSDS Creation Date: Jan. 9, 2004, pp. 1-6. cited by other.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		16
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US4100082 | US5196129 | US5801131 | US20020006519
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		19800605 | 59916904
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2005-08-04 | 2004-08-04
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		UNIVERSITY OF UTAH RESEARCH FOUNDATION
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		UNIVERSITY OF UTAH RESEARCH FOUNDATION
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Salt Lake City, UT
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Salt Lake City, UT
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		HANSON, FRANCIS, V. | FLETCHER, JOHN, V. | REDDING, ALYSSA, M. | OLSON, CHRISTOPHER | JATURAPITPORNSAKUL, JUMPOL
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		HANSON, FRANCIS, V.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		5
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Salt, Lake, City, UT
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Salt, Lake, City, UT | Murray, UT | Concord, CA | Tooele, UT | Salt, Lake, City, UT
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		THORPE NORTH &amp; WESTERN LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		CALDAROLA, GLENN A
	</str>
	<str name="Assistant Examiner">
		OLADAPO, TAIWO
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

