<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7507341
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11198703
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Method of and apparatus for converting biological materials into energy resources
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A method of converting biological material into energy resources includes transmitting biological material to a pulsed electric field (PEF) station, and applying a PEF to the biological material within a treatment zone in the PEF station to generate treated biological material. The method also includes transmitting the treated biological material to a biogenerator, and processing the treated biological material in the biogenerator to produce an energy resource. A converter may carry out this process, and may include the PEF station and the biogenerator.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2005-08-05
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2005
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2005-08
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-03-24
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-03
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/28
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/28
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		48/197A | 210/609 | 48/127.3 | 210/748 | 210/603 | 205/751 | 205/637 | 205/688
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		48/197A
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		48
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US7507341 | US20090176300A1 | US20060118485A1 | US7645382
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Castro et al., Microbial Inactivation of Foods by Pulsed Electric Fields, J. Food Proc. Pres. 17:47-73 (1993) (USA). cited by other . | Chauhan, S., Feasability of Biosludge Dewatering Using Pulsed Electric Fields, Battelle Final Report, 1-24 (1998). cited by other . | Liu et al., Electricity Generation Using an Air-Cathode Single Chamber Microbial Fuel Cell in the Presence and Absence of a Proton Exchange Membrane, Environmental Sci &amp; Tech, 4040-4046 (Jun. 12, 2004) (USA). cited by other . | Zhang, Q. H., Monsalve-Gonzalez, A., Barbosa-Canovas, G. V. and Swanson, B. G., Inactivation of E. coli and S. cerevisiae by pulsed electric fields under controlled temperature conditions, Transactions of the ASAE. 37(2):581-587 (1994) (USA). cited by other . | Graham Mfg. Co., Heliflow Heat Exchanger. cited by other . | Logan, Extracting Hydrogen and Electricity from Renewable Resources, Environmental Sci. &amp; Tech, 160A-167A (May 1, 2004) (USA). cited by other . | Zhang, Q. H., Barbosa-Canovas, G. V. and Swanson, B. G., Engineering aspects of pulsed electric field pasteurization, J. Food Eng. 25(2):261-281 (1995) (Great Britain). cited by other . | U.S. Departments of Energy and Agriculture, Biomass as Feedstock for a Bioenergy and Bioproducts Industry: The Technical Feasibility of a Billion-Ton Annual Supply (Apr. 2005) (USA) (misnumbering in original). cited by other . | Cox et al., Review of Recent Lab-Scale Investigation on Co-Digestion of Organic Wastes, Water Environment Federation--Joint Residuals and Biosolids Management Conference 2005 (Apr. 17, 2005) (USA). cited by other . | Mertens et al., Developments of Nonthermal Processes for Food Preservation, Food Tech. 46(5):124, 126-133 (May 1992) (USA). cited by other . | Controlling Fluid Flow with Porous Metals, Machine Design (Jan. 8, 1987). cited by other . | Puippe, Influence of Charge and Discharge of Electrical Double Layer in Pulse Plating in Theory and Practice of Pulse Plating (America Electroplaters and Surface Finishers Society), ch. 4, pp. 41-43 (1986) (USA). cited by other . | Kady International materials--2 pages (circa 1999) (USA). cited by other . | Morrisey et al., Sterilization Methods Used in Microbiology, Sterilization Technology, 1993. cited by other . | El-Shazly et al., High-Speed Metal Deposition Using Interrupted Current Techniques in AESF (American Electroplaters and Surface Finishers Society) Third International Pulse Plating Symposium C1-C11 (1986) (USA). cited by other . | Curtiss, Bacterial Cell Wall, Microbiology, W.W. Norton &amp; Co. (1976). cited by other . | Oh et al., Biological Hydrogen Production Using a Membrane Bioreactor, Biotechnology &amp; Bioeng'g 119-127 (Jul. 5, 2004) (USA). cited by other . | Milad et al., PPR Plating for HDI, PC Fab, 40, 42, 44, 46 (2000) (USA). cited by other . | Zhang, Q. H., Qin, B.-L., Barbosa-Canovas, G. V. and Swanson, B. G, Inactivation of E. coli for food pasteurization by high-strength pulsed electric fields, J. Food Process Preserv. 19(2):103-118 (1995) (USA). cited by other . | Gupta, R.P., Pulsed High Electric Field Sterilization. cited by other . | Supplemental European Search Report, issued in regard to EP application No. 01924692 (3 pages, Feb. 29, 2008). cited by other. | Zhang, Q. H., Chang, F.-J. and Barbosa-Canovas, G. V., Inactivation of microorganisms in a semisolid model food using high voltage pulsed electric fields, Lebensm Wiss Technol. 27(6):538-543 (1994) (believed to be Germany). cited by other . | Liu et al., Production of Electricity During Waste Water Treatment Using a Single Chamber Microbial Fuel Cell, Environmental Sci &amp; Tech, 2281-2285 (Feb. 21, 2004) (USA). cited by other . | Water Environment Federation, Be in the Know . . . Go with the Flow! (Sep. 2001) (USA). cited by other . | Dossenbach et al., Pulse Current Electrodeposition of Palladium Silver Alloys in AESF (American Electroplaters and Surface Finishers Society) Third International Pulse Plating Symposium H1-H3 (1986) (USA). cited by other . | Marlen OPTT Series Pump/Stuffer product brochure. cited by other . | Minnesota Dairy Runs Hydrogen Fuel Cell on Biogas, Biocycle, 58 (Jun. 2005) (USA). cited by other . | Method Improves Sludge Digestion, Waste Treatment Tech. News v.12 i8 (1996) (USA). cited by other . | Gutierrez, Recent Advances in Pulse Plating Power Supply Technology &amp; Plating Capability, AESF 5th Pulse Plating Symposium 1-23 (Jun. 2000) (USA). cited by other . | Parry et al., Bioenergy Conversion of Cow Manure, Water Environment Federation--Joint Residuals and Biosolids Management Conference 2005 (Apr. 17, 2005) (USA). cited by other . | Newmet-Thermet Krebsoge Company, Porous Metal Products products brochure. cited by other . | Consideration of Sludge Dewatering Methods in The Microbiology of Waste Waters (W.B. Sauders &amp; Co.) pp. 6-8, 17 (1971) (USA). cited by other . | Bradley et al., Bipolar Electrodeposition on Nanotubes (USA). cited by other . | Wadehra et al, Reduced Wasting from Activated Sludge Processes Using a Mechanical Cell Lysis Technology in WEFTEC 1999, (1999) (USA). cited by other . | Zhang, Q. H., Qiu, X. and Sharma, S. K., Recent development in pulsed electric field processing. National Food Processors Association--New Technologies Yearbook. 31-46 (1997) (believed to be USA). cited by other . | Stafford et al., A Competitive Approach to Bioenergy Management, Water Environment Federation--Joint Residuals and Biosolids Management Conference 2005 (Apr. 17, 2005) (USA). cited by other . | Peshkovsky et al., Dipolar Interactions in Molecules Aligned by Strong AC Electric Fields, J. Magnetic Resonance, 147:104-109 (2000) (USA). cited by other . | Dentel et al., Overview of Electrical Arc Conditioning of Biosolids in Water Environment Research Foundation: Workshop #116 Recent Advances in Biosolids Research: Conditioning, Dewatering, and Beneficial Use 86-98 (1999) (USA). cited by other . | U.S. Food and Drug Administration, Kinetics of Microbial Inactivation for Alternative Food Processing Technologies--Pulsed Electric Fields (Jun. 2000) (USA). cited by other . | Puippe, Qualitative Approach to Pulse Plating in Theory and Practice of Pulse Plating (America Electroplaters and Surface Finishers Society), ch. 1, pp. 1-3 (1986) (USA). cited by other . | Koelzer, Back to the Basics: Pulse Math, Plating &amp; Surface Finishing (Dec. 2000) (USA). cited by other . | Gaudy, et al., The Microbiology of Waste Disposal, in The Microbiology of Waste Waters, W.B. Saunders &amp; Comp., chapter 36 (1971). cited by other . | Kady International materials--4 pages (circa 1999) (USA). cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		43
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US7645382
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US4592291 | US4747920 | US0980463 | US4306978 | US3397140 | US4367132 | US5326530 | US5026484 | US4620493 | US5695650 | US6090266 | US3913500 | US4971705 | US5143626 | US5034111 | US5846425 | US6395176 | US3670891 | US4043047 | US4101400 | US6709594 | US4561953 | US3280982 | US5976719 | US5049248 | US5037524 | US5522553 | US5037560 | US3265605 | US5230809 | US6540919 | US5965093 | US4631133 | US6030538 | US4608179 | US4655932 | US6402065 | US4193206 | US4861496 | US5801489 | US5893979 | US3699906 | US3962069 | US4013552 | US5091079 | US5630915 | US4917785 | US5464513 | US4957606 | US5690978 | US5048404 | US5507927 | US6491820 | US4755305 | US4671874 | US6984305 | WO2004004036 | JP2000185238 | JP1999253999 | JP1989307500 | JP1978091468 | WO2001004356 | JP1999179391 | JP1985025597 | WO1999024372 | WO1998058740 | JP1989210100 | DE4101076 | FR2327965 | JP1998137778
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		70
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US | US | US | US | US | US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		19870305 | 79594404 | 27042002 | 10761402 | 61277600 | 46842799 | 22927999 | 59935504
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2005-08-05 | 2004-03-08 | 2002-10-15 | 2002-03-26 | 2000-07-10 | 1999-12-21 | 1999-01-13 | 2004-08-06
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		OPENCEL LLC
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		OPENCEL LLC
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Glencoe, IL
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Glencoe, IL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		GALLAGHER, MICHAEL, T. | HELD, JEFFREY | CHAUHAN, SATYA, P. | TOMASELLO, ANTHONY, J.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		GALLAGHER, MICHAEL, T.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Highland, Park, IL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Highland, Park, IL | Chicago, IL | Columbus, OH | Libertyville, IL
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		MARSHALL, GERSTEIN &amp; BORUN LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		HRUSKOCI, PETER A
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

