<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7531133
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11/445965
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Use of nitric oxide gas in an extracorporeal circuitry to treat blood plasma
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A method of reducing pathogens in blood by exposure to a nitric oxide containing gas in an extracorporeal circuitry is provided. The method includes: obtaining blood from a mammal or a blood source, separating the blood into plasma and blood cells, exposing the plasma to nitric oxide containing gas, combining the exposed plasma with the blood cells, reducing nitric oxide content in the recombined blood, and returning the blood to the mammal or blood source.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2006-06-01
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2006
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2006-06
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-05-12
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-05
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		A61M1/00 | A61M37/00 | C02F1/44
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		A61M1/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		A
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		A61
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		A61M
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		A61M1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		422/44 | 210/645 | 422/48 | 604/23 | 604/4.01 | 604/5.01 | 604/5.04
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		422/44
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		422
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US20070014688A1 | US7531133 | US20040081580A1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Croen, KD, Evidence for an antiviral effect of Nitric Oxide. J Clin Invest 91:2446-2452, 1993. cited by examiner | Ray, James D. et al., &quot;A New Method of Preparing Nitric Oxide,&quot; Contribution from the Department of Chemistry, Stanford University (1956). cited by other | Shank, J. L. et al., &quot;The Effect of Nitric Oxide on Bacteria,&quot; Applied Microbio, No. 10, 189-189 (1962). cited by other | Norman, C. et al., &quot;Nitrogen Oxides in Tobacco Smoke,&quot; Nature, vol. 205, No. 4971, pp. 915-916, (Feb. 1965). cited by other | Canetti, G., &quot;Present aspects of bacterial resistance in tuberculosis,&quot; Am. Rev. Respir. Dis. 92:687-703 (1965). cited by other | Bass, H. et al., &quot;Regional structure and function in brochiectasis,&quot; Am. Rev. Respir. Dis. 97:598-609 (1968). cited by other | Contractor, A. M. et al., &quot;Development and Evaluation of an Inhalation Aerosol of Nitroglycerin,&quot; Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences, vol. 63, No. 6, pp. 907-911 (Jun. 1974). cited by other | Oda, H. et al., &quot;Nitrosyl-Hemoglobin Formation in the Blood of Animals Exposed to Nitric Oxide,&quot; Archives of Environmental Health, vol. 30, No. 7, pp. 453-456 (Sep. 1975). cited by other | Katsuki, S. et al., &quot;Stimulation of Guanylate Cyclase by Sodium Nitroprusside, Nitroglycerin and Nitric Oxide in Various Tissue Preparations and Comparison to the Effects of Sodium Azide and Hydroxylamine,&quot; Journal of Cyclic Nucleotide Research, vol. 3, pp. 23-25 (1977). cited by other | Hugod, C., &quot;Effect of exposure of 43 PPM nitric oxide and 3.6 PPM nitrogen dioxide on rabbit lung,&quot; Arch. Occup. Environ. Health 42:159-167 (1979). cited by other | Yoshida, J. et al., &quot;Metabolic Fate of Nitric Oxide,&quot; Int Arch Occup Environ Health, vol. 46, No. 1, pp. 71-77 (Apr. 1980). cited by other | Borland, C., &quot;The Fate of Inhaled Nitric Oxide,&quot; Clinical Science, Abstract No. 104, p. 37P (1983). cited by other | Mancinelli et al., &quot;Effects of Nitric Oxide and Nitrogen Dioxide on Bacterial Growth,&quot; Applied and Environmental Microbiology, vol. 46, No. 1, pp. 198-202 (Jul. 1983). cited by other | Demling, R. H. et al., &quot;The Pulmonary and Systemic Response to Recurrent Endotoxemia in the Adult Sheep,&quot; Surgery, vol. 100, No. 5, pp. 876-883 (Nov. 1986). cited by other | Higenbottam, T., &quot;Primary Pulmonary Hypertension,&quot; British Medical Journal, vol. 293, pp. 1456-1457 (Dec. 1986). cited by other | Higenbottam, T. et al., &quot;Primary Pulmonary Hypertension,&quot; British Medical Journal, vol. 294, p. 705 (Mar. 1987). cited by other | Palmer, R.M.J. et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide Release Accounts for the Biological Activity of Endothelium-Derived Relaxing Factor,&quot; Nature, vol. 327, pp. 524-526 (Jun. 1987). cited by other | Ignarro, L. J. et al., &quot;Endothelium-Derived Relaxing Factor Produced and Released From Artery and Vein is Nitric Oxide,&quot; Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, vol. 84, No. 24, pp. 9265-9269 (Dec. 1987). cited by other | Higenbottam, T. W. et al., &quot;Inhaled `Endothelium Derived-Relaxing Factor` (EDRF) in Primary Hypertension (PPH),&quot; Abstract, American Review of Respiratory Disease, Suppl., vol. 137, No. 4, Part 2, p. 107 (Apr. 1988). cited by other | Ignarro, L. J. et al., &quot;Endothelium-Derived Relaxing Factor and Nitric Oxide Possess Identical Pharmacologic Properties as Relaxants of Bovine Arterial and Venous Smooth Muscle,&quot; The Journal of Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics, vol. 246, No. 1, pp. cited by other | Dinh-Xuan, A. T. et al., &quot;Non-Prostanoid Endothelium-Derived Vasoactive Factors,&quot; The Journal of International Medical Research, vol. 17, pp. 305-315 (1989). cited by other | Borland, C. D. R. et al., &quot;A Simultaneous Single Breath Measurement of Pulmonary Diffusing Capacity with Nitric Oxide and Carbon Monoxide,&quot; The European Respiratory Journal, vol. 2, No. 1, pp. 56-63 (Jan. 1989). cited by other | Buga, G. M. et al., &quot;Endothelium-Derived Nitric Oxide Relaxes Nonvascular Smooth Muscle,&quot; European Journal of Pharmacology, vol. 161, No. 1, pp. 61-72, (Feb. 1989). cited by other | Garg, U. C. et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide-generating Vasodilaters and 8-Bromo-Cyclic Guanosine Monophosphate Inhibit Mitogensis and Proliferation of Cultured Rat Vascular Smooth Muscle Cells,&quot; The Journal of Clinical Investigation, vol. 83, No. 5, pp. 1774-1777 (May 1989). cited by other | Meyer, M. et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide (NO), a New Test Gas for Study of Alveolar-capillary Diffusion,&quot; The European Respiratory Journal, vol. 2, No. 6, pp. 494-496 (Jun. 1989). cited by other | Dinh-Xuan, A. T. et al., &quot;Primary Pulmonary Hypertension: Diagnosis, Medical and Surgical Treatment,&quot; vol. 84, pp. 189-197 (1990). cited by other | Stavert, D. M. et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide and Nitrogen Dioxide as Inducers of Acute Pulmonary Injury When Inhaled at Relatively High Concentrations for Brief Periods,&quot; Inhalation Toxicology 2:53-67 (1990). cited by other | Moinard, J. et al., &quot;Determination of Lung Capilary Blood Volume and Membrane Diffusing capacity in Patients with COLD using the NO-CO Method,&quot; The European Respiratory Journal, vol. 3, pp. 318-322 (1990). cited by other | Archer, S. L., &quot;Comparison of the Hemodynamic Effects of Nitric Oxide and Endothelium-Dependent Vasodilators in Intact Lungs,&quot; Journal of Applied Physiology, vol. 68, No. 2, pp. 735-747 (Feb. 1990). cited by other | Meyer, M. et al., &quot;Pulmonary Diffusing Capacities for Nitric Oxide and carbon Monoxide Determined by Rebreathing in Dogs,&quot; Journal of Applied Physiology, vol. 68, No. 6, pp. 2344-2357 (Jun. 1990). cited by other | Vane, J. R. et al., &quot;Regulatory Functions of the Vascular Endothelium,&quot; The New England Journal of Medicine, vol. 323, No. 1, pp. 27-36 (Jul. 1990). cited by other | Higenbottam, T. et al., &quot;Has the Treatment of Asthma Improved?&quot; Chest, vol. 98, No. 3, pp. 706-712 (Sep. 1990). cited by other | Swami, A. et al., &quot;The Pulmonary Physician and critical Care: 2. The Injury Lung: Conventional and Novel Respiratory Therapy,&quot; Thorax, vol. 47, pp. 555-562 (1992). cited by other | Bult, H. et al., &quot;Chronic Exposure to Exogenous Nitric Oxide May Suppress its Endogenous Release and Efficacy,&quot; Journal of Cardiovascular Pharmacology, vol. 17, Suppl. 3, pp. S79-S82 (1991). cited by other | Frostell, C. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide, A Selective Pulmonary Vasodilator Reversing Hypoxic Pulmonary Vasoconstriction,&quot; Circulation Journal of the American Heart Association, vol. 83, pp. 2083-2047 (1991). cited by other | Hendrickson, D.A. et al, &quot;Regents and Stains,&quot; Manual of Clinical Microbiology, 5.sup.th Ed., American Society for Microbiology, pp. 1289-1314 (1991). cited by other | Cremona, g. et al., &quot;Endothelium-derived Relaxing Factor and the Pulmonary Circulation,&quot; Lung, vol. 169, pp. 185-202 (1991). cited by other | Falke, K. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide Selectively Reduces Pulmonary Hypertension in Severe ARDS and Improves Gas Exchange as well as right Heart Ejection fraction--A Case Report.&quot; Abstract 248. Am. Rev. Respir. Dis., vol. 143 (1991). cited by other | Fratacci, M. D., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide--A Selective Pulmonary Vasodilator of Heparin-Protamine Vasoconstriction in Sheep,&quot; Anesthesiology, vol. 75, pp. 990-999 (1991). cited by other | Denis, M., &quot;Interferon--Gamma-treated Murine Macrophages Inhibit Growth of Tubercle Bacilli via the Generation of Reactive Nitrogen Intermediates,&quot; Cellular Immunology, vol. 132, No. 1, pp. 150-157 (Jan. 1991). cited by other | Dinh-Xuan, A. T. et al., &quot;Impairment of Endothelium-Dependent Pulmonary-Artery Relaxation in Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease,&quot; The New England Journal of Medicine, vol. 324, No. 22, pp. 1539-1547 ( May 1991). cited by other | Frostell, C. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide--A Selective Pulmonary Vasodilator Reversing Hypoxic Pulmonary Vasoconstriction,&quot; Circulation, vol. 83, No. 6 (Jun. 1991). cited by other | Moncada, S. et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide: Physiology, Pathophysiology, and Pharmacology,&quot; Pharmacological Reviews, vol. 43, No. 2 (Jun. 1991). cited by other | Frostell, C. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide Dilates Human Hypoxic Pulmonary Vasoconstriction Without Causing Systemic Vasodilation,&quot; Anesthesiology, The Journal of The American Society of Anesthesiologists, Inc., vol. 75, No. 3A, Abstract A989 (Sep. 1991). cited by other | Girard, C. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide (NO) in Pulmonary Hypertension Following Mitral Valve Replacement,&quot; Anesthesiology, The Journal of the American Society of Anesthesiologists, Inc., vol. 75, No. 3A, Abstract A983 (Sep. 1991). cited by other | Robert, J. D. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide (NO): A Selective Pulmonary Vasodilator for the Treatment of Persistent Pulmonary Hypertension of the Newborn (PPHN),&quot; Abstract 1279, Circulation, vol. 84, No. 4, pp. II-321 (Oct. 1991). cited by other | Pepke-Zaba, J. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide as a Cause of Selective Pulmonary Vasodilatation in Pulmonary Hypertension,&quot; The Lancet, vol. 338, No. 8776, pp. 1173-1174 (Nov. 1991). cited by other | Radomski, M. W., et al., &quot;Human Colorectal Adenocarcinoma Cells: Differential Nitric Oxide Synthesis Determines Their Ability to Aggregate Platelets,&quot; Cancer Research, vol. 51, pp. 6073-6078 (Nov. 15, 1991). cited by other | Johns, R. A., &quot;EDRF/Nitric Oxide--The Endogenous Nitrovasodilator and a New cellular Messenger,&quot; Anesthesiology, The Journal of The American Society of Anesthesiologists, Inc., vol. 75, No. 6, pp. 927-931 (Dec. 1991). cited by other | Pearl, R. G., &quot;The Pulmonary Circulation,&quot; Anesthesiology, vol. 5, pp. 848-854 (1992). cited by other | Chan, J. et al., &quot;Killing of Virulent Mycobacterium Tuberculosis by Reactive Nitrogen Intermediates Produced by Activated Murine Macophages,&quot; J. Exp. Med. 175:1111-1122 (Apr. 1992). cited by other | Rossiant, R. et al., &quot;Successful Treatment of Severe Adult Respiratory Distress Syndrome with Inhaled Nitric Oxide,&quot; American Review of Respiratory Disease, Suppl. vol. 145, No. 4, Part 2, p. A80 (Apr. 1992). cited by other | Rossiant, R. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide in Contrast to Infused Prostacyclin Selectively Reduces Pulmonary Hypertension and Improves Gas Exchange in Severe ARDS,&quot; Abstract, American Review of Respiratory Disease, Suppl. vol. 145, No. 4, Part 2, p. A185. cited by other | Bigatello, L. M., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide is a Selective Pulmonary Vasodilator in Septic Patients with Severe ARDS,&quot; Abstract, American Review of Respiratory Disease, Suppl., vol. 145, No. 4, Part 2, p. A185(Apr. 1992). cited by other | Snyder, S. H. et al., Biological Roles of Nitric Oxide, Scientific American, vol. 266, No. 5, pp. 68-77 (May 1992). cited by other | Foubert, L., &quot;Safety Guidelines for Use of Nitric Oxide,&quot; The Lancet, vol. 339, No. 8809, pp. 1615-1616 (Jun. 1992). cited by other | Messent, M. et al., &quot;Pharmacotherapy in Lung Injury,&quot; Thorax, vol. 47, No. 7, pp. 651-656 (Jul. 1992). cited by other | Barash, P. et al. &quot;Anesthesiology,&quot; The Journal of the American Medical Association, vol. 268, No. 3, pp. 335-337 (Jul. 1992). cited by other | Dupuy, P. M. et al., &quot;Bronchodilator Action of Inhaled Nitric Oxide in Guinea Pigs,&quot; J. Clin. Invest., vol. 90, pp. 421-428 (Aug. 1992). cited by other | Kinsella, J. P. et al., &quot;Hemodynamic Effects of Exogenous Nitric Oxide in Ovine Transitional Pulmonary Circulation,&quot; American Journal of Physiology: Heart and Circulatory Physiology, vol. 32, No. 3, pp. H875-H880 (Sep. 1992). cited by other | Roberts, J. D. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide in Persistent Pulmonary Hypertension of the Newborn,&quot; The Lancet , vol. 340, pp. 818-819 (Oct. 1992). cited by other | Kinsella, J. P. et al., &quot;Low-Dose Inhalational Nitric Oxide in Persistent Pulmonary Hypertension of the Newborn,&quot; The Lancet, vol. 340, pp. 819-820 (Oct. 1992). cited by other | Girard, C. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide After Mitral Valve Replacement in Patients with Chronic pulmonary Artery Hypertension,&quot; Anesthesiology, The Journal of the American Society of Anesthesiologists, Inc., vol. 77, No. 5, pp. 880-883 (Nov. 1992). cited by other | Kacmarek, R. M., &quot;Nitric Oxide as a Bronchodilator in Methacholine Induced Bronchospasm in Mild Asthmatics,&quot; Abstract (1993). cited by other | Blomqvist, H. et al., &quot;Enhanced Pneumonia Resolution by Inhalation of Nitric Oxide?&quot; Acta Anaesthesiol Scand, vol. 37, pp. 110-114 (1993). cited by other | Buga, G. M. et al., &quot;Negative Feedback Regulation of Endothelial Cell Function by Nitric Oxide,&quot; Circulation Research, Journal of the American Heart Association, 73:808-812 (1993). cited by other | Higenbottam, T., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide: A Magic Bullet?&quot; Quarterly Journal of Medicine, vol. 86, pp. 555-558 (1993). cited by other | Stenqvist, O. et al., &quot;Evaluation of a New System for Ventilatory Administration of Nitric Oxide,&quot; Acta Anaesthesiologica Scandinavica, pp. 687-691 (1993). cited by other | Rossaint, R. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide For The Adult Respiratory Distress Syndrome,&quot; New England Journal of Medicine, vol. 328, pp. 399-405 (Feb. 1993). cited by other | Maragos, C. M., et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide/Nucleophile Complexes Inhibit the in Vitro Proliferation of A375 Melanoma Cells via Nitric Oxide Release,&quot; Cancer Research, vol. 53, pp. 564-568 (Feb. 1, 1993). cited by other | Pearl, R. G. &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide--The Past, The Present and the Future,&quot; Anesthesiology, vol. 78, No. 3, pp. 413-416 (Mar. 1993). cited by other | Assreuy, J. et al., &quot;Feedback Inhibition of Nitric Oxide Synthase Activity by Nitric Oxide,&quot; British Journal of Pharmacology, vol. 108, pp. 883-837 (Mar. 1993). cited by other | Higenbottam, T. et al., &quot;Highlights on Pulmonary Hypertension: A Commentary,&quot; The European Respiratory Journal, vol. 6, No. 7, pp. 932-933 (Jul. 1993). cited by other | Haworth, S. G., &quot;Pulmonary Hypertension in Childhood,&quot; The European Respiratory Journal, vol. 6, No. 7, pp. 1037-1043 (Jul. 1993). cited by other | Higenbottam, T. et al., &quot;Acute and Chronic Hypoxic Pulmonary Hypertension,&quot; The European Respiratory Journal, vol. 6, No. 8, pp. 1207-1212 (Sep. 1993). cited by other | Mansch, R. et al., &quot;Simulation of Microbiologically and chemically Influenced corrosion of Natural Sandstone,&quot; Abstract, ASTM Speacial Technical Publication, 203-16; 1 pg. (1994). cited by other | Lowenstein, C. J. et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide: a Physiologic Messenger,&quot; Annals of Internal Medicine, vol. 120, Issue 3, pp. 227-237 (Feb. 1994). cited by other | Dong, Z., et al., &quot;Inverse Correlation Between Expression of Inducible Nitric Oxide Synthase Activity and Production of Metastasis in K-1735 Murine Melanoma Cells,&quot; Cancer Research, vol. 54, pp. 789-793 (Feb. 1, 1994). cited by other | Butt, A. Y. et al., &quot;New Therapies for Primary Pulmonary Hypertension,&quot; Chest, vol. 105, No. 2, pp. 21S-25S (Feb. 1994). cited by other | Foubert, L. et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide in Pulmonary Hypertension: Therapeutic Considerations,&quot; Journal of Cardiothoracic and Vascular Anesthesia, vol. 8, No. 3, Suppl. 2, p. 41 (Jun. 1994). cited by other | Snow, D. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide in Pulmonary Hypertension,&quot; Journal of Cardiothoracic and Vascular Anesthesia, vol. 8, No. 3, Suppl. 2, Abstract No. 127 (Jun. 1994). cited by other | O'Brien, L. et al., Strains of Mycobacterium Tuberculosis Differ in Susceptibility to Reactive Nitrogen Intermediates In Vitro, Infection and Immunity, vol. 62, No. 11, pp. 5187-5190 (Aug. 1994). cited by other | Young, J. D., &quot;A Universal Nitric Oxide Delivery System,&quot; British Journal of Anaesthesia, vol. 73, No. 4, pp. 700-702 (Oct. 1994). cited by other | Hagenah, Jens-Uwe, &quot;The Use of Nitric Oxide (NO) in Intensive Care Ventilation,&quot; Dragerwerk Aktiengesellscha, pp. 1 and 3-36. cited by other | Hanson, S. R., et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide Donors: A Continuing Opportunity in Drug Design,&quot; Nitric Oxide Biochemistry, Molecular Biology, and Therapeutic Implications, Advances in Pharmacology, vol. 34, pp. 383-398 (1995). cited by other | Chan, J. et al., &quot;Effects of Nitric Oxide Synthase Inhibitors on Murine Infection with Mycobacterium Tuberculosis,&quot; Infection and Immunity, vol. 63, No. 2., pp. 736-740 (Feb. 1995). cited by other | DeGroote, M. A., et al., &quot;NO Inhibitions: Antimicrobial Properties of Nitric Oxide,&quot; Clinical Infectious Disease, vol. 21, Suppl. 2, pp. S162-S165 (Oct. 1995). cited by other | Body, S. C., M.D. et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide: Delivery, Measurement, and Clinical Application,&quot; Journal of Cardiothoracic and Vascular Anesthesia, vol. 9, No. 6, pp. 748-763 (Dec. 1995). cited by other | Higenbottam, T. et al., &quot;the Treatment of Primary Pulmonary Hypertension,&quot; Therapeutic Applications of Iloprost, A Volume in the Clinical Monograph Series, pp. 35-41 (Apr. 1995). cited by other | Szabo, C., &quot;The Pathophysiological Role of Peroxynitrite in Shock, Inflammation and Ischemia-Reperfusion Injury,&quot; Shock, vol. 6, No. 2, pp. 79-88 (1996). cited by other | Higenbottam, T., &quot;Nitric Oxide and the Lung,&quot; Horizons in Medicine, No. 7 pp. 203-224 (1996). cited by other | Young, J. D. et al., &quot;Delivery and Monitoring of Inhaled Nitric Oxide,&quot; Intensive Care Medicine, vol. 22, No. 1, pp. 77-86 (Jan. 1996). cited by other | Mellgren, K., et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide in the Oxygenator Sweep Gas Reduces Platelet Activation During Experimental Perfusion,&quot; The Annals of Thoracic Surgery, vol. 61, No. 4, pp. 1194-1198 (Apr. 1996). cited by other | Ramnarine, S. I., et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide Inhibition of Basal and Neurogenic Mucus Secretion in Feerrete Trachea in Vitro,&quot; British Journal of Pharmacology, vol. 118 (4), pp. 998-1002 (Jun. 1996). cited by other | Channick, R. N., M.D. et al., &quot;Pulsed Delivery of Inhaled Nitric Oxide to Patients with Primary Pulmonary Hypertension,&quot; Chest, The Cardiopulmonary and Critical Care Journal, vol. 109, No. 6, pp. 1545-1549 (Jun. 1996). cited by other | Hudome, S. M., M.D. et al., &quot;Precise Control of Nitric Oxide Concentration in the Inspired Gas of Continuous Flow Respiratory Devices,&quot; Pediatric Pulmonology, vol. 22, No. 3, pp. 182-187 (Sep. 1996). cited by other | Cuthbertson, B. H. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide,&quot; The Lancet, vol. 348, No. 9039, pp. 1447-1448 (Nov. 1996). cited by other | Gerlach, H. et al., &quot;Low Levels of Inhaled Nitric Oxide in Acute Lung Injury,&quot; Nitric Oxide and the Lung, vol. 98, Chapter 14, pp. 271-283 (1997). cited by other | Dupuy, P. M. et al., &quot;Bronchial Effects of Nitric Oxide,&quot; Nitric Oxide and the Lung, vol. 98, Chapter 15, pp. 285-311 (1997). cited by other | Leopold, J. A. et al., &quot;New Developments in Nitrosovasodilator Therapy,&quot; Vascular Medicine, vol. 2, No. 3 (1997). cited by other | Rook, G. A. W., &quot;Intractable Mycobacterial Infections Associated with Genetic Defects in the Receptor for Interferon Gamma: What Does This Tell Us About Immunity to Mycobacteria?&quot; Thorax, vol. 52 (Suppl. 3), pp. S41-S46 (1997). cited by other | Katayama, Y. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide and Arterial Oxygen Tension in Patients with chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease and Severe Pulmonary Hypertension,&quot; Thorax, The Journal of the British Thoracic Society, vol. 52, pp. 120-124 (1997). cited by other | Neonatal Inhaled Nitric Oxide Study Group, &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide in Full-Term and Nearly Full-Term Infants with Hypoxic Respiratory Failure,&quot; New England Journal of Medicine, 336(9):597-604 (Feb. 1997). cited by other | Roberts, J. D. et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide and Persistent Pulmonary Hypertension of the Newborn,&quot; New England Journal of Medicine, 336:605-610 (Feb. 1997). cited by other | Imanaka, H., M.D. et al., &quot;Inaccuracies of Nitric Oxide Delivery Systems During Adult Mechanical Ventilation,&quot; Anesthesiology, vol. 86, No. 3, pp. 676-688 (Mar. 1997). cited by other | Marriott, H. et al., &quot;The Role of Nitric Oxide in Respiratory Disease,&quot; Schweiz Med Wochenschr, vol. 127, pp. 709-714 (Apr. 1997). cited by other | Nozaki, Y. et al., &quot;Mechanism of Nitric Oxide-Dependent Killing of Mycobacterium bovis BCG in Human Alveolar Macrophages,&quot; Infection and Immunity, vol. 65, pp. 3644-3647 (Sep. 1997). cited by other | Hess, D., RRT, Ph.D. et al., &quot;Delivery Systems for Inhaled Nitric Oxide,&quot; Respiratory Care Clinics of North America, vol. 3, No. 3, pp. 371-410 (Sep. 1997). cited by other | Hoehn T., M.D. et al., &quot;Effect of Therapeutic Concentrations of Nitric Oxide on Bacterial Grown in Vitro,&quot; Crit Care Med, vol. 26, No. 11, pp. 1857-1862 (1998). cited by other | Bauer, J. A. et al., Evaluation of Linear Polyethylenei-mine/Nitric Oxide Adduct on Wound Repair: Therapy Versus Toxicity, The Wound Healing Society, pp. 569-577 (1998). cited by other | Pizzichini, M. M. M. et al., &quot;Asthma and Natural Colds: Inflammatory Indices in Induced Sputum: A Feasibility Study,&quot; American Journal of Respiratory Critical Care Medicine, vol. 158, pp. 1178-1184 (1998). cited by other | Higenbottam, T. et al., &quot;Primary and Secondary Pulmonary Hypertension,&quot; Seminars in Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, vol. 19, No. 1, pp. 91-95 (1998). cited by other | Long R. et al., &quot;Pulmonary Tuberculosis Treated with Directly Observed Therapy: Serial Changes in Lung Structure and Function,&quot; Chest, vol. 113, pp. 933-943 (1998). cited by other | Klein, M.D. et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide Delivery Systems,&quot; Acta Anaesthesiologica Scandinavica, pp. 274-275 (1998). cited by other | Francoe, M, RRT et al., &quot;Inhaled Nitric Oxide: Technical Aspects of Administration and Monitoring,&quot; Critical Care Medicine, vol. 26, No. 4, pp. 782-796 (Apr. 1998). cited by other | Keefer, L. K., &quot;Nitric Oxide-Releasing Compounds: From Basic Research to Promising Drugs,&quot; The American Chemical Society, vol. 28, pp. 30-35 (Aug. 1998). cited by other | Ivy, D. D., M.D. et al., &quot;Acute Hemodynamic Effects of Pulsed Delivery of Low Flow Nasal Nitric Oxide in Children with Pulmonary Hypertension,&quot; The Journal of Pediatrics, vol. 133, No. 3, pp. 453-456 (Sep. 1998). cited by other | Hiesmayr, M. J. et al., &quot;Performance of Proportional and Continous Nitric Oxide Delivery Systems During Pressure- and Volume-Controlled Ventilation,&quot; The British Journal of Anaesthesia, vol. 81, No. 4, pp. 544-552 (Oct. 1998). cited by other | Katayama, Y., M.D. et al., &quot;Minimizing the Inhaled Dose of NO With Breath-by-Breath Delivery of Spikes of Concentrated Gas,&quot; Circulation, Journal of the American Heart Association, vol. 98, No. 22 (Dec. 1998). cited by other | Higenbottam, T. et al., &quot;Treatments for Severe Pulmonary Hypertension,&quot; The Lancet, vol. 353, No. 9150, pp. 338-340 (Jan. 1999). cited by other | Long, R. et al., &quot;Mycobacteriocidal Action of Exogenous Nitric Oxide,&quot; Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy, vol. 43, No. 2, pp. 403-405, (Feb. 1999). cited by other | Schofnagl, H. et al., &quot;Proportional and Continuous NO Delivery Systems,&quot; British Journal of Anaesthesia, vol. 82, No. 4, pp. 647-653 (Apr. 1999). cited by other | Rimmelzwaan, G. F. et al., &quot;Inhibition of Influenza Virus Replication by Nitric Oxide,&quot; Journal of Virology, American Society for Microbiology, vol. 73, No. 10, pp. 8880-8883 (Oct. 1999). cited by other | Webert, K. E., M.D. et al., &quot;Effects of Inhaled Nitric Oxide In A Rate Model of Pseudomonas ceruginosa Pneumonia,&quot; Crit Car Med, vol. 28, No. 7, pp. 2397-2405 (2000). cited by other | Tamaoki, J., M.D., et al., &quot;Impairment of Airway Mucociliary Transport in Patients with Sinobronchial Syndrome: Role of Nitric Oxide,&quot; Journal of Aerosol Medicine, vol. 13, No. 3, pp. 239-244 (Nov. 2000). cited by other | Long et al., &quot;Treatment of Sputum-Smear Positive Pulmonary Tuberculosis With Inhaled Nitric Oxide,&quot; 2001-Abstract Form to the ATS 2001 San Francisco, May 18-23, 2001 (faxed Mar. 27, 2001). cited by other | Frank, S., et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide Drives Skin Repair: Novel Functions Of An Established Mediator,&quot; Kidney International, vol. 61, pp. 882-888 (2002). cited by other | Imada, M., et al., &quot;Functional Roles of Nasal Nitric Oxide in Nasal Patency and Mucociliary Function,&quot; ACTA Oto-Laryngologica, vol. 122, No. 5, pp. 513-519 (Jul. 2002). cited by other | Kirov, M. Y., M.D., et al., &quot;Combination of Intravenously Infused Methylene Blue and Inhaled Nitric Oxide Ameliorates Endotoxin-Induced Lung Injury in Awake Sheep,&quot; Critical Care Medicine, vol. 31, No. 1, pp. 179-186 (Jan. 2003). cited by other | Shami, P. J., et al., JS-K, A Glutathione/Glutathione S-Transferase-activated Nitric Oxide Donor of the Diazeniumdiolate Class with Potent Antineoplastic Activity, Molecular Cancer Therapeutics, vol. 2, pp. 409-417 (Apr. 2003). cited by other | Counter-Defendants's First Amended Responses to Counterclaimants's Second Set of Interrogatories Relating to Counterclaims (Nos. 19-38) (Oct. 2003). cited by other | Miller, Chris C. et al.; &quot;Treatment of Chronic Nonhealing Leg Ulceration with Gaseous Nitric Oxide: A Case Study&quot;; Journal of Cutaneous Medicine and Surgery, pp. 233-238 (2004). cited by other | Vijh, A. K., &quot;High Infectious Burden, Low Cancer Incidence, and Early Malignancy in Developing Countries: A Molecular Hypothesis in Term of the Role of Nitric Oxide,&quot; Medical Hypotheses, vol. 63, pp. 208-210 (Feb. 2004). cited by other | Sanders, S. P. et al., &quot;Role of Nasal Nitric Oxide in the Resolution of Experimental Rhinovirus Infection,&quot; Journal of Allergy and Clinical Immunology, vol. 113, No. 4, pp. 697-702 (Apr. 2004). cited by other | Schmidt, I. et al., Physiologic and Proteomic Evidence for a Role of Nitric Oxide in Biofilm Formation by Nitrosomonas europaea and Other Ammonia Oxidizers; Journal of Bacteriology, vol. 186, No. 9, pp. 2781-2788 (May 2004). cited by other | Reynolds, M. M., et al., &quot;Nitric Oxide-Releasing Hydrophobic Polymers: Preparation, Characterization, and Potential Biomedical Applications,&quot; Free Radical Biology &amp; Medicine, The Official Journal for the Society for Free Radical Biology and Medicine, vol. 37, No. 7, pp. 926-936 (Oct. 2004). cited by other | Lechner, M., et al., &quot;Inducible Nitric Oxide Synthase (iNOS) in Tumor Biology: The Two Sides of the Same Coin,&quot; Seminars in Cancer Biology, vol. 15, pp. 277-289 (2005). cited by other | Ghaffair, A., et al., &quot;A Direct Nitric Oxide Gas Delivery System for Bacterial and Mammalian Cell Cultures,&quot; Nitric Oxide Biology and Chemistry, vol. 12, pp. 129-140 (2005). cited by other | Proud, D., &quot;Nitric Oxide and The Common Cold,&quot; Journal of Allergy and Clinical Immunology, vol. 5, pp. 37-42 (2005). cited by other | Nablo, B. J., Inhibition of Implant-Associated Infections Via Nitric Oxide Release, Science Direct, Biomaterials, vol. 26, pp. 6984-6990 (May 2005). cited by other | McMullin, B. B., MSc RRT, et al., &quot;The Antimicrobial Effect of Nitric Oxide on the Bacteria That Cause Nosocomial Pneumonia in Mechanically Ventilated Patients in the Intensive Care Unit,&quot; Respiratory Care, vol. 50, No. 11, pp. 1451-1456 (Nov. 2005). cited by other | Hurford, W. E.; Nitric Oxide As A Bacterial Agent: Is The Cure Worse Than The Disease?; Respiratory Care, vol. 50, No. 11, pp. 1428-1429 (Nov. 2005). cited by other | Katayama, Y. et al., &quot;A Minimal Dose of Inhaled Nitric Oxide Delivered As A `Spike `of Small Volume in Early Inhalation,&quot; Section of Respiratory Medicine, Division of Clinical Sciences, The Medical School, University of Sheffield (23 pages). cited by other | Turchi, J. J., &quot;Nitric Oxide and Cisplatin Resistance: NO Easy Answers,&quot; PNAS, vol. 103, No. 12, pp. 4337-4338 (Mar. 21, 2006). cited by other.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		144
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US8280484 | US7947227 | US8317776
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US3036584 | US3192106 | US4127121 | US4191952 | US4224941 | US4328823 | US4336798 | US4345612 | US4442856 | US4608041 | US4611590 | US4614513 | US4770168 | US4905685 | US4954526 | US5154697 | US5155137 | US5159924 | US5197462 | US5396882 | US5423313 | US5427797 | US5485827 | US5514204 | US5519020 | US5531218 | US5536241 | US5558083 | US5570683 | US5615669 | US5632981 | US5648101 | US5650442 | US5651358 | US5676963 | US5688236 | US5692497 | US5700830 | US5713349 | US5722392 | US5725492 | US5732693 | US5765548 | US5789447 | US5810795 | US5814666 | US5814667 | US5823180 | US5834030 | US5837736 | US5839433 | US5840759 | US5845633 | US5873359 | US5885621 | US5904938 | US5918596 | US5957880 | US6000403 | US6060020 | US6063407 | US6067983 | US6071254 | US6073627 | US6083209 | US6089229 | US6103275 | US6109260 | US6110895 | US6125846 | US6131572 | US6142147 | US6158434 | US6160021 | US6164276 | US6190704 | US6200558 | US6232336 | US6265420 | US6270779 | US6358536 | US6379660 | US6432077 | US6472390 | US6494314 | US6511991 | US6555058 | US6571790 | US6581599 | US6601580 | US6673338 | US6703046 | US6706274 | US6715485 | US6747062 | US6750254 | US6758214 | US6780849 | US6786217 | US6793644 | US6796966 | US6811965 | US6867194 | US6887485 | US6911478 | US6920876 | US6938357 | US6949530 | US7048951 | US7105502 | US7118767 | US7122018 | US7199154 | US20020069877 | US20020082566 | US20020119115 | US20020138051 | US20020155164 | US20020156416 | US20020169202 | US20030039697 | US20030150457 | US20030165578 | US20030203915 | US20030215528 | US20030228564 | US20040009238 | US20040043026 | US20040081580 | US20040112378 | US20040131703 | US20040163647 | US20040180863 | US20040259840 | US20050016427 | US20050079148 | US20050137521 | US20050142217 | US20050148566 | US20050171066 | US20050191372 | US20050217668 | US20050217679 | US20050251117 | US20050265958 | US20050288260 | US20060008529 | US20060068031 | US20060147553 | US20070065473 | US20070086954 | US20070088316 | US20070104653 | DE003713396 | EP0640356 | EP0640357 | EP0659445 | EP1243278 | FR2656218 | JP1991139364 | JP1991207365 | KR0202066 | WO1992017445 | WO1993015779 | WO1993017741 | WO1995009612 | WO1996000006 | WO1996022803 | WO1996025184 | WO1996031217 | WO1998001142 | WO1999049921 | WO2000007653 | WO2000030659 | WO2001065935 | WO2002056864 | WO2003066109 | WO2005060603 | WO2005110052 | WO2005110441
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		180
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		44596506 | 65866503 | 40940002
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2006-06-01 | 2003-09-09 | 2002-09-10
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		PULMONOX TECHNOLOGIES CORPORATION
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		PULMONOX TECHNOLOGIES CORPORATION
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Edmonton, Alberta, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Edmonton, Alberta, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		HOLE, DOUGLAS | MILLER, CHRISTOPHER, C.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		HOLE, DOUGLAS
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Edmonton, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Edmonton, CA | North, Vancouver, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		SIDLEY AUSTIN LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		DEAK, LESLIE R
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

