<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7540965
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US10/551578
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Process for treating concentrated salt solutions containing DOC
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A process for removing DOC (dissolved organic carbon) from a concentrated salt solution containing DOC by contacting the salt solution with a coagulant/flocculant such that the DOC becomes insoluble and removing the insoluble DOC from the salt solution.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2004-04-02
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2004
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2004-04
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-06-02
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-06
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/661 | 210/663 | 210/667 | 210/670 | 210/692
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/661
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US20070039895A1 | AU2003901583D0 | US7540965 | WO2004087586A1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Bolto et al. (1985) &quot;Continuous Ion Exchange Using Magnetic Micro-Resins--The Continuous Sirotherm Desalination Demonstration Plant,&quot; AWWW 1985 Int. Conf. Proc. :282-288. cited by other | Bursill et al. (1985) &quot;The Effect of Natural Organics on Water Treatment,&quot; AWWA 11th Federal Conv. :197-204. cited by other | Chriswell et al. (1977) &quot;Comparison of Macroreticular Resin and Activated Carbon as Sorbents,&quot; J. AWWW Dec. :669-674. cited by other | Derwent Abstract Accession No. 91-255202/35, HU T0056044A, Vilamosenergiaipari ki, Jul. 29, 1991. cited by other | Galjaard et al. (2002) &quot;Enhanced Pre-Coat Engineering (EPCE) for MF and UF: Steps to Full-Scale Application,&quot; Proc. IWA, ISSSN 0941-0961. cited by other | Laine et al. (2002) &quot;Understanding Membrane Fouling: A Review of Over a Decade of Research,&quot; Proc. IWA, ISSN 0941-0961. cited by other | Lee et al. (2002) &quot;Determination of Mass Transport Characteristics for Natural Organic Matter (NOM) in Ultrafiltration (UF) and Nanofiltration (NF) Membranes,&quot; Water Sci and Technol. 2(2):151-160. cited by other | Rook et al. (1979) &quot;Removal of Trihalomethane Precursors from Surface Waters Using Weal Base Resins,&quot; Water Technol. Quality J. :520-524. cited by other | Shim et al. (2002) &quot;Effects of Natural Organic Matter and Ionic Strength on Membrane Surface Charge,&quot; J. Environmental Sci Technol. 366(17):3864-3871. cited by other | Swinton et al. (1983) &quot;Continuous Ion Exchange Using Magnetic Microbeads--Field Trials of a Transportable Pilot Plant,&quot; AWWW 10th Federal Convention 30-1-30-14. cited by other | Symons et al. (1992) &quot;The Use of Anion Exchange Resins for the Removal of Natural Organic Matter from Municipal Water,&quot; International Water Conference Water Conference, Proceedings Book :92-120. cited by other | Tilsley et al. (1978) &quot;Ion Exchange in the Water Industry--Interaction of Organic Matter with Anion Resins,&quot; Chem. Industry :142-149. cited by other | Amiad Turbocelan Filters, http://www.amiadusa.com , Non dated. cited by other | Amy et al. (1999) &quot;Interactions Between Natural Organic Matter (NOM) and Membranes: Rejection and Fouling,&quot; Water Sci Technol. 40(9):131-139. cited by other | Ariza et al. (2002) &quot;Effect of pH on Electrokinetic and Electrochemical Parameter of Both Sub-Layers of Composite Polyamide/Polysulfone Membranes,&quot; Desalination 148:377-382. cited by other | Bourke et al. (Apr. 1999) &quot;Scale-up of the MIEX DOC Process for Full Scale Water Treatment Plants,&quot; Water Corporation of WA., 18th Federal Convention, Australian Water, and Wastewater Association, Proceedings 11-14, Adelaide Australia. cited by other | Brattebo et al. (1987) &quot;Ion Exchange for the Removal of Humic Acids in Water Treatment,&quot; Wat. Res. 21(9):1045-1052. cited by other | Brown et al. (1974) &quot;Anion Exchange Resin Performance in the Treatment of River Trent Water,&quot; Effluent Water Treat. J. 14:417-422. cited by other | Chai et al. (1998) &quot;Charged Polyacrylonitrile Membranes Having Amphiphilic Quaternized Ammonium Groups for Ultrafiltration,&quot; Appl. Poly. Sci. 69(9):1821-1828. cited by other | Childress et al. (2000) &quot;Relating Nanofiltration Membrane Performance to Membrane Charge (Electrokinetic) Characteristics,&quot; Environ. Sci. Technol. 34:3710-3716. cited by other | Cho et al. (2000) &quot;Membrane Filtration of Natural Organic Matter: Comparison of Flux Decline, NOM Rejection, and Foulants During Filtration with Three UF Membranes,&quot; Desalination 127:283-298. cited by other | Cho et al. (2000) &quot;Membrane Filtration of Natural Organic Matter: Factors and Mechanisms Affecting Rejection and Flux Decline with Charged Ultra Filtration (UF),&quot; J. Memb. Sci. 164:89-110. cited by other | Cho et al. (1998) &quot;Characterization of Clean and Natural Organic Matter (NOM) Fouled NF and UF Membranes, and Foulants Characterization,&quot; Desalination 118:101-108. cited by other | Christy et al. (2002) &quot;High-Performance Tangential Flow Filtration: A Highly Selective Membrane Separation Process,&quot; Desalination 144:133-136. cited by other | Derwent Abstract Accession No. 86-281075/43, JP 61-204080A, Tokuyama Soda KK, Sep. 10, 1986. cited by other | Derwent Abstract Accession No. 92-288534/35, JP 04-197435, Sumitomo Chem. Co Ltd, Jul. 17. 1992. cited by other | Drikas et al. (Non dated) &quot;Operating the Miex Process With Microfiltration of Coagulation.&quot; cited by other | Drikas et al. (2002) &quot;Removal of Natural Organic Matter--A Fresh Approach,&quot; Water Sci. Technol. 2(1):71-79. cited by other | Eldridge, R.J. (1995) &quot;Moving-Bed Ion Exchange with Magnetic Resins,&quot; Rev. Chem. Eng. 11(3):185-228. cited by other | Feed Materials Production Center (Non dated) &quot;Potential Exposure Pathways,&quot; http://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/HAC/PHA/fer/fer.sub.--p2d.html. cited by other | Fu et al. (1989) &quot;Mechanistic Interactions of Aquatic Organic Substances with Anion-Exchange Resins,&quot; Aquatic Humic Resources, Am. Chem. Soc. :797-811. cited by other | Galjaard et al. (2005) &quot;Influence of NOM and Membrane Surface Charge on UF-Membrane Fouling,&quot; http://www.iwaponline.com/wio/2005/04/wio200504001.htm. cited by other | Hach Webpage (Downloaded Jan. 5, 2006) Browse by Parameter, Test for: copper, http://www.hach.com. cited by other | Hach webpage (Downloaded Jan. 5, 2006) DR/4000 Procedure, Methods8506 and Method 8026, http://www.hach.com. cited by other | Harries et al. (1984) &quot;Anion Exchange in High Flow Rate Mixed Beds,&quot; Effluent Water Treatment J. 24:131-139. cited by other | Hongve, D. (1989) &quot;Anion Exchange for Removal of Humus from Drinking Water. Calcium Improves the Efficiency of the Process,&quot; Water Res. 23(11):1451-1454. cited by other | Kaiya et al. (2000) &quot;Analysis of Organic Matter Causing Membrane Fouling in Drinking Water Treatment,&quot; Water Sci. Technol. 41(10-11):59-67. cited by other | Kavitskaya et al. (2003) &quot;Adsorption of Anionic Surface Active Substances(SAS) on Charged Membranes,&quot; Desalination 158:225-230. cited by other | Kim et al. (Dec. 1991) &quot;Using Anion Exchange Resins to Remove THM Precursors,&quot; Research and Technology J. AWWA 83:61-68. cited by other | Kim et al. (2003) &quot;Evaluation of UF Membranes for Effective Effluent Organic Matter (EfOM) Removal with Hydrophilic Polymer Additives,&quot; AWWA Membrane Technology Conference. cited by other | Kunin et al. (1980) &quot;Removal of Humic Material from Drinking Water by Anion Exchange Resins,&quot; Activated Carbon Absorption of Organics from the Aqueous Phase, vol. 2, Ann Arbor Science, Ann Arbor, pp. 425-441. cited by other | Lee et al. (2001) &quot;Cleaning Strategies for Flux Recovery of An Ultra Filtration Membrane Fouled by Natural Organic Matter,&quot; Water. Resources 35(14):3301-3308. cited by other | Miex DOC US Technical Brochure, Downloaded Jan. 5, 2006, http://www.miexresin.com. cited by other | Morran et al. (non dated) &quot;Miex and Microfiltration--A Winning Alliance.&quot; cited by other | Morran et al. (1996) &quot;A New Technique for the Removal of Natural Organic Matter,&quot; AWWA Watertec Convention, Sydney. cited by other | Morran et al. (Mar. 1997) &quot;A Simple Method to Reduce Disinfection By-Product Formation,&quot; 17th Federal Convention, Australian Water and Wastewater Convention, Proceedings 16-21, Melbourne Australia, pp. 373-379. cited by other | Mysels, K.J. (1959) Introduction to Colloid Chemistry, Interscience Publishers, New York, pp. 345. cited by other | Naumczyk et al. (1989) &quot;Organics Isolation from Fresh Drinking Waters by Macroporous Anion-Exchange Resins,&quot; Water Res. 23(12):1593-1597. cited by other | Nguyen et al. (Mar. 1997) &quot;DOC Removal by Miex Process, Scaling-up and Other Development Issues,&quot; 17th Federal Convention, Australian Wastewater Association, Proceedings 16-21, Melbourne Australia, pp. 373-379. cited by other | Odegaard et al. (1989) &quot;Removal of Humic Substances by Ion Exchange,&quot; Aquatic Humic Resources, Am. Chem. Soc. :813-834. cited by other | Slunjski et al. (Apr. 1999) &quot;Miex DOC Process--A New Ion Exchange Process,&quot; Australian Water Quality Centre, 18th Federal Convention, Australian Water and Wastewater Association, Proceedings 11-14, Adelaide Australia. cited by other | Stone et al. (1993) &quot;Charged Micropourous Membranes,&quot; Microelectronics Applications Notes. cited by other | Thurman et al. (1989) &quot;Separation of Humic Substances and Anionic Surfactants from Ground Water by Selective Absorption,&quot; Aquatic Humic Substances: Influence on Fate and Transformation of Pollutants, American Chemical Society :107-114. cited by other | van Breemen et al. (1979) &quot;The Fate of Fluvic Acids During Water Treatment,&quot; Wat. Res. 13:771-779. cited by other | Wlimelech et al. (1996) Water treatment Technology Program Report No. 10, December, U.S. Department of the Interior, Bureau of Reclamation. cited by other | Xenopoulos et al. (2003) Abstract from the Meeting of the North American Membrane Society, Biomedical Applications/Bioseparations section of May 19, 2003, http://www.che.utoledo.edu/nams/2003/viewpaper.cfm?ID=426, accessed May 28, 2004. cited by other.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		56
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US1190863 | US2642514 | US2697724 | US3560378 | US3808305 | US3996131 | US4028237 | US4049546 | US4123396 | US4154675 | US4207397 | US4269760 | US4279756 | US4289617 | US4303531 | US4312956 | US4314905 | US4329225 | US4447475 | US4473474 | US4537683 | US4632745 | US4648976 | US4670154 | US4673504 | US4693832 | US4702840 | US4724082 | US4734200 | US4737921 | US4804465 | US4806244 | US4808316 | US4828715 | US4839057 | US4935450 | US4952386 | US4956061 | US5043072 | US5120688 | US5128041 | US5143583 | US5149437 | US5152896 | US5182023 | US5215632 | US5236595 | US5248424 | US5254257 | US5320756 | US5364534 | US5403495 | US5449522 | US5464530 | US5494582 | US5547585 | US5595666 | US5639377 | US5707514 | US5728302 | US5772891 | US5855790 | US5876685 | US5900146 | US5932099 | US6020210 | US6027649 | US6045694 | US6110375 | US6120688 | US6143717 | US6171487 | US6171489 | US6197193 | US6200471 | US6203705 | US6267892 | US6338803 | US6355221 | US6372143 | US6375848 | US6416668 | US6436297 | US6461514 | US6464881 | US6491827 | US6517723 | US6565748 | US6613232 | US6669849 | US6776913 | US6777454 | US6783681 | US6824685 | US6864397 | US6926832 | US6954738 | US6982037 | US6998054 | US7025884 | US20020106659 | US20040050785 | US20040094485 | US20040140266 | US20050124707 | US20050224413 | US20050274674 | US20060011550 | AU197952709 | AU6053080 | AU704376 | AU705434 | AU744706 | AU749656 | DE3938245 | EP0117096 | EP0522856 | EP0540485 | EP0605826 | EP0779899 | EP0781255 | EP1303566 | GB1559809 | GB2273701 | JP1984049851 | JP1985132609 | JP1987141071 | JP1994102709 | JP1997047761 | JP1999309354 | WO1993021114 | WO1994000237 | WO1996007615 | WO1996007675 | WO1998051622 | WO1999047456 | WO2002044091 | WO2003057739 | WO2003082748 | WO2004087586
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		140
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		AU
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		2003901583
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2003-04-04
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		ORICA AUSTRALIA PTY LTD
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		ORICA AUSTRALIA PTY LTD
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Melbourne, AU
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Melbourne, AU
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		SENGUPTA, ARUP, K. | LI, PING | MURRAY, BRENDAN, J. | HARRISON, STUART, D. | VERO, GREGORY, M.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		SENGUPTA, ARUP, K.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		5
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Bethlehem, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Bethlehem, PA | Bethlehem, PA | Kesington, AU | Box, Hill, North, AU | Camberwell, AU
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		GREENLEE, WINNER &amp; SULLIVAN, P.C.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BARRY, CHESTER T
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

