<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7641055
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11272429
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Polysulfone and poly(N-vinyl lactam) polymer alloy and fiber and filter materials made of the alloy
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A polymer alloy has been developed comprising a polysulfone and a vinyl lactam polymer. The resulting alloy has excellent thermal characteristics and even in the presence of substantial quantities in vinyl lactam polymers, has solvent resistance to both organic and aqueous solvent materials. The materials, when dissolved in solvents, can be spun from a variety of solvents into a variety of useful fiber materials. The resulting fine fiber, microfiber and nanofiber materials have excellent thermal and chemical resistance for a variety of fiber applications. The polymer alloys of the invention can be spun into nanofiber mats that can act as a filtration media and can also be combined into conventional substrate materials for fabrication into filter structures.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2005-11-10
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2005
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2005-11
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-01-05
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-01
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01D71/28 | B01D61/00 | B01D71/68 | B01D46/54
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01D71/28
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01D71
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		95/273 | 210/500.41 | 210/500.42
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		95/273
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		95
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US20100018934A1 | US20070102372A1 | US7641055
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Woo, T. et al., &quot;Poly(amic ester-co-imides) with Different Ratios of Amic Ester and Imide Moieties: Thermally Stable Precursors for Copolyimides,&quot; Bull. Korean Chem. Soc., vol. 20, No. 2, pp. 1-3 (1999). cited by other . | Kim, S. et al., &quot;Effect of Ionic Salts on the Processing of Poly(2-acrylamido-2-methyl-1-propane sulfonic acid) Nanofibers,&quot; Journal of Applied Polymer Science, vol. 96, pp. 1388-1393 (2005). cited by other . | Li, X. et al., &quot;Non-porous ultra-high specific surface ultrafine fibers,&quot; Chinese Science Bulletin, vol. 49, No. 22, pp. 2368-2371 (Nov. 2004). cited by other . | Sen, D. et al., &quot;Small-Angle X-Ray Scattering Study of Porous Polysulfone and Poly(Vinyl Pyrrolidone)/Polysulfone Blend Membranes,&quot; J. Macromol. Sci.-Phys., vol. B39, No. 2, pp. 235-243 (2000). cited by other . | Deimede, V. et al., &quot;Miscibility Behavior of Polybenzimidazole/Sulfonated Polysulfone Blends for Use in Fuel Cell Applications,&quot; Macromolecules, vol. 33, No. 20, pp. 7609-7617 (2000). cited by other . | Haubler, L. et al., &quot;The influence of multiblock copolymers containing polysulfone and poly(tetramethylene oxide) segments on the phase behavior in polymer blends,&quot; Thermochimica Acta, vol. 339, pp. 87-93 (1999). cited by other . | Hayashi, M. et al., &quot;The influence of wettability on the morphology of blends of polysulfones and polyamides,&quot; Polymer, vol. 39, No. 2, pp. 299-308 (1998). cited by other . | Lee, S. et al., &quot;Virus-Based Fabrication of Micro- and Nanofibers Using Electrospinning,&quot; Nano Letters, vol. 4, No. 3, pp. 387-390 (Mar. 2004). cited by other . | Mit-uppatham, C. et al., &quot;Ultrafine Electrospun Polyamide-6 Fibers: Effect of Solution Conditions on Morphology and Average Fiber Diameter,&quot; Macromolecular Chemistry and Physics, vol. 205, pp. 2327-2338 (2004). cited by other . | Yang, Q. et al., &quot;Influence of Solvents on the Formation of Ultrathin Uniform Poly(vinyl pyrrolidone) Nanofibers with Electrospinning,&quot; Journal of Polymer Science: Part B: Polymer Physics, vol. 42, pp. 3721-3726 (2004). cited by other . | Li, D. et al., &quot;Nanofibers of Conjugated Polymers Prepared by Electrospinning with a Two-Capillary Spinneret,&quot; Advanced Materials, vol. 16, No. 22, pp. 2062-2066 (Nov. 18, 2004). cited by other . | Filip, D. et al., &quot;Thermogravimetric analysis of polyurethane-polysulfone blends,&quot; Polymer International, vol. 51, pp. 699-706 (2002). cited by other . | &quot;PVP Polyvinylpyrrolidone Polymers,&quot; International Specialty Products, pp. 1-13 (Date Unknown). cited by other . | Yuan, X. et al., &quot;Morphology of ultrafine polysulfone fibers prepared by electrospinning,&quot; Polymer International, vol. 53, No. 11, pp. 1704-1710 (Nov. 2004). cited by other. | Johnson, J., &quot;Hydrocarbon Oxidation in a Diesel Catalytic Converter,&quot; Thesis Submitted to the Faculty of the Graduate School of the University of Minnesota, pp. i-xii and 1-60 (Oct. 13, 1993). cited by other . | Choi, J. et al., &quot;Effect of organosoluble salts on the nanofibrous structure of electrospun poly(3-hydroxybutyrateco-3-hydroxyvalerate),&quot; International Journal of Biological Macromolecules, vol. 34, pp. 249-256 (2004). cited by other . | Louis, C. et al., &quot;Morphological, thermal and mechanical properties of rubber and polysulfone blends,&quot; Polymer, vol. 42, pp. 7107-7115 (2001). cited by other . | Yoo, J. et al., &quot;Novel ultrafiltration membranes prepared from the new miscible blends of polysulfone with poly(1-vinylpyrrolidone-co-styrene) copolymers,&quot; Journal of Membrane Science, vol. 216, pp. 95-106 (2003). cited by other . | Oyanguren, P. et al., &quot;Development of bicontinuous morphologies in polysulfone-epoxy blends,&quot; Polymer, vol. 40, pp. 5249-5255 (1999). cited by other . | Bognitzki, M. et al., &quot;Preparation of Fibers with Nanoscaled Morphologies: Electrospinning of Polymer Blends,&quot; Polymer Engineering and Science, vol. 41, No. 6, pp. 982-989 (Jun. 2001). cited by other . | Hwang, J. et al., &quot;Effects of Molecular Weight of Polysulfone on Phase Separation Behavior for Cyanate Ester/Polysulfone Blends,&quot; Journal of Applied Polymer Science, vol. 77, pp. 921-927 (2000). cited by other . | &quot;Standard Test Method for Surface Wettability and Absorbency of Sheeted Materials Using an Automated Contact Angle Tester,&quot; ASTM International Designation: D 5725--99 (Reapproved 2003), pp. 1-7 (2003). cited by other . | &quot;PVP (Polyvinylpyrrolidone) Property Chart,&quot; International Specialty Products, 2 pages (Oct. 21, 2003). cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		23
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5104537 | US4919865 | US6495292 | US5853884 | US5914154 | US4839203 | US4942091 | US4684699 | US5683916 | US5690873 | US6740142 | US5954849 | US3912695 | US6303069 | US6170671 | US5152811 | US5364456 | US5131928 | US4970034 | US3898204 | US6132839 | US5399431 | US6395046 | US4822382 | US5853442 | US6130292 | US6673136 | US5534335 | US5230956 | US6328167 | US6746517 | US6759474 | US6837996 | US5672399 | US4720292 | US4941893 | US6743273 | US5979669 | US3895091 | US5811205 | US4772391 | US5082476 | US5389433 | US5238474 | US3655822 | US5480552 | US6800117 | US5480554 | US6217540 | US5820646 | US6616971 | US5613992 | US5641450 | US6783711 | US6716274 | US5527467 | US6488865 | US4650506 | US5789492 | USD425189 | US5834839
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		61
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		27242905
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2005-11-10
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		DONALDSON COMPANY, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		DONALDSON COMPANY, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Minneapolis, MN
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Minneapolis, MN
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		FERRER, ISMAEL | CARDINAL, RICHARD, S. | KALAYCI, VELI
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		FERRER, ISMAEL
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Minneapolis, MN
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Minneapolis, MN | Minneapolis, MN | Burnsville, MN
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		PAULY, DEVRIES, SMITH &amp; DEFFNER, L.L.C.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		MENON, KRISHNAN S
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

