<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7651622
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12244204
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Process and compositions for the disinfection of waters
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A process for killing microorganisms and controlling biofouling in high chlorine demand waters comprises mixing two components, one of which is an oxidant and the other an ammonium salt, and adding the mixture immediately to the aqueous system to be treated.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2008-10-02
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2008-10
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-01-26
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-01
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F1/76 | C02F1/50
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F1/76
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		162/161 | 210/756 | 210/764
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		162/161
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		162
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US6478973 | US7651622 | US20090107923A1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		R.Wolfe et al. &quot;Inorganic Chloramines as Drinking Water Disinfectants: A Review&quot; --Research and Technology Journal, May 1984 pp. 74-88. cited by other . | J. Johnson et al. &quot;Bromine and Bromamine Disinfection Chemistry&quot; --Journal of the Sanitary Engineering Division, Oct. 1971 pp. 617-629. cited by other . | J. Race &quot;Chloramine&quot; --Chlorination of Water Chapter IX pp. 115-131. cited by other . | W. Olszewski &quot;The Monochloramine Process For Disinfecting Swimming Pool Water&quot; Chemiker Zeitung No. 14, Feb. 18, 1928, 3 pgs. cited by other . | S. Rideal &quot;The Influence of Ammonia and Organic Nitrogenous Compounds on Chlorine Disinfection&quot; --Journal of The Royal Sanitary Institute vol. XXXI, No. 2 Issued Mar. 1910 pp. 33-45. cited by other . | Twenty-ninth Annual Report 1934--pp. 60-73. cited by other . | K. Holwerda &quot;On the Control and The Degree of Reliability of the Chlorination-Process of Drinking-Water, In Connection With the Chloramin-Procedure and the Chlorination of Ammoniacal Water&quot; --Laboratory of Purification of Water at Manggarai pp. 252-297. cited by other . | G. Houghton &quot;Experiments as to the Effect of pH and Organic Content in the Ammonia-Chlorine Treatment of Water&quot; --Inst. of Water Engineers 4:5 434 (1950) pp. 434-444. cited by other . | E. Mackenzie Report on a Series of Tests Performed to Ascertain the Efficiency of the Ammonia Chlorine Treatment of Water Applied by a Standardized Method. cited by other . | J. Mcamis &quot;Prevention of Phenol Taste With Ammonia&quot; pp. 341-350. cited by other . | W. Olszewski &quot;The New Ammonia/Chlorine Gas Disinfecting Process&quot; --Chemiker Zeitung No. 28 Apr. 9, 1927, 3 pgs. cited by other . | S. Block, G. Dychidala &quot;Chlorine and Chlorine Compounds&quot; --Disinfection, Sterilization, and Preservation Third Edition pp. 157-173, 178-182. cited by other. | R Trautschold &quot;Its Control in Paper Making by Chlorine and Ammonia&quot; --hemical Industries Jul. '36 pp. 27-29. cited by other . | G. Houghton &quot;Observations on the Chlorination of Water Containing Free Ammonia and Naturally Occuring Bromide&quot; --The Bromide Content of Underground Waters Partt II. Oct. 1946 pp. 324-328. cited by other . | R. Hoather &quot;The Bactericidal Effect of Ammonia-Chlorine Treatment, Residual Chloramine and Free Residual Chlorine&quot; pp. 507-514. cited by other . | M. Schirtzinger &quot;Chlorine Compounds for Microbiological Control&quot; --Paper Mill News Jul. 29, 1963 pp. 18-25. cited by other . | H. Phillips &quot;White Water Utilization&quot; --The Paper Mill, Jan. 28, 1933, 4 pgs. cited by other . | C. Haas &quot;Water Quality Treatment--Chapter 14 Disinfection&quot; --pp. 877-894. cited by other . | R. Chapin &quot;Dichloro-Amine&quot; --W.A&gt; Noyes This Journal, 42, 2173 vol. 51 Jul. 1929 pp. 2112-2117. cited by other . | J. Race &quot;Chlorination of Water Chapter I Histrorical&quot; --Chlorination of Water pp. 1-29. cited by other . | R. Martin et al. &quot;Microbiological Control in Pulp and Paper Manufacture&quot; --Techincal Association Papers, Series 23 Jun. 1940 No. 1 pp. 239-245. cited by other . | H. Harold &quot;Chloamine Treatment Of Water in the Field&quot; --Royal Army Medical Corps pp. 115-119. cited by other . | L. Enslow &quot;Ammonia-Chlorine Reactions and Chloramine Production&quot; --Contract Record and Engineering Review, Mar. 11, 1931 pp. 291-295. cited by other . | &quot;Chloramine at Denver Solves Aftergrowth Problem&quot; --Engineering News-Record, vol. 79, No. 5 p. 210. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		24
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US7285224 | US5683654 | US2112476 | US2443429 | US3222276 | US4566986 | US7052614 | US1413153 | US4872999 | US4431729 | US7067063 | US4643835 | US7449120 | US3328294 | US3799396 | US5976386 | US6478973 | US1378644 | US1581115 | US4767564 | US6132628 | US3975271 | JP1979161592 | JP1981013512 | GB1600289 | WO1989012604 | GB1421417 | GB253623 | EP0403465
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		29
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		IL
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		98352
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		1991-06-03
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		BROMINE COMPOUNDS LIMITED
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		BROMINE COMPOUNDS LIMITED
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Beer-Sheva, IL
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Beer-Sheva, IL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		BARAK, AYALA
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		BARAK, AYALA
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Jerusalem, IL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Jerusalem, IL
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		DARBY &amp; DARBY P.C.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		HRUSKOCI, PETER A
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

