<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7601262
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11023281
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B1
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Sub-micron filter
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Aluminum hydroxide fibers approximately 2 nanometers in diameter and with surface areas ranging from 200 to 650 m.sup.2/g have been found to be highly electropositive. When dispersed in water they are able to attach to and retain electronegative particles. When combined into a composite filter with other fibers or particles they can filter bacteria and nano size particulates such as viruses and colloidal particles at high flux through the filter. Such filters can be used for purification and sterilization of water, biological, medical and pharmaceutical fluids, and as a collector/concentrator for detection and assay of microbes and viruses. The alumina fibers are also capable of filtering sub-micron inorganic and metallic particles to produce ultra pure water. The fibers are suitable as a substrate for growth of cells. Macromolecules such as proteins may be separated from each other based on their electronegative charges.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2004-12-27
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2004
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2004-12
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-10-13
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-10
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01D39/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01D39/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01D39
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/503 | 210/505 | 502/407 | 55/527 | 502/415 | 96/108 | 210/502.1
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/503
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US7601262
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Meltzer, T.H. et al., (1998), Filtration in the biopharmaceutical industry, Marcel Dekker, New York, NY, pp. 262-265. cited by other . | Farrah, S.R. et al., (1991), Adsorption of viruses from water by using cellulose filters modified by in-situ precipitation of ferric and aluminum hydroxides, Applied Environmental Microbiology, 1502-1504 (abstract). cited by other . | Raynor, P.C. et al., The Long-Term Performance of Electrically Charged Filters in a Ventilation System, J. of Occ. and Envir. Hygiene, vol. 1(7): 463-471, Jul. 2004. cited by other . | Tien, Chi, Adsorption Calculations and Modeling, 1994 Butterworth-Heinemann (TOC provided). cited by other . | Yavorovsky, N.A. et al., (2000), Ultra-fine powder by wire explosion method, Acta Materialia 44(8/9): 2247-2251. cited by other . | Tepper, F., Nanosize Powders Produced by Electro-Explosion of Wire and Their Potential Applications, Argonide Corporation, Sanford, FL, Abstract. cited by other . | Blackford, D.B. et al., Alteration in the Performance of Electrostatic Filters Caused by Exposure to Aerosols, 4th World Filtration Congres, 7.27-7.33. cited by other . | Sinha, D., (1990), Pretreatment process considerations for the semiconductor industry, Ultrapure Water 7(6): 21-30. cited by other . | Dicosmo, et al., (1994), Cell immobilization by adsorption to glass fibre mats, Immobilized Biosystems, Ed. by Veliky, I.A. and McLean, R.J.C., Blackie Academic &amp; Professional. cited by other . | Martin, S.M. et al., Electrostatic Respirator Filter Media: Filter Efficiency and Most Penetrating Particle Size Effects, Appl. Occ. &amp; Enviro. Hygiene vol. 15(8):609-17, 2000. cited by other . | Brown, R.C. et al., Effect of Industrial Aerosols on the Performance of Electrically Charged Filter Material, Hyg. vol. 32(3): 271-94, 1988. cited by other . | Johnson, P.R., Whadaya Mean?, Filtration News VOI 20(5): 10-11, 2002. cited by other . | Robinson et al., Depyrogenation by Microporous Membrane Filters, Tech Rpt No. 7, Depyrogenation, Parenteral Drug Assn, Phila, PA, 1985, TOC. cited by other. | Wilkie, A.E. et al., Multi-Component Fiber Technology for Medical and Other Filtration Applications, 1st Inter. Conf. on Med. Filtration, DE Oct. 9, 2002. cited by other . | Lukasik, J. et al., Removal of Microorganisms from Water by Columns Containing Sand Coated with Ferric and Aluminum Hydroxides, Wat Res 33(3): 769-77, 1999, Abstract. cited by other . | Lukasik, J. et al., Influence of Salts on Virus Adsorption to Microporous Filters, Appl Environ Micro, 66: 2914-20. cited by other . | Gitzen, W.H., Alumina as a Ceramic Material, American Ceramic Soc., Special Pub. 4, 1970, 13-14, TOC. cited by other . | Willkommen, H., (Oct. 1-Oct. 3, 2001), Virus validation for filtration procedures, PDA/FDA Viral Clearance Forum, Bethesda, MD. cited by other . | Farrah, S.R. et al., Concentration of Viruses from Water by Using Cellulose Filters Modifies by In-situ Precipitation of Ferric and Aluminum Hydroxides, Appl Envir Micro, 1985. cited by other . | Hou, K. et al., Capture of Latex Beads, Bacteria, Endotoxin and Viruses by Charge-Modified Filters, Appl Envir Micro, Nov. 1980, 892-96. cited by other . | Yavorosvsky, N.A., (1996), Izvestiia VUZ, Fizika 4:114-35. cited by other . | Moyer, E.S. et al., Electrostatic N-95 Respirator Filter Media Efficiency Degradation Resulting from Intermittent NaCl Aerosol Expos., Appl. Occ. &amp; Envir. Hyg. 15(8): 600-8. cited by other . | Sobsey, M.D. et al., Concentration of Poliovisur from Tap Water Using Positively Charged Microporous Filters, Appl Enviro Micro, 1979: 588-595. cited by other . | Khalil, K., Synthesis of Short Fibrous Boehmite Suitable for Thermally Stabilized Transition Aluminas Formation, Journal of Catalysis, 1198 (178):198-206, Abstract. cited by other . | Mandaro, R., (1987), Charge modified depth filters: cationic-charge modified nylon membranes, Filtration in the Pharmaceutical Industry, T.H. Meltzer Ed., Marcel Dekker, Inc., New York, NY. cited by other . | Henderson, D.W. et al., An Apparatus for the Study of Airborne Infection, J. Hyg. Camb. vol. 50, p. 53-67, 1952. cited by other . | Ahuja, S., Handbook of Bioseparations, Academic Press, 2000, TOC. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		27
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6550622 | US5189092 | US5109311 | US6565749 | US2783894 | US4282261 | US4664683 | US6830822 | US6797167 | US4824451 | US5855788 | US4536440 | US5104546 | US20060123991 | US3793061 | US3025233 | US6716218 | US6077588 | US6838005 | US5126044 | US6197515 | US20060163174 | US2917426 | US5366636 | US5744236 | US4178438 | US5547607 | US6953604 | US2915475 | US6290848 | US4395332 | US4761323 | US4673504 | US6913154 | US6464757 | US5147722 | US3117944 | US2773601 | US3352424 | US5759394 | US4555347 | US6630016 | US3234075 | US4604208 | US6872311 | US4511473 | US4149549 | US5865968 | US4807619 | US5219577 | US6057488 | US6235388 | US4059119 | US5350443 | US20060225574 | US4523995 | US4743418 | US3408315 | US3947562 | US6524477 | US5562824 | US4366068 | US4305782 | US6849109 | US4037607 | US6321915 | US5798220 | US4617128 | US6955708 | US4309247 | US6872431 | US4677019 | US6514413 | US6355330 | US5486292 | US4708803 | US4510193 | US4433697 | US4007113 | US4288462 | US4711793 | US4007114 | US4242226 | US4473474 | US20060169144 | US4331631 | US3031418 | US5307796 | US3031417 | US4321288 | US3242073 | US6010606 | US4455187 | US20050029198 | US4606823 | US6402819 | US20030127393 | US5225078 | US5804295 | US5085784 | US4230573 | US6716525 | US6959820 | RU2168357 | GB2045828 | EP0958851 | WO1998002231 | DE2510467 | SU1066942 | EP0099586 | EP1219335 | DE2410215 | WO1999047456 | RU2063383
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		114
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		2328104 | 17770902 | 30018401
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2004-12-27 | 2002-06-21 | 2001-06-22
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		ARGONIDE CORPORATION
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		ARGONIDE CORPORATION
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Sanford, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Sanford, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		TEPPER, FREDERICK | KALEDIN, LEONID
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		TEPPER, FREDERICK
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Sanford, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Sanford, FL | Port, Orange, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		PASSERIN, ESQ., ALICIA M. COHEN &amp; GRIGSBY, P.C.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		DRODGE, JOSEPH W
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

