<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7604742
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11125748
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Soil conditioning products from organic waste
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A process for conversion of organic wastes into biofertilizers such as soil conditioning agents of fertilizer grade, culture grade and soil grade is provided. Also provided is a process for conversion of organic wastes into material for converting waste water into reusable water. The invention provides methods for conversion of organic solid wastes to biofertilizers and reusable water in the presence of a geophagus earthworm Pheretima elongata culure to produce a variety of valuable soil conditioning products and reusable water.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2005-05-09
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2005
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2005-05
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-10-20
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-10
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C05F1/00 | C02F3/32 | C05F5/00 | C05F7/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C05F1/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C05
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C05F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C05F1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		71/21 | 71/14 | 210/610 | 210/602 | 210/620 | 119/6.7 | 71/11
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		71/21
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		71
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		AU2003249573A1 | AU2003249573A8 | WO2004091160A3 | US20040065610A1 | WO2003091160A2 | US7604742 | US6890438 | US20050210941A1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		8
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		12
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		International Search Report of PCT/IN03/00168. cited by examiner . | Hach Co. (1997). Hach Water Analysis Handbook, 3rd edition. Loveland, Colorada, USA. pp. vii-xviii. (Table of Contents). cited by other . | Sihorwala, T. A. et al. (1997): &quot;Effect Of Different Species Of Earthworm And Their Combination on Carbon-Nitrogen Ratio of Black Cotton Soil And Characterization of Vermicasting Powders Produced From Solid Waste Treatment By Earthworm Biotechnology,&quot; Proceedings of the International Conference On Solid Waste Technology and Management, 13th(vol. 2), Paper 7C/1, 1-9 , Database CA Online Chemical Abstracts Service, Columbus, Ohio, US, retrieved from STN Database accession No. 128:88252 CA XP002262033). cited by other . | Shanthi, N. R. et al. (Oct. 1993). &quot;Vermicomposting of Vegetable Waste&quot; Compost Science and Utilization Fall 1993 (Oct. 1993), 1(4): 27-30, (Database COMPENDEX Online Engineering Information, Inc., New York, NY, US, Database accession No. EIP94021204266 XP002262031 &amp; Compost. Sci. Util.). cited by other . | Stumm, W. et al. eds. (1981). Aquatic Chemistry--An Introduction Emphasizing Equilibria in Natural Waters. 2.sup.nd edition. Wiley Interscience: New York., pp. V-XIV. (Table of Contents). cited by other . | Asthana G. P. (1977). &quot;On The Nitrogenous Components in The Earthworm Pheretima-Elongata,&quot; Indian Journal of Zoology, 5(2):12-16 (ISSN: 0302-7562, Database BIOSIS Online Biosciences Information Service, Philadelphia, PA, US, Database accession No. PREV197866027623 XP002262032). cited by other . | Bhawalkar, Converting Wastes Into Resources: Vermiculture Biotechnology, ILEIA Newsletter, 10.3, Oct. 1994. cited by examiner . | Sherman-Huntoon, Snapshots of Selected Large-Scale Vermicomposting Operations, North Carolina Cooperative Extension Service, Apr. 1997. cited by examiner . | Wong, S. H. et al. (1991).&quot;Vermicomposting in the Management of Pig-Waste in Hong Kong,&quot; World Journal of Microbiology and Biotechnology, 7(6):593-595, (ISSN: 0959-3993, Database BIOSIS Online Biosciences Information Service, Philadelphia, PA, US, Database accession No. PREV199293082297 XP002262034). cited by other . | Menon, &quot;Worms Recruited to clear Bombay's Rubbish&quot;, New Scientist, Dec. 1994. cited by examiner . | International Search Report of PCT/IN03/00168, mailed Dec. 18, 2003. cited by examiner . | Merck Co. (1997). Manual for Photometer SQ 118. Located at &lt;http://www.merck.de/servlet/PB/show/1282710/manual.sub.--sq.sub.--118- .sub.--e.sub.--1.pdf&gt; visited on Apr. 27, 2004. pp. 1-28. cited by other . | Krishnamoorthy R. V. et al. (1986). &quot;Biological Activity of Earthworm Casts an Assessment of Plant Growth Promoter Levels in the Casts,&quot; Proceedings of The Indian Academy of Sciences Animal Sciences, 95(3)341-352, (Database BIOSIS Online Biosciences Information Service, Philadelphia, PA, US, Database accession No. PREV198783019292 XP002262030, ISSN: 0253-4118). cited by other . | American Public Health Association et al. eds. (1992). APHA--Standard Methods for the Examination of Water and Wastewater. 18th edition. APHA: Washington, D.C., pp. iii-xxxi. (Table of Contents). cited by other . | Earthworms--Benefits, Nature's Way Resources, Sep. 1999. cited by other . | Collection and Reprocessing of Organic Food Waste: A Feasibility Study, Nolan ITU Pty Ltd, May 1997. cited by other . | Lee, K.E. ed. (1985). Earthworms: Their Ecology and Relationship with Soils and Land Use. Academic Press: New York. pp. v-viii. (Table of Contents). cited by other . | Arceivala, S.J. (1998). Wastewater Treatment for Pollution Control. 2nd edition. McGraw-Hill Publising:New Delhi. pp. xi-xv. (Table of Contents). cited by other . | International Search Report mailed on Dec. 18, 2003, for PCT Patent Application No. PCT/IN2003/000168, filed on Apr. 24, 2003, published as WO 2003/091160, on Nov. 6, 2003, 6 pages total. cited by other.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		19
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US7947105 | US8105413 | US8202342 | US8192519 | US7789931 | US7947104
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		6
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US4262633 | US5863433 | US2680069 | US3961603 | US4552726 | US5432088 | US4334498 | US4108609 | US5389257 | US6277274 | USR34545 | US3635816 | US3944408 | US5603744 | US4108625 | US5820759 | US6890438 | US2779670 | US4161158 | US6264838 | AU4513297
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		21
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		IN | IN
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		383/MUM/2002 | 384/MUM/2002
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2002-04-26 | 2002-04-26
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		INDIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY BOMBAY
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		INDIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY BOMBAY
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Mumbai, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Mumbai, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		SHANKAR, HARIHARAN, S. | PATTANAIK, BIPLAB, R. | BHAWALKAR, UDAY, S.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		SHANKAR, HARIHARAN, S.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Mumbai, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Mumbai, IN | Cuttack, IN | Pune, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		MORRISON &amp; FOERSTER LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		PRINCE, FRED
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		3
	</str>
</doc>

