<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7678238
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US10482960
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Method and apparatus for underwater decomposition of organic content of electrically conductive aqueous waste solutions
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The object of the present invention is a method and an apparatus for underwater decomposition of organic content of aqueous waste solutions, involving the measurement and, if necessary, adjustment of the pH and electric conductivity of the solution, maintaining optimum pH and/or electric conductivity during the process, and further involving the partial or total decomposition of organic materials contained by the solution. The apparatus comprises a feed tank, at least one decomposition loop, and a storage tank. The method according to the invention is characterized by submerging electrodes in the solution, producing and maintaining an electric arc between the electrodes and the electrically conductive the solution, where the arc is produced by an electric current of at least 0.5 A/cm.sup.2 current density at a voltage of at least 70 V and by a symmetrical alternating current having preferably a frequency of at least 10 Hz; and by decomposing the organic content of the solution into water, carbon dioxide, and nitrogen.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2002-07-16
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2002
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2002-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-03-16
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-03
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F1/46
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F1/46
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		204/275.1 | 204/278 | 204/165 | 204/164
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		204/275.1
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		204
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Guo, Xianhui, et al., &quot;Experimental Research on the Treatment of Nitrobenzene Wastewater With Pulse Discharge Plasma,&quot; Electric Power Environmental Protection, vol. 17, No. 2, Jun. 2001, pp. 37-38. cited by other. | Fang, Xingdong, et al., &quot;Research on Treatment of Waste Water by High Voltage Pulse Discharge,&quot; High Voltage Engineering, vol. 26, No. 1, Feb. 2000, pp. 29-31. cited by other . | Patent Abstracts of Japan and JPO Computer English translation of JP 07068267 dated Mar. 14, 1995. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5630915 | US4582004 | JP1995068267 | WO1997022556 | EP0659691 | WO1999001382
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		6
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		HU
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		0102986
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2001-07-17
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		G.I.C. KFT
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		G.I.C. KFT
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Budapest, HU
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Budapest, HU
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		SCHREMMER, ISTVAN | TILKY, PETER
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		SCHREMMER, ISTVAN
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Budapest, HU
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Budapest, HU | Paks, HU
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		LADAS &amp; PARRY LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		PHASGE, ARUN S
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

