<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7658850
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12194995
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Mixed bacterial culture for atrazine degradation
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The present invention provides a mixed bacterial culture, designated as the culture Atz Mix 1, which degrades atrazine at various temperatures (10.degree. C. to 30.degree. C.) in a wide range of atrazine concentrations (several ppb to ten thousand ppm), without formation of toxic metabolites. Atz Mix 1 is a stable mixed culture and includes catabolic genes trzN, atzB, atzC coding the enzymes for the degradation of atrazine to cyanuric acid, and the gene trzD coding the enzymes for subsequent opening of s-triazine ring. The invention further includes a microbiological method of degrading atrazine and other s-triazine compounds for remediation of atrazine-contaminated soils, even those rich in nitrogen, as well as for accelerating the process of atrazine mineralization in waste waters containing high concentrations of s-triazine compounds.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2008-08-20
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2008-08
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-02-09
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-02
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		435/262.5 | 210/903 | 210/611
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		435/262.5
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		435
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Udikovic, et al., &quot;Enrichment and Characterization of Atrazine Degrading Bacterial Communites&quot;; Food Technol. Biotechnol. 41 (3) 211-217; 2003; 7 pages. cited by other. | Boundy-Mills, Kyria L., et al, &quot;The atzB Gene of Pseudomonas sp. Strain ADP Encodes the Second Enzyme of a Novel Atrazine Degradation Pathway&quot;, Applied and Enviromental Microbiology, pp. 916-923, Mar. 1997. cited by other . | Stucki G et al: &quot;Microbial atrazine mineralisation under carbon limited and denitrifying conditions&quot; Water Research, Elsevier, Amsterdam, NL, vol. 29, No. 1, Jan. 1995 (Jan. 1995), pp. 291-296, XP004035522 ISSN: 0043-1354 abstract. cited by other . | Stipicevic, Sanja, et al, &quot;Comparison of gas and high performace liquid chromatography with selective detection for determination of triazine herbicides and their degradation products extracted ultrasonically from soil&quot; Journal of Separation Science, pp. 1237-1246, 2003. cited by other . | Radosevich, Mark, et al, &quot;Degradation and Mineralization of Atrazine by a Soil Bacterial Isolate&quot; Applied and Enviromental Microbiology, pp. 297-302, Jan. 1995. cited by other . | International Preliminary Report on Patentability, PCT/HR2007/000002, Feb. 29, 2008, 7 pages. cited by other . | International Search Report, PCT/HR2007/000002, Jun. 22, 2007, 2 pages. cited by other . | Behki, Ram M, et al &quot;Degradation of Atrazine, propazine, and Simazine by Rhodococcus Strain B-30&quot; J. Agric Food Chem., pp. 1237-1241, 1994. cited by other . | Garcia-Gonzales, Vicente, et al, &quot;Regulation of the Pseudomonas sp. Strain Adp Cyanuric Acid Degradation Operon&quot; Journal of Bacteriology, pgs. 155-167, Jan. 2005. cited by other . | Strong, Lisa C., et al &quot;Arthrobacter aurescens TC1, Metabolizes Diverse s-Trazine Ring Compounds&quot;, Applied and Enviromental Microbiology, pp. 5973-5980, Dec. 2002. cited by other . | Ralebitso, T. Komang, et al &quot;Microbial aspects of atrazine degradation in natural enviroments&quot; Biodegeneration, pp. 11-19, 2002. cited by other . | Hrsak, D., et al, &quot;Enrichment of linear alkylbenzenesuplhonate (LAS) degrading bacteria in continuous culture&quot; Journal of Applied Bacteriology, pp. 413-422, 1982. cited by other . | Sadowsky, Michael J., et al, &quot;AtzC is a New Member of the Amidohydrolase Protein Superfamily and Is Homologous to Other Atrazine-Metabolizing Enzymes&quot; Journal of Bacteriology, pgs. 152-158, Jan. 1998. cited by other . | Rousseaux, Sandrine, et al, &quot;Isolation and characterisation of new Gram-negative and Gram-positive atrazine degrading bacteria from different French soils&quot; FEMS Microbiology, pp. 211-222, 2001. cited by other . | Sparling, Graham, et al, &quot;Atrazine miseralisation in New Zealand topsoils and subsoils: influence of edaphic factors and numbers of atrazine-degrading microbes&quot;, Australian Journal of Soil Research, pp. 557-570, 1998. cited by other . | de Souza, Mervyn L., &quot;Atrazine Chlorohydrolase from Pseudomonas sp. Straid ADP: Gene Sequence, Enzyme Purification and Protein Characterization&quot; Journal of Bacteriology, pp. 4894-4900, Aug. 1996. cited by other . | Smith D et al: &quot;Cooperative catabolic pathways within an atrazine-degrading enrichment culture isolated from soil&quot; Fems Microbiology Ecology, Elsevier, NL, vol. 53, No. 2, Jul. 1, 2005 (Jul. 1, 2005), pp. 265-273, XP004945377 ISSN: 0168-6496 abstract; figures 3,4 paragraph [02.2]. cited by other . | Bouquard, Corinne, et al, &quot;Dechlorination of Atrazine by Rhizobium sp. Isolate&quot;, Applied and Environnental Microbiology, pp. 862-866, Mar. 1997. cited by other . | Mandelbaum, Ralphi T., et al, &quot;Isolation and Characterization of a Pseudomonas sp. That Mineralizes the s-Triazine Herbicide Atrazine&quot; Applied and Enviromental Microbiology, pp. 1451-1457, Apr. 1995. cited by other . | Behki, Ram M., et al &quot;Degradation of Atrazine by Pseudomonas: N-Dealkylation and Dehalogenation of Atrazine and Its Metabolites&quot; J. Agric. Food Chem, pp. 746-749, 1986. cited by other . | Topp, Edward, et al, &quot;Characterization of an Atrazine-Degrading Pseudaminobacter sp. Isolated from Canadian and French Agricultural Soils&quot; Applied and Enviromental Microbiology, pp. 2773-2782, Jul. 2000. cited by other . | Kontchou, Clotaire Yanze, et al, &quot;Mineralization of the Herbicide Atrazine in Soil Inoculated with a Pseudomonas Strain&quot; J. Agric. Food Chem., pp. 2291-2294, 1995. cited by other . | Martinez, Better, et al, &quot;Complete Nucleotide Sequence and Organization of the Atrazine Catabolic Plasmid pADP-1 from Pseudomonas sp. Strain ADP&quot; Journal of Bacteriology, pp. 5684-5697, Oct. 2001. cited by other . | Gebendinger, N., et al, Inhibition of atrazne degradation by cyanazine and exogenous nitrogen in bacterial isolate M91-3, Appl Microbiol Biotechnol, pp. 375-381, 1999. cited by other . | Written Opinion of the International Searching Authority, PCT/HR2007/000002, Jun. 22, 2007, 6 pages. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		25
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US20030170879 | US5508193 | US5429949 | US20070101461 | US20040208706 | US20060257890
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		6
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		HR
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		P060076A
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2006-02-20
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		RUDJER BOSKOVIC INSTITUTE
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		RUDJER BOSKOVIC INSTITUTE
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Zagreb, HR
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Zagreb, HR
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		HRSAK, DUBRAVKA | HAVRILUK, MAJA
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		HRSAK, DUBRAVKA
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Zagreb, HR
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Zagreb, HR | Sesvete, HR
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		ST. ONGE STEWARD JOHNSTON &amp; REENS LLC
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BARRY, CHESTER T
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

