<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7625351
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US10938693
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		System, method and apparatus for purifying biological fluids such as blood and constituents thereof
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Provided herein is an innovative hemoperfusion system and method including a thermal-fused broad-spectrum biocidal iodinated interactive polymer for the treatment of biological contaminants in body fluids. In one exemplary embodiment, the system and method utilizes a Triosyn.RTM. thermal fused broad-spectrum iodinated interactive polymer, included in a hemoperfusion column, for devitalizing high levels of cell-free microorganisms in whole blood and biological fluids in relation with the characterization of blood cells viability and function post-treatment.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2004-09-10
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2004
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2004-09
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2009-12-01
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2009-12
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		A61M1/00 | B01D33/15 | A61M37/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		A61M1/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		A
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		A61
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		A61M
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		A61M1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		604/5.01 | 210/654 | 604/6.01 | 210/650 | 210/660 | 210/806 | 422/44 | 210/638 | 210/260 | 210/636 | 210/645 | 422/48 | 210/800 | 210/634 | 210/669 | 210/782 | 210/646 | 210/781 | 604/6.03 | 604/5.04 | 604/6.09 | 604/5.02
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		604/5.01
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		604
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		US20090178973A1 | US7625351 | US20050180878A1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Sazama K. 1994. Bacteria in blood for transfusion. A review. Arch Pathol Lad Med, vol. Apr. 118:4, pp. 350-365. cited by other. | Wallas, C.H.; 1979. Sodium and Potassium Changes in Blood Bank Stored Human Erythrocytes. Transfusion, 19(2), pp. 210-215. cited by other . | Bertolini F, Porretti L, Lauri E, Rebulla P, Sirchia G. 1993. Role of lactate in platelet storage lesion. Vox Sanguinis vol. 65 pp. 194-198. cited by other . | Wagner SJ.; Friedman LI.; Dodd RY.. 1994. Transfusion-associated bacterial sepsis. Clin Microbiol Rev, vol. Jul. 7:3, pp. 290-302. cited by other . | Busch MP; Lee T.. 1995. Role of Donor Leukocytes and Leukodepletion in transfusion-Associated Viral Infections. Clinical Benefits of Leukodepleted Blood Products. edited by Joseph Sweeney, M.D. and Andrew Heaton, M.D.,R.G. Landes Company, chapter 8, pp. 99-112. cited by other . | Harmening, Denisi M., 1991. Clot Retraction, Platelet Retention/ Adhesion, Platelet Aggregation, Platelet Factor 3 Availability. Clinical Hematology and Fundamentals of Hemostasis, pp. 588-592. cited by other . | Corash, Laurence, 1999. Inactivation of Viruses, Bacteria, Protozoa, and Leukocytes in Platelets Concentrates: Current Research Perspectives, Transfusion Medicine Reviews, vol. 13:1, pp. 18-30. cited by other . | AuBuchon JP.; Pickard C.; Herschel L.; O'Connor JL.. Documentation of efficient leukocyte removal with a new filter. Transfusion, vol. 38:64S. cited by other . | Snyder E.; Mechanic S.; Baril L.; Davenport R. 1996. Removal of soluble biological response modifiers (compliment and chemokines) by a bedside leukoreduction filter. Transfusion, vol. 36, pp. 707. cited by other . | Weber, David J., Barbee, Susan L., Sobsey, Mark D. and Rutala, William A. 1999. The Effect of Blood on the Antiviral Activity of Sodium Hypochlorite, a Phenolic, and a Quaternary Ammonium Compound. Infection Control and Hospital Epidemiology, vol. 20, pp. 821-827. cited by other . | AuBuchon JP; Dodd RY. 1992. Inactivation of Microbial Contaminants of Blood Components. Clin Lab Med, vol. Dec. 12:4, pp. 787-803. cited by other . | Adams GA, Swenson SD, Rock G. 1986. Survival and recovery of human platelets stored for five days in a non-plasma medium. Blood, vol. 67:3 pp. 672-675. cited by other . | Beutler, E., 1984. Determination of 2,3-Diphosphoglycerate in Erythrocytes. Red Cell Metabolism . A Manual of Biochemical Methods. 3rd ed. Orlando, Grune &amp; Stratton, pp. 127-12. cited by other . | Arthur P. Bode. (1990) Platelet Activation May Explain the Storage Lesion in Platelet Concentrates., Blood Cells (1990) vol. 16: pp. 109-126. cited by other . | Dodd RY. 1998. Transmission of Parasites by Blood Transfusion. Vox Sang, vol. 74, suppl. 2, pp. 161-163. cited by other . | Girotti S., Ferri E., Cascione ML., Orlandini A., Farina L., Nucci S., Di Graci F., Budini R., 1991. Methodological Problems of Direct Bioluminescent ADP assay in Platelets and Erythrocytes. Anal. Biochem., Feb. 1, vol. 192, No. 2, pp. 350-357. cited by other . | AuBuchon JP.; Elfath MD.; Popovskyk MA.; Stromberg RR.; Pickard C.; Herschel L.; Whitley P.; McNeil D.; Arnold N.; O'Connor JL.. 1997. Evaluation of a new prestorage leukoreduction filter for red blood cells. Vox Sang, vol. 72, pp. 101-106. cited by other . | Amy D. Shapiro, M.D., Indiana Hemophilia and Thrombosis Center, Indianapolis, U.S.A. (1999) Platelet Function Disorders. Treatment of Hemophilia Monograph Series, No. 19. World Federation of Hemophilia: pp. 1-11. cited by other . | Kitasato Institute, Tokyo, Japan, sponsored by Yamada Corporation, 1994. Triosyn Air Technology Validation. cited by other . | Bove Jr..1990. Transfusion- transmitted diseases other then AIDS and hepatitis. Yale J Biol Med, vol. Sep.-Oct. 63:5, pp. 347-351. cited by other . | American Association of Blood Banks, America's Blood Centers and the American Red Cross. (Aug. 2000) Circular of Information for the use of human blood and blood components pp. 1-32. cited by other . | New Drug Development Institute, Tokyo, Japan, sponsored by Yamada Corporation, 1996. Triosyn Intake: Oral Irritation GLP Study. cited by other . | Valeri CR, Feingold H, Marchionni LD, 1974. The relation between response to hypotonic stress and 51-Cr recovery in vivo of preserved platelets. Transfusion, vol. 14, pp. 331-337. cited by other . | Van der Meer PF, Pietersz RN, Nelis JT, Hinloopen B, Dekker WJ, Reesink HW, 1999. Six filters for the removal of white cells from red cell concentrates, evaluated at 4 degrees. cited by other . | Sayers MH.; Anderson KC.; Goodnough LT.; Kurtz SR.; Lane TA.; Pisciotto P.; Silberstein LE.. 1992. Reducing the risk for transfusion-transmitted cytomegalovirus infection. Ann Intern Med, vol. Jan. 1, 116:1, pp. 55-62. cited by other . | Sirchia G, rebulla P, sabbioneda L, Garcea F, Greppi N, 1996. Optimal conditions for white cell reduction in red cells by filtration at the patient's bedside. Transfusion, vol. 36, No. 4, pp. 322-327. cited by other . | James G. White ., (1992) Ultrastructural Changes in Stored Platelets., Blood Cells (1992) vol. 18: pp. 461-475. cited by other . | Beaujean F, SegierJM, Le Forestier C, Duedari N. 1992. Leukocyte depletion of red cell concentrates by filtration: influence of blood product temperature. Vox Sang, vol. 62:4, pp. 242-243. cited by other . | Illert WE.; Sanger W.; Weise W.. 1995. Bacterial contamination of single-donor blood components. Transfus Med, vol. Mar. 5:1, pp. 57-61. cited by other . | Sweeney JD, Holme S, Stromberg RR, Heaton WA. 1995. In vitro and in vivo effects of prestorage filtration of apheresis platelets. Transfusion vol. 35:2, pp. 125-130. cited by other . | Dodd RY. 1992. The risk of transfusion-transmitted infection. New England Journal of Medicine, vol. Aug. 6 327:6, pp. 419-421. cited by other . | Rebulla, Paolo and Dzik, Walter H., 1994. Multicenter Evaluation of Methods for Counting Residual White Cells in Leukocyte-Depleted Red Blood Cells. Vox Sang, vol. 66, pp. 25-32. cited by other . | G.A. Becker, M. Tuccelli, T. Kunicki, M. K. Chalos and R. H. Aster. (1973) Studies of Platelet Concentrates Stored at 22 C and 4 C., Transfusion vol. 13, pp. 61-68. cited by other . | Kekez, MM, Sattar, SA. Nov. 1997. &quot;A new ozone-based method for virus inactivation: preliminary study.&quot; Phys Med Biology, 42 (110), pp. 2027-2039. cited by other . | Murphy S, Rebulla P, Bertolini F, et al., 1994. In vitro assessment of the quality of stored platelet concentrates. Transfus Med Rev, vol. 8, pp. 29-36. cited by other . | Martin C, Boisson C, Haccoun M, Thomachot L, Mege JL, 1997. Patterns of cytokine evolution (tumor necrosis factor-alpha and interleukin-6) after septic shock, hemorrhagic shock, and severe trauma. Crit care Med, vol. 25:11, pp. 1813-1819. cited by other . | Leach MF.; AuBuchon JP.; Pickard CA.; Herschel LH.; Cooper LK. Jenike DM.; Simpson SY.; Southworth SV.. 1998. Evaluation of glucose and Ph test strips in the detection of microbial contaminants in aphersis platelets. Vox Sanguinis, vol. 74(S1), p. 1180. cited by other . | Blajchman MA.. 1995. Bacterial contamination of blood products and the value pretransfusion testing. Immunol Invest, vol. Jan.-Feb. 24:1-2, pp. 163-170. cited by other . | Holmsen, H. (1994) Significance of testing platelet functions in vitro. Eur J Clin Invest. vol. 24, Suppl.1, pp. 3-8. cited by other . | Dodd, RY., 1990. Will Blood Products Be Free of Infectious Agents? : Transfusion Medicine in the 1990's. In Nance SJ ed. Arlington, VA, American Association of Blood Banks, pp. 223-251. cited by other . | Cabantchik, Z.I., Silfen J., Firestone R.A., Krugliak M., Nissani E. and Ginsburg H., 1989. Effects of Lysosomotropic Detergents on the Human Malarial Parasite Plasmodium Falciparum in In Vitro Culture. Biochemical Pharmacology, vol. 38, No. 8, pp. 1271-1277. cited by other . | Fratantoni, J.C., Poindexter, B.J., and Bonner, R.F. (1984) Quantitative assessment of platelet morphology by light scattering: a potential method for the evaluation of platelets for transfusion., J. Lab. Clin. Med vol. 103, pp. 620-631. cited by other . | Bertolini, F. and Murphy, S. (1994) A multicenter evaluation of reproducibility of swirling in platelet concentrates., Transfusion vol. 34, pp. 796-801. cited by other . | Holme S., Moroff G., Murphy S., 1998. A multi-laboratory evaluation of in vitro platelet assays: The tests for extent of shape change and response to hypotonic shock. Transfusion, vol. 38:31, pp. 31-40. cited by other . | Greenwalt, TJ and Allen, CM, 1990. A Method for Counting Leukocytes in Filtered Components. Transfusion, vol. 30, No. 4, pp. 377-379. cited by other . | Sherwood WC. 1993. The significance of the blood-borne viruses: blood banking and transfusion medicine. Dev Bio Stand, vol. 81, pp. 25-33. cited by other . | Buchholz DH.; AuBuchon JP.; Snyder EL.; Kandler R.; Piscitelli V.; Pickard C.; Napychank P.; Edberg S.. 1994. Effects of leukocyte reduction of the resistance of blood components to bacterial multiplication. Transfusion, vol. 34, pp. 852-857. cited by other . | Valeri C.R., 1974. Oxygen Transport and Viability of Preserved Red Blood Cells. J. Med. vol. 5. cited by other . | Coleman, Roger; Holdsworth, George. 1975. Effects of Detergents on Erythrocyte Membranes: Different Patterns of Solubilization of the Membrane Proteins by Dihydroxy and Trihydroxy Bile Salts. Biochemical Society Transactions, vol. 3, pp. 747-748. cited by other . | Kunicki, T. J., Tucelli, M., Becker, G.A., and Aster, R.H. (1975) A study of variables affecting the quality of platelets stored at room temperature., Transfusion vol. 15, pp. 414-421. cited by other . | Wylie BR. 1993. Transfusion transmitted infection: viral and exotic diseases. Anaesth Intensive Care, vol. Feb. 21:1, pp. 24-30. cited by other . | America's Blood Centers. &quot;Bacterial Contamination of Blood Components&quot; Jul. 2000. Online at: http://66.155.15.152/medical/bulletin.sub.--v3.sub.--n2.htm. cited by other . | Ledent E, Berlin G, 1996. Factors influencing white cell removal from red cell concentrates by filtration. Transfusion, vol. 36, No. 8, pp. 714-718. cited by other . | Holme S, Heaton WA. Courtright M. 1987. Improved in vivo and in vitro viability of platelet concentrates stored for seven days in a platelet additive solution. British Joumal of Haematology vol. 66:2 pp. 233-238. cited by other . | Valeri, C.R.; Ragno, G.; MacGregor, H.; Pivacek, L.E., 1997. The Effect of Disinfection on Viability and Function of Baboon Red Blood Cells. Photochemistry and Photobiology, 65(3), pp. 446-450. cited by other . | Kubanek B.; Cardoso M.; Gluck D.; Koerner K. 1993. Risk of infection transmission by blood components. Infusionsther Transfusionsmed, vol. Apr. 20:1-2, pp. 54-59. cited by other . | Holme S. 1992. Effect of additive solutions on platelet biochemistry. Blood Cells vol. 18:3 pp. 431-434. cited by other . | Blajchman MA.; Ali AM,; Richardson HL..1994. Bacterial contamination of blood components. Vox Sang, vol. 67 suppl 3, pp. 25-33. cited by other . | Gomez-Abones, X.; Pinacho, A.; Ortiz, P.; Macia, J.; Gallart, M.; Araguas, C.; Sanchez, J.M.; Teixido. A Simple Flow-Cytometric Method For Absolute Counting of Residual White Blood Cells in Leukocyte-Reduced Packed Red Cells. Vox Sanguinis. vol. 76, pp. 64-65. cited by other . | Barret BB.; Anderson.; JW.; Anderson KC.. 1993. Strategies for the avoidance of bacterial contamination of blood components. Transfusion, vol. Mar. 33:3, pp. 228-233. cited by other . | Rosenberg RD, Aird WC, 1999. Vascular-bed-specific hemostasis and hypercoagulable states. N Engl J Med, vol. 340, pp. 1555-1564. cited by other . | Chu RW. 1999. Leukocytes in Blood Transfusion: Adverse effects and their prevention. HKMJ, vol. 5, No. 3, pp. 280-284. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		62
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6096216 | US4248736 | US20050042131 | US6544727 | US4401430 | US5639452 | US6045820 | US5545401 | US7229427 | US6106773 | US4140652 | US20020197252 | US5609864 | US20020045157 | US6407212 | US5240601 | US6736972 | US5693452 | US20020058032 | US5370869 | US6045787 | US5360605
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		22
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		93869304 | 50178003
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2004-09-10 | 2003-09-10
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		TRIOSYN HOLDING, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		TRIOSYN HOLDING, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Williston, VT
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Williston, VT
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		MESSIER, PIERRE
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		MESSIER, PIERRE
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		St., Sauveur, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		St., Sauveur, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		MESSIER, PIERRE J. TRIOSYN HOLDING INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		ZALUKAEVA, TATYANA
	</str>
	<str name="Assistant Examiner">
		CHAPMAN, GINGER T
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

