<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7799293
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11530508
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Actinide extraction methods
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Methods of separating actinides from lanthanides are disclosed. A regio-specific/stereo-specific dithiophosphinic acid having organic moieties is provided in an organic solvent that is then contacted with an acidic medium containing an actinide and a lanthanide. The method can extend to separating actinides from one another. Actinides are extracted as a complex with the dithiophosphinic acid. Separation compositions include an aqueous phase, an organic phase, dithiophosphinic acid, and at least one actinide. The compositions may include additional actinides and/or lanthanides. A method of producing a dithiophosphinic acid comprising at least two organic moieties selected from aromatics and alkyls, each moiety having at least one functional group is also disclosed. A source of sulfur is reacted with a halophosphine. An ammonium salt of the dithiophosphinic acid product is precipitated out of the reaction mixture. The precipitated salt is dissolved in ether. The ether is removed to yield the dithiophosphinic acid.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2006-09-11
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2006
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2006-09
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-09-21
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-09
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C01G56/00 | C22B60/00 | B01D11/04
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C01G56/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C01G
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C01G56
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		423/21.5 | 423/10 | 210/638 | 568/8 | 210/634 | 423/8 | 210/749 | 423/3 | 568/16 | 210/753 | 423/20 | 568/14 | 423/21.1 | 568/13
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		423/21.5
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		423
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Xie, Neilson et al., Organometallics, vol. 4, (1985), pp. 339-344. cited by other . | Written Opinion of the International Searching Authority, International Application No. PCT/US 06/35807, International filing date Sep. 13, 2006. cited by other . | Screttas et al., The Utilization of Organolithium Compounds, etc., Journal of American Chemical Society, vol. 27, (1962), pp. 2573-2577. cited by other . | International Search Report for International Application WO 2008/088576 (PCT/US2007/073229), Mailed Aug. 7, 2008. cited by other . | Patel &amp; Harwood, The Chemistry of Diphosphine Disulfides, The Journal of American Chemical Society, vol. 32, (1967), pp. 2999-3003. cited by other . | Modolo, G. Influence of the Purity and Irradiation Stability of Cyanex 301, etc., Journal of Radioanalytical and Nuclear Chemistry, vol. 228, (1998), pp. 83-88. cited by other . | Modolo, Giuseppe and Nabet, Sherif. &quot;Thermodynamic Study on the Synergistic Mixture of Bis(chlorophenyl)dithiophosphinic Acid and Tris(2-ethylhexyl)phosphate for Separation of Actinides(III) from Lanthanides(III).&quot; Solvent Extraction and Ion Exchange; May 2005, vol. 23 Issue 3, pp. 359-373. cited by examiner . | Ionova et al., Mechanism of Trivalent Actinide/Lanthanide Separation Using Synergistic Mixtures, etc., New Journal of Chemistry, vol. 25, (2001), pp. 491-501. cited by other . | Pinkerton &amp; Cavell, Synthesis and Characterization of Bis(trifluoromethyl)thiophosphinic Acid and its Anhydride, Journal of the American Chemical Society, vol. 94:6, (1972), pp. 1870-1874. cited by other . | Modolo et al. &quot;The separation of trivalent actinides from lanthanides by dithiophosphinic acids from HNO3 acid medium.&quot; Journal of Alloys and Compounds 271-273 (1998) 248-251. cited by examiner . | Hays, H., The Controlled Alkylation of Mono-n-alkylphosphines, Journal of American Chemical Society, vol. 31, (1966), pp. 3817-3820. cited by other . | Ionova, Rabbe et al., Solvent Extraction and Ion Exchange, 19(3), (2001), pp. 391-414. cited by other . | Kosolapoff, G., Some Variations of the Grignard Synthesis of Phosphinic Acids, Journal of the American Chemical Society, vol. 72, (1950), pp. 5508-5509. cited by other . | Higgins, Vogel &amp; Craig, Aromatic Phosphinic Acids and Derivatives, etc., Journal of the American Chemical Society, (1954), pp. 1864-1866. cited by other . | Benner, S., Diphenylphosphinodithioic Acid, etc., Tetrahedron Letters, vol. 22, No. 20, (1981), pp. 1851-1854. cited by other . | Hopkins, Vogel, Aromatic Phosphinic Acids and Derivatives, Journal of American Chemical Society, vol. 78, (1956), pp. 4447-4450. cited by other . | Klaehn et al., U.S. Appl. No. 11/232,541, filed Sep. 21, 2005, Extraction Agent and Method for Forming an Extraction Agent for the Separation of Actinides From Lanthanides. cited by other . | Meier et al., Nonsymmetric palladium Complexes etc., Organometallics, vol. 22, (2003), pp. 3905-3914. cited by other . | Casey, et al., Electron Withdrawing Substituents on Equatorial and Apical Phosphines, etc., Journal of the American Chem. Soc., 119, (1997), pp. 11817-11825. cited by other . | Casalnuovo et al., Ligand Electronic Effects in Asymmetric Catalysis, etc., Journal of the American Chemical Society, 116, (1994), pp. 9869-9882. cited by other . | Stuebe, et al., The Preparation and Reactions of Diphenylphosphinous Chloride, Journal of American Chemical Society, vol. 77, (1954), pp. 3526-3529. cited by other . | Authors Unknown, Mitigation of Long Lived Actinides and Fission Products, ITU Annual Report (1997), pp. 83-95. cited by other . | Peters, G., Reactions of Secondary Phosphine Sulfides, Journal of the American Chemical Society, vol. 27, (1961), pp. 2198-2201. cited by other . | Dilworth &amp; Wheatley, The Preparation and Coordination Chemistry of Phosphorus-Sulfur Donor Ligands, Coordination Chemistry Review, vol. 1999, (2000), pp. 89-158. cited by other . | International Search Report for PCT/US06/35807 dated Aug. 3, 2007. cited by other. | Guoxin et al., Investigation of the Extraction Complexes of Light Lanthanides, etc., Inorg. Chemistry, vol. 42, (2003), pp. 735-741. cited by other . | Romanovskiy et al. &quot;The Universal Solvent Extraction (UNEX) Process. I. Development of the UNEX Process Solvent for the Separation of Cesium, Strontium, and the Actinides From Acidic Radioactive Waste.&quot; Solvent Extraction and Ion Exchange; Jan. 2001, vol. 19 Issue 1, pp. 1-21. cited by examiner . | Bartlett &amp; Meguerian, Reactions of Elemental Sulfur, etc., Journal of the American Chemical Society, vol. 78, (1956), pp. 3710-3715. cited by other . | Modolo &amp; Odoj, Synergistic Selective Extraction of Actinides (III) Over Lanthanides, etc., Solvent Extraction and Ion Exchange, vol. 17(1), (1999), pp. 33-53. cited by other . | Cowley, A., Preparation and Properties of Bulky Secondary Phosphones, Inorg. Chem., (1983), 22, pp. 547-550. cited by other . | Cowley &amp; Kemp, Preparation and Properties of Bulky Secondary Phosphines, Inorg. Chemistry, vol. 22, (1983), pp. 547-550. cited by other . | Nash, K., A Comparison of New Reagents and Processes for Hydrometallurgical Processing of Actinides, Paper presented at Global 2001, Sep. 9-13, 2001, Paris, France. American Nuclear Society. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		32
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US4867951 | US5447552 | US4523009 | US3018301 | US4369147 | US6312654 | US5639433 | US4318893 | US4536596 | US5475146 | US4548790 | US4721605 | US4412053 | US4308214 | US3463619 | US5966584 | US5826161 | US7157003 | US20050203314 | US20040230079 | US5908805 | US4470933 | WO2007037995 | WO2008088576
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		24
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		BATTELLE ENERGY ALLIANCE, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		BATTELLE ENERGY ALLIANCE, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Idaho Falls, ID
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Idaho Falls, ID
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		PETERMAN, DEAN, R. | KLAEHN, JOHN, R. | HARRUP, MASON, K. | TILLOTSON, RICHARD, D. | LAW, JACK, D.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		PETERMAN, DEAN, R.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		5
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Idaho, Falls, ID
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Idaho, Falls, ID | Idaho, Falls, ID | Idaho, Falls, ID | Moore, ID | Pocatello, ID
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		TRASKBRITT
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		KASTLER, SCOTT
	</str>
	<str name="Assistant Examiner">
		WALCK, BRIAN
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

