<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7790033
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12126208
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Surface water treatment using flocculation and associated methods
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A method and system for removing pollutants from water are provided. The system includes at least one settling basin having shallow and deep areas. Coagulants can be added to bring pollutants down to the bottom surface of the basin. During dry periods, the deep areas retain a level of water therein, and the flocs that have settled on the bottom of the shallow areas will dry out, and can be tilled into the soil until re-flooding.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2008-05-23
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2008-05
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-09-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-09
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/32 | C02F1/52
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/32
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/631 | 210/747 | 210/602 | 210/702 | 210/170.01
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/631
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		DeBusk et al., &quot;Effectiveness of Mechanical Aeration in Floating Aquatic Macrophyte-Based Wastewater Treatment Systems,&quot; Journal of Environmental Quality, vol. 18, No. 3, pp. 349-354, Jul.-Sep. 1989. cited by other . | Wen, Li and Recknagel, Friedrich, &quot;In Situ Removal of Dissolved Phosphorus in Irrigation Drainage Water by Planted Floats: Preliminary Results from Growth Chamber Experiment,&quot; Agriculture, Ecosystems and Environment, vol. 90, pp. 9-15, Jun. 2002. cited by other . | Lake Apopka Water Hyacinth Demonstration Project, Second Semi-Annual Report prepared for St. Johns River Water Management District, prepared by Amasek, Inc., Apr. 4, 1991. cited by other . | Youngchul, Kim and Wan-Joong, Kim, &quot;Roles of Water Hyacinths and Their Roots for Reducing Algal Concentration in the Effluent from Waste Stabilization Ponds,&quot; Water Research, vol. 34, No. 13, pp. 3285-3294, Sep. 1, 2002. cited by other. | Clark, Mark, &quot;Biophysical Characterization of Floating Wetlands (Flotant) and Vegetative Succession of a Warm-Temperature Aquatic Ecosystem,&quot; Dissertation, University of Florida, 2000. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		5
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US4668388 | US4765914 | US5893978 | US6692641 | US6986845 | US5733453 | US3579443 | US5766474 | US6251264 | US7179387 | US6413426 | US6837994 | US5993649 | US7014776 | US5938936 | US4818416 | US5456844 | US2352772 | US4507206
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		19
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		DEBUSK, THOMAS, A.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		DEBUSK, THOMAS, A.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Cocoa, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Cocoa, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		HARTT, JACQUELINE E. LOWNDES, DROSDICK, DOSTER, KANTOR &amp; REED, P.A.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		PRINCE, FRED
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

