<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7790039
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US10992154
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Tangential flow filtration devices and methods for stem cell enrichment
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The present invention provides methods for enriching a heterogenous mixture of bone marrow or blood constituents for stem cells by removal of non-stem cell constituents comprising separation of the non-stem cell constituents using a tangential flow filtration device.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2004-11-18
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2004
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2004-11
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-09-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-09
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01D11/00 | B01D61/00 | C12N5/00 | A01N1/02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01D11/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01D11
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/651 | 210/650 | 435/372 | 435/373 | 424/529 | 210/645 | 435/2 | 435/297.4
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/651
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Pujol, B. et al., &quot;Endothelial-like cells derived from human CD14 positive monocytes,&quot; Differentiation, 65:287-300 (Jun. 2000). cited by other . | Sun, R. et al. &quot;The effects of natural killer-cell depletion on ex vivo expansion of hematopoietic progenitor cells from umbilical cord blood,&quot; Haematologica, 88:561-569 (May 2003). cited by other . | Grimm et al., &quot;An enhanced and scalable process for the purification of SIV gag-specific MHC tetramer,&quot; Protein Expression and Purification 23:270-281 (2001). cited by other . | Nicholson, G. et al., &quot;Induction of osteoclasts from CD14-positive human peripheral blood mononuclear cells by receptor activator of nuclear factor .kappa.B ligand (RANKL),&quot; Clin. Sci. (Lond.), 99:133-140 (Aug. 2000). cited by other . | Britten, M.B. et al., &quot;Infarct remodeling after intracoronary progenitor cell treatment in patients with acute myocardial infarction (TOPCARE-AMI): Mechanistic insights from serial contrast-enhanced magnetic resonance imaging,&quot; Circulation, 108:2212-2218 (Nov. 4, 2003). cited by other . | Gill, M. et al., &quot;Vascular trauma induces rapid but transient mobilization of VEGFR2.sup.+AC133.sup.+ endothelial precursor cells,&quot; Circ. Res., 88:167-174 (Feb. 2, 2001). cited by other . | Assmus, B. et al., &quot;Transplantation of progenitor cells and regeneration enhancement in acute myocardial infarction (TOPCARE-AMI),&quot; Circulation, 106:3009-3017 (Dec. 10, 2002). cited by other . | Perin, E. et al., &quot;Transendocardial, autologous bone marrow cell transplantation for severe, chronic ischemic heart failure,&quot; Circulation, 107:2294-2302 (May 13, 2003). cited by other . | Quirk, A and Woodrow, J. &quot;Investigation of the parameters affecting the separation of bacterial enzymes from cell debris by tangential flow filtration,&quot; Enzyme Microb. Technol., 6:201-206 (May 1984). cited by other . | Nakamura et al., &quot;Enrichment of lineage .sup.-CD34.sup.- cells using a newly developed filter system,&quot; British Journal of Haematology 108:801-804 (2000). cited by other . | Laham, R. and Oettgen, P., &quot;Bone marrow transplantation for the heart: fact or fiction?&quot; Lancet, 361:11-12 (Jan. 4, 2003). cited by other . | Bosch, M., U.S. Appl. No. 10/517,871, filed Dec. 13, 2004, entitled &quot;Tangential Flow Filtration Devices and Methods for Leukocyte Enrichment.&quot; cited by other . | Badorff, C. et al., &quot;Transdifferentiation of blood-derived human adult endothelial progenitor cells into functionally active cardiomyocytes,&quot; Circulation, 107:1024-1032 (Feb. 25, 2003). cited by other . | Havemann, K. et al., &quot;In vitro transformation of monocytes and dendritic cells into endothelial like cells,&quot; in Novel Angiogenic Mechanisms: Role of Circulating Progenitor Endothelial Cells, pp. 47-57, Nicanor I. Moldovan eds., 2003. cited by other . | Orlic, D. et al., &quot;Bone marrow cells regenerate infarcted myocardium,&quot; Nature, 410:701-705 (Apr. 5, 2001). cited by other . | Radlett, P.J., &quot;The concentration of mammalian cells in a tangential flow filtration unit,&quot; Appl. Chem. Biotechnol., 22:495-499 (1972). cited by other . | Denning-Kendal, P.A. et al. &quot;Different behaviour of fresh and cultured CD34+ cells during immunomagnetic separation,&quot; Br. J. Haematol., 105:780-785 (Jun. 1999). cited by other . | Peichev, M. et al., &quot;Expression of VEGFR-2 and AC133 by circulating human CD34+ cells identifies a population of functional endothelial precursors,&quot; Blood, 95:952-958 (Feb. 1, 2000). cited by other . | Tomita, S. et al., &quot;Improved heart function with myogenesis and angiogenesis after autologous porcine bone marrow stromal cell transplantation,&quot; J. Thorac. Cardiovasc. Surg, 123:1132-1140 (Jun. 2002). cited by other . | Rehman, J. et al., &quot;Peripheral blood `Endothelial Progenitor Cells` are derived from monocyte/macrophages and secrete angiogenic growth factors,&quot; Circulation, 107:1164-1169 (Mar. 4, 2003). cited by other . | Tse, HF et al., &quot;Angiogenesis in ischaemic myocardium by intramyocardial autologous bone marrow mononuclear cell implantation,&quot; Lancet, 361:47-49 (Jan. 4, 2003). cited by other . | Genovesi, C., &quot;Several uses for tangential-flow filtration in the pharmaceutical industry,&quot; J. Parenter. Sci. Technol., 37:81-86 (May-Jun. 1983). cited by other . | Deliliers, G. et al., &quot;Harvesting of autologous blood stem cells after a mobilising regimen with low-dose cyclophosphamide,&quot; Leuk. Lymphoma, 43:1957-1960 (Oct. 2002). cited by other . | Sekhar et al., &quot;Retroviral transduction of CD34-enriched hematopoietic progenitor cells under serum-free conditions,&quot; Human Gene Therapy 7:33-38 (1996). cited by other. | Rowley, SD et al. &quot;Isolation of CD34+ cells from blood stem cell components using the Baxter Isolex system,&quot; Bone Marrow Transplant., 21:1253-1262 (Jun. 1998). cited by other . | Stamm, C. et al., &quot;Autologous bone-marrow stem-cell transplantation for myocardial regeneration,&quot; Lancet, 361:45-46 (Jan. 4, 2003). cited by other . | Becker, S. et al., &quot;Colony-stimulating factor-induced monocyte survival and differentiation into macrophages in serum-free cultures,&quot; J. Immunol., 139:3703-3709 (Dec. 1, 1987). cited by other . | Strauer, B. et al., &quot;Repair of infarcted myocardium by autologous intracoronary mononuclear bone marrow cell transplantation in humans,&quot; Circulation, 106:1913-1918 (Oct. 8, 2002). cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		28
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US4240398 | US5948441 | US6949355 | US5843780 | US4644056 | US4420398 | US5846427 | US7002027 | US4722902 | US6455306 | US6984379 | US6183640 | US6313285 | US6544506 | US5192553 | US5423738 | US6565427 | US6140040 | US20030134416 | WO2004076651 | EP0208450 | WO2003000444 | WO1985003011
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		23
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		NORTHWEST BIOTHERAPEUTICS, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		NORTHWEST BIOTHERAPEUTICS, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Bethesda, MD
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Bethesda, MD
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		BOSCH, MARNIX, L. | LODGE, PATRICIA, A. | MCEARCHERN, JULIE, ANNA | BOYNTON, ALTON, L. | HUGENHOLTZ, PAUL, G.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		BOSCH, MARNIX, L.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		5
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Medina, WA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Medina, WA | Everett, WA | Mill, Creek, WA | Kingston, WA | AA, Oosterbeek, NL
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		CHRISTENSEN O'CONNOR JOHNSON KINDNESS PLLC
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		FORTUNA, ANA M
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

