<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7776217
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12425246
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Bioretention system and method
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A bioretention system and method are provided for removing phosphorus, nitrogen and other materials from effluent such as wastewater and stormwater. The system and method can include a filtration media comprising water treatment residuals and other fill such as soil. Plants can be growing in the soil. The system can also include a drainage system to regulate outflow, to function during both low and high throughputs of water.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2009-04-16
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2009-04
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-08-17
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-08
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/04 | C02F3/32 | B01D33/70
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/04
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/150 | 210/290 | 210/263 | 210/903 | 210/602 | 210/807 | 210/109 | 210/617 | 210/170.03 | 210/906
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/150
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		William C. Lucas, &quot;Nutrient Retention in Vegetated and Nonvegetated bioretention Mesocosms&quot;, Journal of Irrigation and Drainage Engineering, Sep./Oct. 2008, pp. 613-623, ASCE. cited by other . | Bolan, N.S. et al., &quot;A Critical Review on the Role of Mycorrhizal Fungi in the Uptake of Phosphorus by Plants,&quot; Plant and Soil, 1991, vol. 134, pp. 189-207. cited by other . | M. Razali, &quot;Effectiveness of a drinking-water treatement sludge in removing difference phosphorus species from aqueous solution&quot;, Separation and Purification Technology, 2007, pp. 300-306, vol. 55, Elsevier B.V. cited by other . | Johansson, L., &quot;Blast Furnace Slag as Phosphorus Sorbents--Column Studies,&quot; The Science of Total Environment, 1999, vol. 229, pp. 89-97. cited by other . | Dietz, M.E. et al., &quot;A Field Evaluation of Rain Garden Flow and Pollutant Treatment,&quot; Water, Air, and Soil Pollution, 2005, vol. 167, pp. 123-138. cited by other . | Y. Q. Zhao, &quot;Alum sludge-based constructed wetland: An innovative and cost-effective system for wastewater treatment&quot;, 11th International Conference on Wetland Systems for Water Pollution Control, Nov. 1-7, 2008, Indore, India. cited by other . | Hunt, W.F. et al., &quot;Evaluating Bioretention Hydrology and Nutrient Removal at Three Field Sites in North Carolina,&quot; Journal of Irrigation and Drainage Engineering, 2006, pp. 600-608. cited by other . | Van Tichelen, K. K., &quot;Kinetics of Phosphate Absorption by Mycorrhizal and Non-Mycorrhizal Scots Pine Seedlings,&quot; Physiologia Plantarum, 2000, vol. 110, pp. 96-103. cited by other . | Davis, A. P. et al., &quot;Laboratory Study of Biological Retention for Urban Stormwater Management,&quot; Water Environment Research, 2001, vol. 73, No. 1, pp. 5-14. cited by other . | Hsieh, C. H. et al., &quot;Multiple-Event Study of Bioretention for Treatment of Urban Storm Water Runoff,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 2006, vol. 51, No. 3-4, pp. 177-181. cited by other . | Henderson, C., &quot;Removal of Dissolved Nitrogen, Phosphorus and Carbon From Stormwater by Biofiltration Mesocosms,&quot; Water Science &amp; Technology, 2007, vol. 55, No. 4, pp. 183-191. cited by other . | Y. Q. Zhao, &quot;Use of dewatered alum sludge as main substrate in treatment reed bed receiving agricultural wastewater: Long-term trial&quot;, Bioresource Technology, 2009, pp. 644-648, vol. 100, Elsevier Ltd. cited by other . | Hsieh, C.H. et al., &quot;Evaluation and Optimization of Bioretention Media for Treatment of Urban Storm Water Runoff,&quot; Journal of Environmental Engineering, 2005, pp. 1521-1531. cited by other . | International Search Report Issued by Lee W. Young, May 20, 2009, PCT/US09/40844. cited by other. | Sovik, A.K. et al., &quot;Phosphorus Retention Processes in Shell Sand Filter Systems Treating Municipal Wastewater,&quot; Ecological Engineering, 2005, vol. 25, pp. 168-182. cited by other . | A.O. Babatunde, &quot;Reuse of dewatered aluminium-coagulated water treatment residual to immobilize phosphorus: Batch and column trials using a condensed phosphate&quot;, Chemical Engineering Journal, 2008, pp. 108-115, vol. 136, Elsevier B.V. cited by other . | Westholm, L. J., &quot;Substrates for Phosphorus Removal--Potential Benefits for On-Site Wastewater Treatment?&quot; Water Research, 2005, vol. 40, pp. 23-36. cited by other . | Erickson, A.J. et al., &quot;Enhanced Sand Filtration For Storm Water Phosphorus Removal,&quot; Journal of Environmental Engineering, 2007, pp. 485-497. cited by other . | Hsieh, C.H. et al., &quot;Bioretention Column Studies of Phosphorus Removal From Urban Stormwater Runoff,&quot; Water Environment Research, 2007, vol. 79, No. 2, pp. 177-184. cited by other . | A.O. Babatunde, &quot;Testing and evaluation of a tidal flow alum sludge based contructed wetland system&quot;, 11th International Conference on Wetland Systems for Water Pollution Control, Nov. 1-7, 2008, Indore India. cited by other . | Y. Q. Zhao, &quot;Use of dewatered alum sludge as a substrate in reed bed treatment systems for wastewater treatment&quot;, Journal of Environmental Science and Health, Part A, 2008, pp. 105-110, vol. 43, Taylor &amp; Francis Group, LLC. cited by other . | Davis, A.P. et al., &quot;Water Quality Improvement Through Bioretention Media: Nitrogen and Phosphorus Removal,&quot; Water Environment Research, 2006, vol. 78, No. 3, pp. 284-293. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		22
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US8333885
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US7232278 | US6652743 | US6814871 | US7077963 | US6582156 | US5863433 | US5462666 | US6558555 | US6537340 | US7320752 | US6468942 | US5876606 | US5702593 | US6830688 | US7087169 | US7341661 | US7294275 | US6896805 | US5893975 | US6712969 | US6923917 | US4707270 | US20020179509 | US20060151387 | US5322629 | US5733453 | US6620321 | US20070256966 | US6277274 | US6569321 | US5976401 | US6406627 | US4184947 | US6623642 | JP1990119992
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		35
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		LUCAS, WILLIAM
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		LUCAS, WILLIAM
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Malvern, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Malvern, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		STROOCK &amp; STROOCK &amp; LAVAN LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		PRINCE, FRED
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

