<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7749447
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11137254
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		N-channel, Y-energy mode, Z-coupled nested gaussian surfaces for liquid(s) dispensing, liquid(s) treatment, liquid(s) introduction and solid(s) production methods and apparatus
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Femtoliter to milliliter volumes of one or a plurality of different liquids are accurately transported, dispensed and/or treated where the fluids are energized electrokinetically or in a hybrid mode where auxiliary energy sources including but not limited to pneumatic, piezoelectric; peristaltic; ultrasonic; thermal; gravitational, acoustic are employed concurrently or sequentially to transport liquids for various purposes from diverse devices. Liquids in nested Gaussian surfaces or common liquid handling devices (e.g., syringes) can be energized by electric induction or conduction of lumen or targets or both and are optionally concurrently or sequentially combined with non electrical energy to effect highly accurate volumetric and spatial liquid transport with active or passive flight direction yielding non touch or touch liquid sample placement, parallel dispensing, with or without filtration, SPE, LC, or other treatment technologies for scientific instrument introduction (e.g., MALDI/ESI), drug delivery, diagnostics, manufacturing of products, product tagging, sample preparation or related applications.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2005-05-25
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2005
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2005-05
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-07-06
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-07
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01L3/02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01L3/02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01L
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01L3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		422/100 | 250/288 | 210/656
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		422/100
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		422
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		See Gather 2001 American Laboratory Sauter et al. cited by other. | Sauter, Jr. et al., &quot;&quot;Electric&quot; Zip Tips.TM., Preliminary Results&quot;, Apr. 1, 2002, Journal of the Association for Laboratory Automation, vol. 7 Issue 2, pp. 52-55. cited by examiner . | See Proceedings For Labautomation 2005 Poster Session of Sauter et al. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US20020139751 | US6245227 | US6132582 | US3476291 | US5275016 | US2933087 | US20020190203 | US6269701 | US5916524 | US6149815
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		10
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		SAUTER, JR., ANDREW, DANIEL
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		SAUTER, JR., ANDREW, DANIEL
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Henderson, NV
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Henderson, NV
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		WARDEN, JILL
	</str>
	<str name="Assistant Examiner">
		HURST, JONATHAN M
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

