<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7744761
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12163205
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Desalination methods and systems that include carbonate compound precipitation
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Desalination methods that include carbonate compound precipitation are provided. In certain embodiments, feed water is subjected to carbonate compound precipitation conditions prior to desalination. In certain embodiments, desalination waste brine is subjected to carbonate compound precipitation conditions. In yet other embodiments, both feed water and waste brine are subjected to carbonate compound precipitation conditions. Aspects of embodiments of the invention include carbon dioxide sequestration. Embodiments of the invention further employ a precipitate product of the carbonate compound precipitation conditions as a building material, e.g., a cement. Also provided are systems configured for use in methods of the invention.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2008-06-27
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2008-06
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-06-29
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-06
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01D61/10
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01D61/10
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01D61
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		423/220 | 210/652 | 210/718 | 588/252 | 423/165 | 210/710 | 423/430 | 203/10
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		423/220
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		423
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		International Search Report dated Sep. 8, 2009 of PCT/US2009/045722. cited by other . | Rahardianto et al., &quot;High recovery membrane desalting of low-salinity brackish water: Integration of accelerated precipitation softening with membrane RO&quot;; Science Direct; Journal of Membrane Science 289 (2007) 123-137. cited by other . | Haywood et al., &quot;Carbon dioxide sequestration as stable carbonate minerals--environmental barriers&quot;; Environmental Geology (2001) 41:11-16; Springer-Verlag 2001. cited by other . | Kohlmann et al., &quot;Carbon Dioxide Emission Control by Mineral Carbonation: The Option for Finland&quot;; INFUB 6th European Conference on Industrial Furnaces and Boilers Estoril Lisbon Portugal, Apr. 2-5, 2002 10pp. cited by other . | Christiansen, L.E., et al. Measurement of Sulfur Isotope Compositions by Tunable Laser Spectroscopy of SO2. Analytical Chemistry, Nov. 17, 2007, vol. 79, No. 24, pp. 9261-9268 (abstract) [online] [retrieved on Dec. 30, 2009] &lt;URL: http://pubs.acs.org/doi/abs/10.1021/ac071040p&gt;. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Feb. 2, 2010 of PCT/US09/059141. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/126,776 filed May 23, 2008, Constantz, Brent R., et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Feb. 25, 2010; 21 pp. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Oct. 30, 2009 of PCT/US09/056573. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Jan. 13, 2010 of PCT/US09/059135. cited by other . | Turner, J.A. 1999. &quot;A Realizable Renewable Energy Future.&quot; Science. 285 (5428): 687-689. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Sep. 22, 2009 of PCT/US2009/047711. cited by other . | Bond, G.M., et al. 2002. Brines as possible cation sources for biomimetic carbon dioxide sequestration. American Geophysical Union Abstract #U22A-07. cited by other . | Rau, G. 2004. Possible use of Fe/CO2 fuel cells for CO2 mitigation plus H2 and electricity production. Energy Conversion and Management. 45: 2143-2152. cited by other . | Rakib, M. et al. 1999. Behaviour of Nafion.RTM. 350 membrane in sodium sulfate electrochemical splitting: continuous process modelling and pilot scale tests. Journal of Applied Electrochemistry. 29: 1439-1448. cited by other . | Rosenthal, E., &quot;Cement Industry is at Center of Climate Change Debate&quot; New York Times; www.nytimes.com/2007/10/26/business/worldbusiness/26cement.html''ref=toda- yspaper; 4pp. cited by other . | Hill et al., &quot;Preliminary Investigation of Carbon Sequestration Potential in Brine from Pennsylvania's Oriskany Sandstone Formation in Indiana County, PA&quot;; The Energy Institute and the Department of Energy &amp; Geo-Environmental Engineering; 5pp. cited by other . | Nayak, V.S. &quot;Nonelectrolytic Production of Caustic Soda and Hydrochloric Acid from Sodium Chloride&quot;; Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 1996. 35: 3808-3811. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Dec. 14, 2009 of PCT/US09/061748. cited by other . | Park, a., et al. 2004. CO2 mineral sequestration: physically activated dissolution of serpentine and pH swing process. Chemical Engineering Science 59 (22-23): 5241-5247. cited by other . | Carbon Sequestration. National Energy Technology Laboratory, Jul. 1, 2008 (online) [retrieved on Dec. 21, 2009] &lt;URL: http://web.archive.org/web/20080701213124/http://www.netl.doe.gov/technol- ogies/carbon.sub.--seq/index.html&gt;. cited by other . | Serizawa et al., &quot;Cell-compatible properties of calcium carbonates and hydroxyapatite deposited on ultrathin poly (vinyl alcohol)-coated polyethylene films&quot;; J. Biomater Sci. Polymer Edn., vol. 14, No. 7 (2003) pp. 653-663. cited by other . | Green Car Congress &quot;Researcher Proposes System for Capture of Mobile Source CO2 Emissions Directly from Atmosphere&quot;; www.greeencarcongress.com/2007/10/researcher-prop.html#more; Oct. 8, 2007; 4pp. cited by other . | Huntzinger, D.N. et al. 2009. A life-cycle assessment of Portland cement manufacturing: comparing the traditional process with alternative technologies. Journal of Cleaner Production. 17: 668-675. cited by other . | Montes-Hernandez, G. et al.,&quot;Mineral sequestration of CO2 by aqueous carbonation of coal combustion fly-ash.&quot; Journal of Hazardous Materials vol. 161 (2009). pp. 1347-1354. cited by other . | O'Connor, W.K. et al. &quot;Carbon dioxide sequestration: Aqueous mineral carbonation studies using olivine and serpentine.&quot; 2001. Albany Research Center, National Energy Technology Laboratory: Mineral Carbonation Workshop, Pittsburgh, PA. cited by other . | Mazrou, S., et al. 1997. Sodium hydroxide and hydrochloric acid generation from sodium chloride and rock salt by electro-electrodialysis. Journal of Applied Electrochemistry 27: 558-567. cited by other . | Uibu, M. et al.,&quot;Mineral trapping of CO2 via oil shale ash aqueous carbonation: controlling mechanism of process rate and development of continuous-flow reactor system.&quot; Oil Shale. vol. 26, No. 1 (2009)pp. 40-58. cited by other . | Faverjon, F. et al. 2006. Regeneration of hydrochloric acid and sodium hydroxide from purified sodium chloride by membrane electrolysis using a hydrogen diffusion anode-membrane assembly. Joumal of Membrane Science 284 (1-2): 323-330. cited by other . | Berg et al., &quot;A 3-Hydroxyproprionate/ 4-Hydroxybutyrate Autotrophic Carbon Dioxide Assimilation Pathway in Archea&quot;; Science 14, Dec. 2007; vol. 318, No. 5857 DOI 10.1126/science 1149976; pp. 1782-1786. cited by other . | Huntzinger, D.N. Carbon Dioxide Sequestration in Cement Kiln Dust Through Mineral Carbonation. Michigan Technological University, 2006 [online], [retrieved on Dec. 29, 2009]. &lt;URL: http://www.geo.mtu.edu/.about.dnhuntzi/DNHuntzingerETD.pdf&gt;. cited by other . | Uibu, M. et al. &quot;CO2 mineral sequestration in oil-shale wastes from Estonian power production.&quot; Journal of Environmental Management vol. 90 (2009). pp. 1253-1260. cited by other . | Faverjon, F. et al. 2005. Electrochemical study of a hydrogen diffusion anode-membrane assembly for membrane electrolysis. Electrochimica Acta 51 (3): 386-394. cited by other . | Wen-Zhi et al., Using Electrolytic Method to Promote CO2 Sequestration in Serpentine by Mineral Carbonation; Journal of China University of Mining and Technology; vol. 36, No. 6; Nov. 2007 (Publication and English Translation). cited by other . | International Search Report dated Sep. 17, 2008 of PCT/US2008/068564. cited by other . | O'Connor et al., &quot;Carbon Dioxide Sequestration by Direct Mineral Carbonation: Results From Recent Studies and Current Status&quot;; Albany Research Center, Albany Oregon; Office of Fossil Energy, US Dept. of Energy; 1st Annual DOE Carbon Sequestration Conference, Washington DC, May 2001 12pp. cited by other . | Graff &quot;Just Catch--CO2 Capture Technology&quot; Aker Kvaerner; Pareto Clean Energy Tech Seminar Oct. 11 (2007) 25pp. cited by other . | Lackner, K.S. et al. &quot;Carbon Dioxide Disposal in Carbonate Minerals.&quot; Energy. 1995. 20(11): 1153-1170. cited by other . | Shell Global Solutions, &quot;ADIP-X and Sulfinol-X--new regenerable acid-gas removal processes&quot;; Shell Global Solutions International; OG 130210370903-En(A); www.shellglobalsoultions.com 2 pp. cited by other . | Winschel, R.A., et al. Stable Carbon Isotope Analysis of Coal/Petroleum Coprocessing Products. Preprints of Papers, American Chemical Society, Division of Fuel Chemistry, Jan. 1, 1988, vol. 33, No. 1, pp. 114-121 [online], [retrieved on Dec. 29, 2009] &lt;URL: http://www.anl.gov/PCS/acsfuel/preprint%20archive/Files/33.sub.--1.sub.--- Toronto.sub.--06-88.sub.--0114.PDF&gt;. cited by other . | Wright, L.L., et al. 1993. &quot;U.S. Carbon Offset Potential Using Biomass Energy Systems.&quot; Water, Air, and Soil Pollution. 70:483-497. cited by other. | Huntzinger, D.N. et al.,&quot;Carbon Dioxide Sequestration in Cement Kiln Dust through Mineral Carbonation&quot;; Environmental Science &amp; Technology, vol. 43, No. 6 (2009) pp. 1986-1992. cited by other . | Huijgen, W.J.J., et al. 2003. Carbon dioxide sequestration by mineral carbonation. ECN-C-03-016; Energy Research Centre of the Netherlands: Petten; pp. 1-42. cited by other . | Huijgen, W.J.J., et al. 2005. Carbon dioxide sequestration by mineral carbonation: Literature review update 2003-2004, ECN-C-05-022; Energy Research Centre of the Netherlands: Petten; pp. 1-37. cited by other . | &quot;Biomass Burning: A Hot Issue in Global Change.&quot; National Aeronautics and Space Administration. Langley Research Center, Hampton, Virginia. Fact Sheet Fs-2001-02-56-LaRC. Feb. 2001. 4 pages. cited by other . | Sadhwani et al., &quot;Case Studies on environmental impact of seawater desalination&quot; Science Direct; http://www.sciencedirect.com/science?.sub.--ob=ArticleURL&amp;.sub.--udi=B6TF- X-4HMX97J-38&amp;.sub.--u... 3pp. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Jan. 4, 2010 of PCT/US09/062795. cited by other . | Gain, E. et al. 2002. Ammonium nitrate wastewater treatment by coupled membrane electrolysis and electrodialysis. Journal of Applied Electrochemistry 32: 969-975. cited by other . | Goldberg et al., &quot;CO2 Mineral Sequestration Studies in US&quot;; National Energy Technology Laboratory; goldberg@netl.doe.gov; 10pp. cited by other . | Lackner, K. &quot;Carbonate Chemistry for Sequestering Fossil Carbon&quot;; Annual Review Energy Environ. 2002 27:193-232. cited by other . | Sasakawa, M., et al. Carbonic Isotopic Characterization for the Origin of Excess Methane in Subsurface Seawater. Journal of Geophysical Research, vol. 113 (abstract) [online], Mar. 11, 2008 [retrieved on Jan. 1, 2010] &lt;URL: http://www.agu.org/pubs/crossref/2008/2007JC004217.shtml&gt;. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Oct. 19, 2009 of PCT/US2009/050223. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Mar. 11, 2009 of PCT/US2008/088318. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/344,019 filed Dec. 24, 2008, Constantz, Brent R., et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Nov. 16, 2009. cited by other . | Raz et al., &quot;Formation of High-Magnesium Calcites via an Amorphous Precursor Phase: Possible Biological Implications&quot;; Advanced Materials; Adv. Mater. (2000) vol. 12, No. 1; 5pp. cited by other . | Bond, G.M., et al. 2001. CO2 Capture from Coal-Fired Utility Generation Plant Exhausts, and Sequestration by a Biomimetic Route Based on Enzymatic Catalysis--Current Status (paper presented at the First National Conference on Carbon Sequestration, May 14-17, in Washington D.C., USA; Paper Sa.5. cited by other . | Aker, &quot;Aker Clean Carbon, Carbon Capture Solutions Provider&quot; Aker Clean Carbon Presentation for UN's IPCC; Jan. 24, 2008; 8pp. cited by other . | Stanley, S.M., et al. 2002. Low-magnesium calcite produced by corallin algae in seawater of Late Cretaceous composition. PNAS. 99(24): 15323-15326. cited by other . | Holze, S. et al. 1994. Hydrogen Consuming Anodes for Energy Saving in Sodium Sulphate Electrolysis. Chem. Eng. Technol. 17: 382-389. cited by other . | Tececo Pty Ltd, &quot;Eco-Cement&quot;; www.tececo.com/simple.eco-cement.php; Dec. 29, 2008; 6pp. cited by other . | Levy, D. &quot;Burnt biomass causes short-term global cooling, long-term warming.&quot; http://news-service.stanford.edu/news/2004/august4/biomass-84.h- tml. 3 pages. cited by other . | Biello, D. Cement from CO2: A Concrete Cure for Global Warming? Scientific American Aug. 7, 2008., pp. 1-3 [online] [retrieved on Dec. 29, 2009] &lt;URL: http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm&gt;. cited by other . | &quot;Electrochemical cell&quot;, Wikipedia (2009), http:en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electrochemical.sub.--Cell, Nov. 24, 2009, 5 pp. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Aug. 5, 2009 of PCT/2009/048511. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Sep. 17, 2009 of PCT/US2009/050756. cited by other . | Cannell, M.G.R. 2003. &quot;Carbon sequestration and biomass energy offset: theoretical, potential and achievable capacities globally, in Europe and the UK.&quot; Biomass and Bioenergy. 24: 97-116. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Mar. 11, 2009 of PCT/2008/088246. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Feb. 19, 2009 of PCT/US08/88242. cited by other . | Druckenmiller et al., &quot;Carbon sequestration using brine of adjusted pH to form mineral carbonates&quot;; Elsevier; www.elsevier.com/locate/fuproc; Fuel Processing Technology 86 (2005) 1599-1614. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/486,692 filed Jun. 17, 2009, Constantz Brent. et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Mar. 1, 2010. cited by other . | Green Car Congress &quot;PKU Researchers Carry Out Aqueous Fischer-Tropsch Reaction for First Time&quot;; www.greeencarcongress.com/2007/12/pku-researchers.html; Dec. 12, 2007; 2pp. cited by other . | Uliasz-Bochenczyk, A. et al. &quot;Utilization of Carbon Dioxide in Fly Ash and Water Mixtures.&quot; Chemical Engineering Research and Design. 2006. 84(A9): 843-846. cited by other . | Publication: &quot;Existing &amp; Emerging Concentrate Minimization &amp; Disposal Practices for Membrane Systems&quot;; Sandeep Sethi, Steve Walker, Jorg Drewes and Pei Xu; Florida Water Resources Journal, Jun. 2006, pp. 38,40,42,44,46 and 48. cited by examiner . | Huijgen, W.J.J., et al. 2006. Energy Consumption and Net CO2 Sequestration of Aqueous Mineral Carbonation. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 45: 9184-9194. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/375,632 filed Mar. 5, 2009, Kirk, Donald W. et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Sep. 8, 2009. cited by other . | Justnes, H. et al. &quot;Pozzolanic, Amorphous Silica Produced from the Mineral Olivine.&quot; Proceedings of the Seventh CANMET/ACI International Conference on Fly Ash, Silica Fume, Slag and Natural Pozzolans in Concrete, 2001. SP-199-44. pp. 769-781. cited by other . | Green Car Congress &quot;Researchers Develop New Method for Ocean Sequestration of Carbon Dioxide Through Accelerated Weathering f Volcanic Rocks&quot;; www.greeencarcongress.com/2007/11/researchers-dev.html#more; Nov. 7, 2007; 3pp. cited by other . | Huijgen, W.J.J., et al. 2005. Mineral CO2 Sequestration by Steel Slag Carbonation. Environ. Sci. Technol. 39: 9676-9682. cited by other . | Lin, C. et al. Use of Cement Kiln Dust, Fly Ash, and Recycling Technique in Low-Volume Road Rehabilitation. Transportation Research Record, 1992, No. 1345, pp. 19-27 (abstract) [online], [retrieved on Dec. 31, 2009] &lt;URL: http://pubsindex.trb.org/view.aspx?id=370714&gt;. cited by other . | Genders, D. 1995. Electrochemical Salt Splitting. http://www.electrosynthesis.com/news/mwatts.html (accessed Feb. 5, 2009). cited by other . | Alexander, G. et al., &quot;Evaluation of reaction variables in the dissolution of serpentine for mineral carbonation&quot;; Elsevier; ScienceDirect Fuel 86 (2007) 273-281. cited by other . | Wang, W., et al. 2005. Effects of biodegradation on the carbon isotopic composition of natural gas--A case study in the bamianhe oil field of the Jiyang Depression, Eastern China. Geochemical Journal. 39(4): 301-309. (abstract) [online] [retrieved on Dec. 29, 2009] &lt;URL: http://www/jstage.jst.go.jp/article/geochemj/39/4/39.sub.--301/.sub.--art- icle&gt; ab. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/475,378 filed May 29, 2009, Constantz Brent. et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Mar. 2, 2010. cited by other . | Back, M. et al.,&quot;Reactivity of Alkaline Lignite Fly Ashes Towards CO in Water.&quot; Environmental Science &amp; Technology. vol. 42, No. 12 (2008) pp. 4520-4526. cited by other . | CICCS &quot;Aims and Research&quot;; www.nottingham.ac.uk/carbonmanagement/ccs.sub.--aims.php 2pp Aug. 3, 2007. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		84
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US8137444 | US8177909 | US8147697 | US8151482 | US8187464 | US8197693 | US7931809 | US7993500 | US8062418 | US8114214 | US8048309 | US8333944 | US8357270 | US8137455 | US8006446
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		15
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US4107022 | US20060165583 | US20050031522 | US2329940 | US6090197 | US3374164 | US6190428 | US20040231568 | US3511712 | US5037286 | US20050180910 | US3917795 | US6786963 | US3558769 | US7132090 | US20050154669 | US20060185985 | US4838941 | US4410606 | US7452449 | US6936573 | US4450009 | US6264740 | US20020127474 | US20070163443 | US20100024686 | US20080275149 | US5776328 | US3511595 | US4140510 | US20060169177 | US1678345 | US2934419 | US6518217 | US7135604 | US4217186 | US20040267077 | US1897725 | US20060051274 | US20080138265 | US6638413 | US20020009410 | US3904496 | US7427449 | US20050087496 | US5470671 | US20070186820 | US20070148509 | US20070056487 | US3725267 | US6416574 | US20060105082 | US6248166 | US6180012 | US4818367 | US4264367 | US20050036932 | US20060185560 | US5766338 | US5766339 | US5366513 | US20060184445 | US20070202032 | US7040400 | US5364611 | US3120426 | US5614078 | US20060288912 | US4370307 | US6071336 | US20090232861 | US20070261947 | US3963592 | US7440871 | US20080236143 | US4561945 | US6375825 | US7198722 | US20090186244 | US7282189 | US6217728 | US5897704 | US20040040671 | US3925534 | US5785868 | US5855666 | US20090010827 | US20060060532 | US6402831 | US20090169452 | US20050232855 | US3179579 | US6200381 | US3463814 | US6024848 | US3202522 | US2383674 | US2606839 | US20040213705 | US4915914 | US20030126899 | US5362688 | US4026716 | US5584923 | US4335788 | US5584926 | US20080223727 | US6080297 | US20040219090 | US4477573 | US20080248350 | US6602630 | US4242185 | US5855759 | US5246551 | US3420775 | US20040052865 | US3627480 | US6352576 | US20080277319 | US20040126293 | US20060185516 | US20050011770 | US3630762 | US5690729 | US3861928 | US6517631 | US3525675 | US20030213937 | US20050238563 | US20060196836 | US20010023655 | US3953568 | US20030017088 | US4620969 | US20050022847 | US1865833 | US20060048517 | US3627479 | US4899544 | US4246075 | US7285166 | US5100633 | US20080031801 | US5624493 | US7347896 | US5531821 | US4147599 | US6890497 | US20050129606 | US5520898 | US6648949 | US7595001 | US4716027 | US20070217981 | US5965201 | US6475460 | US20050255174 | US5925255 | US6059974 | US20070187247 | US20070092427 | US3970528 | US6537456 | US20060195002 | US5282935 | US20090090277 | US6235186 | US6200543 | US20040040715 | US7037434 | US20050118081 | US20090001020 | US5595641 | US4188291 | US6280505 | US20080171158 | US6495013 | US2304391 | US4036749 | US20030123930 | US5230734 | US5846669 | US4128462 | US4931264 | US6776972 | US20090081093 | US20090081096 | US6129832 | US20010054253 | US20080245672 | US20070212584 | US6623555 | US20070240570 | US3864236 | US20080289495 | US20030188668 | US2458039 | US6251356 | US6890419 | US20040259231 | US7261912 | US20040014845 | US4804449 | US4080270 | US20080245660 | US5531865 | US4376101 | US6755905 | US3350292 | US20080112868 | US20040228788 | US6712946 | US20090301352 | US3046152 | US6387212 | US4588443 | US2967807 | US20010022952 | US5547027 | US5702585 | US6841512 | US5803894 | US6908507 | US4361475 | US20040139891 | US20040234443 | US20050002847 | US6444107 | US20080245274 | JP1995061842 | EP0522382 | WO2007106372 | EP1571105 | WO2002000551 | WO2004098740 | WO2008115662 | EP1379469 | WO2009024826 | EP1554031 | DE2653649 | WO1999013967 | WO2003068685 | WO2008108657 | GB2032441 | WO2006134080 | WO2009086460 | WO2008142017 | DE3638317 | EP0844905 | WO2010006242 | WO2008140821 | WO2007094691 | WO2009065031 | JP1982100280 | JP1976102357 | WO2007016271 | WO2007096671 | WO2007001633 | WO2009070273 | WO2008061305 | CA1335974 | JP1988312988 | WO2008151060 | WO2001096243 | EP0591350 | GB2371810 | GB911386 | DE19523324 | EP0487102 | WO2006036396 | WO2009039655 | WO2008018928 | WO2006009600 | WO2008068322 | JP1991020491 | DE3146326 | WO2009146436 | WO2007140544 | EP1650162 | AU20072007100157 | WO1993016216 | WO2008124538 | WO2008089523 | WO2003008071 | WO2007139392 | WO2005086843 | EP1716911 | WO2004001731 | WO2007003013 | WO2008026201 | JP2001041388 | WO2009006295 | WO2007123917 | WO2008031834 | JP1987142093 | DE19631794 | WO1996034997 | WO2008101293 | WO2001007365 | WO2003054508 | CA2646462 | WO2007060149 | WO2008142025 | WO2008095057 | WO2007106883 | WO2005108297 | WO2006034339 | WO2004094043 | EP0628339 | WO2005078836
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		311
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		CALERA CORPORATION
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		CALERA CORPORATION
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Los Gatos, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Los Gatos, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		CONSTANTZ, BRENT, R. | FARSAD, KASRA | FERNANDEZ, MIGUEL
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		CONSTANTZ, BRENT, R.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Portola, Valley, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Portola, Valley, CA | San, Jose, CA | San, Jose, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		BOZICEVIC, FIELD &amp; FRANCIS, LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		DRODGE, JOSEPH W
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		10
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		10
	</str>
</doc>

