<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7892432
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12378442
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Organic waste treatment using anaerobic and facultative anaerobic bacteria
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A method to prepare an organic composition for a digestor minimizes injury to and enhance the decomposition function of anaerobic and facultative anaerobic bacteria in the organic composition. The method is utilizes at an animal processing facility. Manure produced at the facility is periodically collected at least seven day intervals and at a temperature greater than thirty-two degrees F. Large pieces of inorganic material are removed from the manure while preserving a significant proportion of the living anaerobic and facultative anaerobic bacteria in the manure. The decomposition activity of anaerobic and facultative anaerobic bacteria is facilitated by, at a temperature in the range of fifty degrees F to one hundred and five degrees F, adding water to produce a slurry including seventy-five to ninety-five percent by weight water and twenty-five to five percent by weight of organic material. Organic material in the slurry is separated into particles having a length in the range of one micron to one-eighth of an inch. Inorganic material is removed from the slurry at a temperature in the range of fifty degrees F to ninety degrees F and while preserving the living anaerobic and facultative bacteria in the slurry to produce a slurry product comprised of less than twenty-five percent by weight of said organic material. The slurry product is transported to a digestor. The anaerobic and facultative anaerobic bacteria in the slurry product to decompose in the digestor organic material in the slurry product.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2009-02-12
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2009-02
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-02-22
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-02
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/613
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/613
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6660163 | US5846425 | US6893567
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		INTEGRATED ORGANIC ENERGY, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		INTEGRATED ORGANIC ENERGY, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Goodyear, AZ
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Goodyear, AZ
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		STEPENOFF, GARY, F. | STEPENOFF, G., SCOTT
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		STEPENOFF, GARY, F.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Phoenix, AZ
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Phoenix, AZ | Phoenix, AZ
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		TOD R. NISSLE, P.C.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BARRY, CHESTER T
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

