<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7883627
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12655314
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Automated fuel polishing system and methods
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		An automated system for fuel polishing stored fuel in multiple storage tanks, and methods for making and using such systems, such methods including the use of an apparatus comprising a pump having a flow velocity sufficient to suspend settled impurities in a fuel storage tank, at least a first and second fuel storage tank each having an inlet and an outlet; said at least one filter; a fluid pathway connecting said pump, said fuel storage tanks, and at least one filter; a first three-way valve positioned at a junction between the inlet of at least said first and second fuel storage tanks; a second three-way valve positioned at a junction between the outlet of at least said first and second fuel storage tanks; and a system controller component operably connected to said first and second three-way valve to automatically control the position of each valve without manual intervention.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2009-12-28
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2009-12
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-02-08
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-02
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01D37/04 | B01D37/00 | B01D17/12
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01D37/04
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01D37
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/196 | 210/197 | 210/138 | 210/805 | 210/741
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/196
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Photo of GCF Fuel Polishing Systems, Gulf Coast Filters, Inc., accessed from http://www.gulfcoastfilters.com/fuel.sub.--polishing.sub.--systems.h- tm, 3 pages, product information accessed on Jun. 24, 2008. cited by other . | Advanced Diesel Solutions New Zealand, DE-BUG Models, accessed from http://www.dieselsolutions.co.nz/products.shtml, 4 pages, product information accessed on Jun. 24, 2008. cited by other . | Fuel Polishing, Gulf Coast Filters, Inc., Optimum Fuel Quality At All Times, accessed from http://www.gulfcoastfilters.com/fuel.sub.--polishing.htm, 7 pages, product information accessed on Jun. 24, 2008. cited by other . | ASA Environmental Products--Fuel Polishing, Diesel Fuel Polishing Systems, accessed from http://www.asa-environmental.com/Catg1.asp?Cat1ID=92&amp;gclid=CJDosYGAjpQCFS- EbagodGUNGWw, 2 pages, product information accessed on Jun. 24, 2008. cited by other. | Andrews Annotated Figures 1 and 2, Adapted from above reference by Wil Andrews, p. 11. cited by examiner . | Wil Andrews, &quot;Captn Wil's Polishing System&quot;, Oct. 1, 2007, Water World Productions--published on the web at http://trawlersandtrawlering.com. cited by examiner .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		6
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5149433 | US5353760 | US6702948
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		BARRETT, DOUGLAS, P.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		BARRETT, DOUGLAS, P.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Mission, Viejo, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Mission, Viejo, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		STOUT, UXA, BUYAN &amp; MULLINS FISHER, CARLOS A.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		SMITH, DUANE
	</str>
	<str name="Assistant Examiner">
		DURAND, PAUL J
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

