<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7820061
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12499608
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Titanium oxide and alumina alkali metal compositions
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The invention relates to Group 1 metal/porous metal oxide compositions comprising porous metal oxide selected from porous titanium oxide and porous alumina and an alkali metal or an alkali metal alloy. The compositions of the inventions are described as Stage 0 and I materials. These materials differ in their preparation and chemical reactivity. Each successive stage may be prepared directly using the methods described below or from an earlier stage material. Stage 0 materials may, for example, be prepared using liquid alloys of Na and K which are rapidly absorbed by porous metal oxide under isothermal conditions, preferably at or just above room temperature, to form loose black powders that retain much of the reducing ability of the parent metals. When the low melting Group 1 metals are absorbed into the porous metal oxide at about 150.degree. C., an exothermic reaction produces Stage I material, loose black powders that are stable in dry air. Further heating forms higher stage materials of unknown composition. It is believed that Stage I higher materials represent reductions of the porous metal oxide after absorption of the Group 1 metal. Preferred Group 1 metal/porous metal oxide compositions of the invention are those containing sodium, potassium, or sodium-potassium alloys with sodium and sodium-potassium alloys being most preferred. Each stage of the Group 1 metal/porous metal oxide composition of the invention may be used as a reducing agent reacting with a number of reducible organic materials in the same manner known for alkali metals and their alloys.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2009-07-08
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2009-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-10-26
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-10
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C01G23/47 | B01J29/00 | B01J21/00 | B01J37/00 | C02F1/70 | B01J23/00 | C07C403/00 | C07C1/20 | C01G23/00 | B01J20/00 | C07C15/02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C01G23/47
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C01G
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C01G23
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		585/400 | 502/439 | 423/657 | 502/344 | 423/598 | 502/355 | 210/757 | 502/350 | 502/415 | 423/610 | 585/469
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		585/400
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		585
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Daryl P. Wernette, Andrew S. Ichimura, Stephanie A. Urbin, and James L. Dye, &quot;Inorganic Electrides Formed by Alkali Metal Addition to Pure Silica Zeolites,&quot; Chem. Mater., 2003, pp. 1441-1448, vol. 15, No. 7, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | V. Petkov, S.J.L. Billinge, T. Vogt, A.S. Ichimura, and J.L. Dye, &quot;Structure of Intercalated Cs in Zeolite ITQ-4: An Array of Metal Ions and Correlated Electrons Confined in a Pseudo-1 D Nanoporous Host,&quot; Physical Review Letters, Aug. 12, 2002, pp. 075502-1- 075502-4, vol. 89, No. 7, The American Physical Society. cited by other . | R. Qadeer, S. Akhtar, F. Mahmood, &quot;Nitrogen Adsorption on Metal Impregnated Alumina by Continuous Flow Method&quot; Back to Journal of IAS, vol. 8, No. 4, 1995. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Jan. 6, 2006. cited by other . | J. A. Rabo, P. H. Angell, P. H. Kasai, V. Schomaker, Studies of Cations in Zeolites: Adsorption of Carbon Monoxide; Formation of Ni ions and Na3/4.sup.+ centres, Discussions of the Faraday Society 41, 328-349 (1966). cited by other . | P. A. Anderson, D. Barr, P. P. Edwards, &quot;Solvated Electrons in the Synthesis of Ionic Clusters in Zeolites&quot; Angewandte Chemie International Edition in English 11, 1501-1502 (1991). cited by other . | J. Monte Russell, Michal Sabat, and Russell N. Grimes, &quot;Organotransition-Metal Metallacarboranes. 59. Synthesis and Linkage of Boron-Functionalized Ferracarborane Clusters,&quot; Organometallics, 2002, 21, pp. 4113-4128, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | V.I. Srdanov, G.D. Stucky, E. Lippmaa, and G. Engelhardt, &quot;Evidence for an Antiferromagnetic Transition in a Zeolite-Supported Cubic Lattice of F Centers,&quot; Physical Review Letters, Mar. 16, 1998, pp. 2449-2452, vol. 80, No. 11, The American Physical Society. cited by other . | Yasuo Nozue, Tetsuya Kodaira, Satoshi Ohwashi, Takenari Goto, and Osamu Terasaki, &quot;Ferromagnetic Properties of Potassium Clusters Incorporated into Zeolite LTA,&quot; Physical Review B, Oct. 15, 1993, pp. 12253-12261, vol. 48, No. 16, The American Physical Society. cited by other . | Jiliang IIE, Dennis D. Klug, Kentaro Uehara, Keith F. Preston, Christopher I. Ratcliffe, and John S. TSE, &quot;NMR and X-ray Spectroscopy of Sodium--Silicon Clathrates,&quot; J. Phys. Chem. B, 2001, pp. 3475-3485. vol. 105, No. 17, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Mar. 15, 2006. cited by other. | L. F. Fieser, M. Fieser, &quot;Topics in Organic Chemistry&quot;. (Reinhold, New York, 1963) pp. 514-515. cited by other . | Jaacov Levy, Dov Tamarkin, Henry Selig, and Mordecai Rabinovitz, &quot;Potassium Metal Dispersed on Silica: A Versatile Reagent in Organic Chemistry,&quot; Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. Engl. 20, 1981, No. 12, p. 1033, Verlag Chemie GmbH, 6940 Weinheim. cited by other . | Andrew S. Ichimura, James L. Dye, Miguel A. Camblor, and Luis A. Villaescusa, &quot;Toward Inorganic Electrides,&quot; J. Am. Chem. Soc., 2002, pp. 1170-1171, vol. 124, No. 7, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | P. P. Edwards, P. A. Anderson, J. M. Thomas, &quot;Dissolved Alkali Metals in Zeolites&quot; Accounts of Chemical Research 29, 23-29 (1996). cited by other . | KM. Unruh, T.E. Huber, and C.A. Huber, &quot;Melting and freezing behavior of indium metal in porous glasses,&quot; Physical Review B, Sep. 15, 1993, pp. 9021-9027, vol. 48, No. 12, The American Physical Society. cited by other . | Tetsuya Kodaira, Yasuo Nozue, Satoshi Ohwashi, Takenari Goto, and Osamu Terasaki, &quot;Optical Properties of Potassium Clusters Incorporated into Zeolite LTA,&quot; Physical Review B, Oct. 15, 1993, pp. 12245-12252, vol. 48, No. 16, The American Physical Society. cited by other . | A. Wurtz, &quot;Ueber eince neue Klasse organischer Radicale; nach&quot; Justus Liebig Ann. Chem. 96, 364-375 (1855). cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		18
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6403852 | US4353815 | US4087477 | US5288935 | US4278650 | US4440631 | US3878289 | US6399528 | US4446251 | US4413156 | US5292985 | US3527563 | US6586636 | US4471075 | US5157185 | US7083657 | US3405196 | US2378290 | US3808152 | US4229610 | US4720601 | US3347944 | US3954896 | US3322495 | US4508930 | US1939647 | US3079234 | US3274277 | US3658724 | US4982044 | US4366091 | US6096934 | US6022823 | US3897509 | US4727204 | US5856262 | US3535262 | US4633029 | US3575885 | US1665264 | US3670033 | US4394302 | US4276279 | US4313925 | US7315718 | US6358488 | US3794712 | US6492014 | US3793382 | US5008480 | US3493341 | US4675307 | US3489516 | US2337419 | US3577473 | US3915995 | US6315718 | US2816917 | US2765242 | US4769501 | US4837194 | US4205192 | US3576891 | US3033801 | US3033800 | US3290790 | US3928485 | US4248741 | US3165379 | US6706928 | US2731326 | US5128291 | US3679605 | US4168247 | US3801705 | US6548711 | US2740820 | US4975405 | US4435606 | US3507810
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		80
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		SIGNA CHEMISTRY, INC. (NEW YORK, NY), BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF MICHIGAN STATE UNIVERSITY
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		SIGNA CHEMISTRY, INC. (NEW YORK, NY), BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF MICHIGAN STATE UNIVERSITY
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		East Lansing, MI
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		East Lansing, MI
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		LEFENFELD, MICHAEL | DYE, JAMES, L.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		LEFENFELD, MICHAEL
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		New, York, NY
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		New, York, NY | East, Lansing, MI
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		J.A. LINDEMAN &amp; CO., PLLC
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		NGUYEN, CAM N
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

