<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7879593
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US10395424
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Fermentation systems, methods and apparatus
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The present invention relates to apparatus, methods, and applications for treating wastewater, and more particularly to biological processes for removing pollutants from wastewater. This invention further relates to apparatus and methods for growing microbes on-site at a wastewater treatment facility, and for economically inoculating sufficient microbes to solve various treatment problems rapidly
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2003-03-24
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2003
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2003-03
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-02-01
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-02
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/34
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/34
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		435/262.5 | 435/264 | 435/262
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		435/262.5
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		435
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Introductory Microbiology by Levy, et al., John Wiley &amp; Sons Inc., 1973, ISBN 0-471-53155-3, Title page only. cited by other. | Notification of Transmittal of the International Search Report Or the Declaration for PCT patent application No. PCT/US00/34197. cited by other . | &quot;Handbook of Microbiological Media,&quot; Ronald M. Atlas, CRC Press, edited by Lawrence C. Parks, ISBN: 0-8493-2944-2, Title page only. cited by other . | &quot;Catalogues of the National Collections of Type Cultures and Pathogenic Fungi&quot;, The Public Health Laboratory Service (PHLS), 1989, ISBN 0-901144-25-8. cited by other . | &quot;Optimizing Biological Processes--`A Look Inside The Black Box`,&quot; G.R. Whiteman, Gwinnett Industrial Conference, Duluth, GA, Apr. 1995. cited by other . | &quot;Advances In Sequencing Brings Use Of New Tools,&quot; B.E. Rittmann and G.R. Whiteman, Water Quality International, No. 1, pp. 14-16, 1994. cited by other . | 40 USC .sctn. 131.36. Apr. 12, 2000. &quot;Toxics criteria for those states not complying with Clean Water Act section 303(c)(2)(B).&quot; pp. 1120-1135. cited by examiner . | Bergey's &quot;Manual of Systematic Bacteriology&quot; Williams &amp; Wilkins, London, 1984 ISBN: 0-683-04108-8, Title page only. cited by other . | Buchanan RL et al. 1996. Culturing enterohemorrhagic Escherichia coli in the presence and absence of glucose as a simple means of evaluating the acid tolerance of stationary-phase cells. Appl Environ Microbiol 62: 4009-4013. cited by examiner . | &quot;Bioaugmentation Aids Wastewater Systems,&quot; M.H. Foster and G.R. Whiteman, Nalco Chemical Co. Reprint No. 587, from Environmental Protection, Oct. 1992. cited by other . | Staley JT, et al., &quot;Bergey's Manual of Systematic Bacteriology,&quot; Williams &amp; Wilkins Baltimore, vol. 3 (1989), Table of Contents only. cited by other . | &quot;Identification Methods in Applied and Environmental Microbiology&quot;, R. G. Board, Dorothy Jones, and F. A. Skinner, Blackwell Scientific Publications, London, 1992 &quot;The Society for Applied Bacteriology Technical Series No. 29,&quot; ISBN: 0-632-03379-7, Title page only. cited by other . | Catalogue of the National Collection of Type Cultures (NCTC), Catalogue of the Plasmid Section, National Collection of Type Cultures; and Catalogue of the National Collection of Pathogenic Fungi, Public Health Laboratory Service (PHLS) (1989), Table of Contents only. cited by other . | Bi-Chem LC 2009GT {online]. Novozymes, Inc., not dated [retrieved on Jun. 18, 2007]. Retrieved from the Internet: &lt;URL:www.novozymes.com/en/MainStructure/ProductsAndSolutions/Bioaugmen- tation++bioremediation/Municipal+wastewater+treatment/BI-CHEM+2009GT/BI-CH- EM+LC+2009GT.htm&gt;. cited by examiner . | &quot;Improving Treatment Performance With `Natural` Bioaugmentation,&quot; G.R. Whiteman, T. Gathraight, and S. Bailey, Proc. TAPPI Environmental Conference, Vancouver, Canada, c. 1997. cited by other . | Biochemistry, Second Edition, Albert L. Lehninger, Worth Publishers Inc., 1975, ISBN: 0-87901-047-9, Title page only. cited by other . | Krieg NR and Holt JG, &quot;Bergey's Manual of Systematic Bacteriology,&quot; Williams &amp; Wilkins Baltimore, vol. 1 (1984), Table of Contents only. cited by other . | Board RG, et al., &quot;Identification Methods in Applied and Environmental Microbiology,&quot; The Society for Applied Bacteriology Technical Series No. 29, Blackwell Scientific Publications, London (1992), Table of Contents only. cited by other . | &quot;Increasing Ligninolytic Enzyme Activities in Several White-Rot Basidiomycetes by Nitrogen Sufficient Media&quot; Erwin et al., Biosource Technology, vol. 53, (1995), pp. 133-139, Elsevier Science Limited. cited by other . | Kaal Erwin EJ, et al., &quot;Increasing Ligninolytic Enzyme Activities in Several White-Rot Basidiomycetes by Nitrogen Sufficient Media,&quot; Bioresource Technology 53: 133-139 (1995). cited by other . | American Type Culture Collection--&quot;Catalogue of Bacteria and Bacteriophages&quot;, Seventeenth edition (1989), Table of Contents only. cited by other . | &quot;The Application of Selected Microbial Formulations In The Pulp And Paper Industry,&quot; J.P. Nghiem, L.M. Coppedge, G.R. Whiteman, and J.L. Zuncich, TAPPI Environmental Conference, Book 1, pp. 235-238, San Antonio, TX, Apr. 1991. cited by other . | &quot;Filamentous and Dispersed Growth in Anaerobic Contact Systems,&quot;G. R. Whiteman, Ph.D. Thesis, 1985 University of Newcastle-upon-Tyne, England or Advanced Biological Services (ABS) Inc., Duluth, Ga. USA. cited by other . | Atlas RM and Parks LC, &quot;Handbook of Microbiological Media,&quot; CRC Press, Inc. (1993), Table of Contents only. cited by other . | American Type Culture Collection--&quot;Catalogue of Bacteria and Bacteriophages&quot;, 17.sup.th edition, 1989, ISBN: 0-930009-23-1, Title page only. cited by other . | Levy J, et al., Introductory Microbiology, John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc., (1973), Table of Contents only. cited by other . | Sneath PHA, et al., &quot;Bergey's Manual of Systematic Bacteriology,&quot; Williams &amp; Wilkins Baltimore, vol. 2 (1986), Table of Contents only. cited by other . | Lehninger AL, Biochemistry, Second Edition, Worth Publishers, Inc. (1975), Table of Contents only. cited by other . | AgBioSafety Glossary of Terms [online]. University of Nebraska-Lincoln, 2006 [retrieved on Jun. 14, 2007]. Retrieved from the Internet: &lt;URL:agbiosafety.unl.edu/glossary.htm&gt;. cited by examiner . | &quot;Bi-Chem LC 2009 GT: improved with Patented BioS 3112.&quot; 2007. Novozymes, Inc. Available online &lt;http://www.novozymes.com/NR/rdonlyres/726EEFB6-B097-4675-92EB-9E3AB7B- C36D5/0/BICHEMLC2009GTPDS.pdf&gt;, retrieved from the Internet Dec. 18, 2007. 3 pages. cited by examiner . | &quot;Case Study--Biological Additive INOC.TM. 8166 Allows Nitrification Of Wastewater Treatment Plant,&quot; Nalco Chemical Co. Reprint No. CH-241, case study was supplied courtesy of InterBio, Inc. 1991. cited by other . | &quot;The Application of Selected Microbial Formulations for Enhancing BOD Removal And Residence Time Studies,&quot; G.R. Whiteman and K.A. Holzer, Proc. TAPPI Environmental Conference, Book 3, pp. 773-781, Richmond, VA, Apr. 1992. cited by other . | Todar's Online Textbook of Bacteriology's entry on the Genus Bacillus [online]. University of Wisconsin-Madison, not dated [retrieved on Jun. 14, 2007]. Retrieved from the Internet: &lt;URL: textbookofbacteriology.net/ Bacillus.html&gt;. cited by examiner . | &quot;Bioaugmentation: A Coming Of Age,&quot; B.E. Rittmann and G.R. Whiteman, Water Quality International, No. 1, pp. 12-14, 1994. cited by other . | &quot;Developments in Biodegradation of Hydrocarbons-1&quot; by Watkinson, Applied Science Publishers, 1978 ISBN: 0-85334-751-4, Title page only. cited by other . | &quot;The Application of Selected Micro-Organisms To An Aerobic Waste Water Treatment Plant In The Chemical Industry,&quot; G.R. Whiteman, Proc. Chemical Waste Management--On Site or Off, Manchester, U.K., Oct. 1989. cited by other . | Williams ST, et al., &quot;Bergey's Manual of Systematic Bacteriology,&quot; Williams &amp; Wilkins Baltimore, vol. 4 (1989), Table of Contents only. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		37
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6136193 | US5798253 | US5981260 | US5888805 | US4009119 | US4554075 | US5866002 | US5846425 | US5449619 | US5980748 | US3979283 | US5369031 | US4649117 | US5879928 | US4894342 | US20020117445 | US6649401 | US5470460 | US3635797 | US4822490 | US5821112 | US3607737 | US5407577 | US5833857 | JP1983156397 | EP1063202 | JP1995132078 | EP0714858
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		28
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		WHITEMAN, G., ROBERT
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		WHITEMAN, G., ROBERT
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Duluth, GA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Duluth, GA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		GIBNEY, JR., LAWRENCE J.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BARNHART, LORA E.
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

