<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7846341
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11566681
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Method of ultrasonically treating a continuous flow of fluid
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The present invention relates to a method of utilizing ultrasonic waves emitted into a fluid to treat the fluid, matter within the fluid, and/or organisms within the fluid in a variety of manners such as, but not limited to, cleaning objects within the fluid, sterilizing the fluid and/or objects within it, separating bonded matter within the fluid, segregating matter within the fluid into discrete laminas, killing organisms within the fluid, inactivating organisms within the fluid, extracting matter from organisms within the fluid, extracting matter from other matter within the fluid, inducing chemical reactions within the fluid, and/or converting toxic matter within the fluid into a less toxic state. The method of the present invention comprises the steps of flowing the fluid to be treated, which may contain matter and/or organisms to be treated, through an object or plurality of objects such as, but not limited to a pipe, emptying the fluid flowing through the first object into an second object or plurality of second objects such as, but not limited to, a tank, wherein each second object possesses a cross-sectional area larger than the opening between the first objects and second objects, emitting ultrasonic waves into the fluid that are not parallel to the primary flow of fluid through the second objects as it flows through the second objects, establishing laminar flow in the fluid as the fluid flows through the second objects, and collecting the fluid in a third object or plurality of third objects such as, but not limited to, pipes.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2006-12-04
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2006
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2006-12
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-12-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-12
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F1/36
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F1/36
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/748.01 | 422/22
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/748.01
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		F. Javier Benitez, Simultaneous Photodegradation and Ozonation Plus UV of Phenolic Acids--Major Pollutants in Agro-Industrial Wastewaters, J. Chem. Technol. Blotechnol. 1997, pp. 253-260, vol. 70, Dept. of Chemical Engineering and Energy, University of Extremadura, Badajoz, Spain. cited by other . | R. Rajan, et al., Modeling of Sonochemical Decomposition of CCI4 in Aqueous Solutions, Environ. Sci. Technol., 1998, pp. 1128-1133, vol. 32, Dept. of Chemical Engineering, Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore, India. cited by other . | Jun Liang, et al., Improvement in Sonochemical Degradation of 4-chlorophenol by Combined Use of Fenton-like Reagents, Ultrasonics Sonochmistry, 2007, pp. 201-207, vol. 14, Graduate School of Env. Studies, Tohoku University, Sendai, Japan and Inst. of Multidisciplinary Research for Advanced Materials (IMRAM), Tohoku University, Sendai, Japan. cited by other . | Hugo Destaillats, et al., Scale-Up of Sonochemical Reactors for Water Treatment, Ind. Eng. Chem. Res., 2001, pp. 3855-3860, vol. 40, W. M. Keck Labs., California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, California, USA and Ultrasonic Energy Systems Inc., Panama City, FL, USA. cited by other . | A. Keck, et al., Influence of Particles on Sonochemical Reactions in Aqueous Solutions, Ultrasonics, 2002, pp. 661-665, vol. 40, Institut fur Technische Chemie, Karlsrue, Germany. cited by other . | Constantinos Vassilakis, et al., Sonolysis of Natural Phenolic Compounds in Aqueous Solutions: Degradation Pathways and Biodegradability, Water Research, Jul. 2004, pp. 3110-3118, vol. 38--Issue 13, Dept. of Environmental Engineering, Technical University of Crete, Polytechneioupolis, Chania, Greece. cited by other . | EPA, Wastewater Technology Fact Sheet, Ultraviolet Disinfection, EPA, Sep. 1999, Office of Water, United States EPA, Washington, D.C. cited by other. | Weihua Song, et al., Ultrasonically Induced Degradation of 2-methylisoborneol and Geosmin, Water Research, 2007, pp. 2672-2678, vol. 41, Dept. of Chemistry and Biochemistry, Florida Int'l University, University Park, Miami, FL, USA. cited by other . | Sridevi Goskonda, et al., Sonochemical Degradation of Aromatic Organic Pollutants, Waste Management, 2002, pp. 351-356, vol. 22, Dept. of Chemistry, University of Louisiana at Monroe, LA, USA and Lab for Ecological Chemistry, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, LA, USA. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		9
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US20040079680 | US20020088705 | US4599459 | US6547935 | US20060058710 | US20060086604 | US4747920 | US20070088386 | US20070244528 | US20070239250 | US6228273 | US7018546 | US20040159537 | US5738824 | US6929750 | US6395096 | US20040030254 | US20020156400 | US6649069 | US6964647 | US6444176 | US6858181 | US6478754 | US20030042174 | US20070031611 | US5958228 | US5951456 | US20070088245 | US20020190136 | US5779985 | US20020159917 | US4086057 | US5876671 | US20030019791 | US5876677 | US6960173 | US6569099 | US5124050 | US20070233054 | US20030153961 | US20070185527 | US20040256213 | US5076266 | US5679257 | US6723064 | US20050220665 | US20050015024 | US20030229304 | US20070088217 | US6601581 | US20030183798 | US20040042936 | US6911153 | US20040186384 | US6623444 | US5783790 | US6761729 | US20040129643 | US20030234173 | US6533803 | US20030171701 | US20020195402 | US20020082666 | US3708263 | US20070016110 | US5658534 | US6878288 | US20030236560 | US6663554 | US20010053384 | US20070051307 | US20060025716 | US7101485 | US6214222 | US4168295 | US20020103448 | US5611993 | US6827844 | US4211744 | US20070231346 | US20020138036 | US20030051988 | US20040069717 | US20030051989 | US6245207 | US6402965 | US5807521 | EP0424532 | WO2002076547 | WO2004014284 | WO1990005008 | WO2004091722 | WO2004012859 | WO1998017584 | WO2007121123 | WO1997017933 | WO2002028350 | EP1526825 | WO2007117800 | WO2002055150 | WO2000007941 | WO1997022398 | WO2002060525 | WO2007021427 | WO2002055131 | WO2002085456 | WO1999008967 | EP1322275 | EP1370321 | WO1997007830 | WO2007046989 | WO2006084308 | WO2007117964 | WO2007046990 | WO2007002598 | EP1596940 | WO2004089469 | WO2007018980 | EP1355696 | WO2002024150 | EP1617910 | WO1990011135 | EP0416106 | WO1990012655
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		124
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		BACOUSTICS, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		BACOUSTICS, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Minnetonka, MN
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Minnetonka, MN
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		BABAEV, ELIAZ
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		BABAEV, ELIAZ
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Minnetonka, MN
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Minnetonka, MN
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		GRIFFIN, WALTER D
	</str>
	<str name="Assistant Examiner">
		ALLEN, CAMERON J
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

