<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7833415
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11585842
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Method for treating raw sludge including a simultaneous or pulsed aerobic/anoxic digestion process
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		An improved process for sludge treatment includes anaerobic digestion followed by post-mesophilic aerobic and/or anoxic digestion. The first anaerobic step may be performed under either mesophilic or thermophilic conditions. The subsequent aerobic/anoxic digestion may be performed using either simultaneous, sequential or pulsed aerobic and anoxic conditions. An apparatus for performing the improved sludge treatment may be one digester for performing the anaerobic followed by aerobic/anoxic digestion. Alternatively, the system for performing the improved sludge treatment techniques may be at least two digest reactors.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2006-10-25
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2006
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2006-10
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-11-16
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-11
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/605
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/605
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Gavala, Hariklia N., et al., &quot;Mesophilic and thermophilic anaerobic digestion of primary and secondary sludge. Effect of pretreatment at elevated temperature,&quot; Water Research, 2003, vol. 37; pp. 4561-4572. cited by other . | Science Dictionary definition of &quot;raw sludge,&quot; http://www.science-dictionary.com/definition/raw-sludge.html, downloaded May 23, 2010. cited by examiner . | Messenger, J.R., et al., &quot;Oxygen Utilization Rate as a Control Parameter for the Aerobic Stage in Dual Digestion,&quot; Water Science Technology, 1990, vol. 22, No. 12; pp. 217-227. cited by other . | Salem, S., et al., &quot;Bio-Augmentation by Nitrification with Return Sludge,&quot; Water Research, 2003, vol. 37, No. 8; pp. 1794-1804. cited by other . | Yi, Y.-S., et al., &quot;Gas analysis reveals novel aerobic deammonification in themophilic aerobic digestion,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 2003, vol. 47, No. 10; pp. 131-138. cited by other . | Jeris, John S., et al., &quot;Determining the Stability of Treated Municipal Sludges,&quot; EPA, 1985, EPA-600/2/85-001, pp. 129,132. cited by other . | Ros, M., et al., &quot;Two-Stage Thermophilic Anaerobic-Aerobic Digestion of Waste-Activated Sludge,&quot; Environmental Eng. Sci., 2004, vol. 21, No. 5; pp. 617-626. cited by other . | Murthy, Sudhir, et al., &quot;Mesophilic Aeration of Autothermal Thermophilic Aerobically Digested Biosolids to Improve Plant Operations,&quot; Water. Env. Research, 2000, vol. 72, No. 4; pp. 476-483. cited by other . | Ranade, Bipin. R., et al., &quot;Microbial Massacre,&quot; Environmental Protection., Jul./Aug. 2004, pp. 1-4. cited by other . | Kumar, P., et al., &quot;Upgrading Wastewater Treatment by Water Hyacinth in Developing Countries,&quot; Water Science Technology, 1990, vol. 22, No. 7/8; pp. 153-160. cited by other . | Mason, C.A., et al., &quot;Aerobic Thermophilic Waste Sludge Treatment,&quot; Water Science Technology, 1992, vol. 25, No. 1; pp. 113-118. cited by other . | Ferran, et al., &quot;The two phase anaerobic digestion process: sludge stabilization and pathogens reduction,&quot; Water Science and Technology, 2000, vol. 42, No. 9, pp. 41-47. cited by other . | Fothergill, S., et al., &quot;VFA Production In Thermophilic Aerobic Digestion of Municipal Sludges,&quot; Journal of Env: Eng., May 2000; pp. 389-396. cited by other . | Chen, et al, &quot;Distribution and change of microbial activity in combined UASB and AFB reactors for wastewater treatment,&quot; Bioprocess and Biosystems Engineering, Apr. 2000, vol. 4, p. 1615-7591. Abstract only. cited by other.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		14
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6685834 | US7172699 | US5540839 | US4919815 | US4056465 | US7407584 | US4559142 | US4488968 | US4134830 | US4271026 | US6719903 | US6730224 | US20050087480 | US4915841 | US5605629 | US3345288 | US0624985 | US6660164 | US5223140 | US4461708 | US5601719 | US6015496 | US6676836 | US20050028680 | US4246099 | US7422688 | US5746919 | US4800021 | US20050145566 | US5266200 | US20030142301 | US5196111 | US5543051 | US4315821 | US6936170
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		35
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		D.C. WATER &amp; SEWER AUTHORITY
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		D.C. WATER &amp; SEWER AUTHORITY
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Washington, DC
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Washington, DC
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		MURTHY, SUDHIR, N. | NOVAK, JOHN, T. | BAILEY, JR., WALTER, F. | DAIGGER, GLEN, T. | SCHAFER, PERRY | PEOT, CHRISTOPHER
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		MURTHY, SUDHIR, N.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		6
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Washington, DC
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Washington, DC | Blacksburg, VA | Washington, DC | Parker, CO | Sacramento, CA | Washington, DC
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		DICKSTEIN SHAPIRO LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BARRY, CHESTER T
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

