<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7824557
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11835722
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Method for controlling microbial biofilm in aqueous systems
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A process has been found which increases the efficiency and effectiveness of introducing antimicrobial compounds into complex biofilm matrices through the use of liposome carriers, thereby removing the biofouling in industrial water bearing systems, including piping, heat exchanges, condensers, filtration systems and fluid storage tanks.According to one embodiment of the invention, antimicrobial compound containing liposomes are added to water systems prone to biofouling and biofilm formation. The liposomes, being similar in composition to microbial membranes or cells, are readily incorporated into the existing biofilm. Once the antimicrobial compound containing liposomes become entrained with the biofilm matrix, the decomposition or programmed disintegration of the liposome proceeds. Thereafter the biocidal aqueous core is released to react directly with the biofilm encased microorganisms. Upon the death of the organisms, the polysaccharide/protein matrix decomposes and thereby results in reduced fouling of the water bearing system, resulting in increased heat transfer, increased flux, less deposit of colloidal and particulate solids and dissolved organics on the surface of the microfiltration membrane, thereby reducing the frequency and duration of the membrane cleaning and ultimate replacement.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2007-08-08
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2007
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2007-08
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-11-02
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-11
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F1/50
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F1/50
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/759 | 422/28 | 210/754 | 210/755 | 424/417 | 210/756 | 210/764 | 422/37 | 210/916 | 424/450
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/759
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US4561981 | US6759040 | US6267979 | US5063213 | US6998049 | US5093357 | US5081134 | US6498862 | US6811711 | US5411666 | US5789239 | US5547939 | US6267897 | US6579541 | US5164096
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		15
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		GENERAL ELECTRIC COMPANY
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		GENERAL ELECTRIC COMPANY
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Schenectady, NY
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Schenectady, NY
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		WHITEKETTLE, WILSON, KURT | TAFEL, GLORIA, JEAN | ZHAO, QING
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		WHITEKETTLE, WILSON, KURT
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Jamison, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Jamison, PA | Doylestown, PA | Shanghai, CN
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		GE GLOBAL PATENT OPERATION TOOP, BARBARA A. WINTER, CATHERINE J.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		HRUSKOCI, PETER A
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

