<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7815810
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11/377810
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Apparatus for disinfection of sea water/ship's ballast water and a method thereof
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The invention disclosed provides an apparatus and method for disinfection of ship's ballast water, such as sea water, based on hydrodynamic cavitation. The apparatus comprises a cavitating chamber of cross section such as circular or non circular shape housing a single or multiple cavitating element(s) in the form of plates of metallic, ceramic, plastic materials of varying thicknesses placed perpendicular to the direction of flow of liquid and positioned at uniform or non-uniform spacing. The cavitating elements are provided with single or multiple orifices of different cross sections, circular or non-circular, with or without sharp edges and with a fraction of cross-sectional open area of the passage. The disinfected water may be re-circulated through the system for additional disinfection or released from the tank into the surrounding waterways. The disinfection of seawater/ship's ballast water is achieved by hydrodynamic cavitation and the method does not involve use of any chemicals or any chemical reaction. The invented apparatus and method is simple, eco-friendly and can be fitted on to existing intake and discharge systems of any ship with minor modifications. It poses no risk to the health of the ship's crew unlike chemical methods and requires no special skill or additional manpower for its operation. The apparatus and method is capable of effectively sterilizing hazardous organisms contained in ballast water stored in a ballast tank.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2006-03-15
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2006
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2006-03
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-10-19
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-10
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F1/34
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F1/34
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/748.01 | 422/20 | 422/39
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/748.01
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Boylston, J.: &quot;Ballast Water Management for the Control of Nonindigenous Species&quot;, Society of Naval Architects and Marine Engineers Transactions, vol. 104, Jan. 1996, pp. 391-417. cited by other.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US7585416 | JP2005246198 | JP2005271648 | PCT/IN1920/05000444
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		IN
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		2988/DEL/2005
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2005-11-08
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		COUNCIL OF SCIENTIFIC &amp; INDUSTRIAL RESEARCH (NEW DELHI, IN) MUMBAI UNIVERSITY INSTITUTE OF CHEMICAL TECHNOLOGY
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		COUNCIL OF SCIENTIFIC &amp; INDUSTRIAL RESEARCH (NEW DELHI, IN) MUMBAI UNIVERSITY INSTITUTE OF CHEMICAL TECHNOLOGY
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Mumbai, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Mumbai, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		BHALCHANDRA, PANDIT, A. | VINAYAK, RANADE, V. | CHANDRASHEKAR, ANIL, A. | SHIVRAM, SAWANT, S. | DANDAYUDAPANI, ILANGOVAN | RAJACHANDRAN, MADHAN | KRISHNAMURTHY, PILARISETTY, V.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		BHALCHANDRA, PANDIT, A.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		7
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Mumbai, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Mumbai, IN | Maharashtra, IN | Goa, IN | Goa, IN | Goa, IN | Goa, IN | Goa, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		EDWARDS ANGELL PALMER &amp; DODGE LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		GRIFFIN, WALTER D
	</str>
	<str name="Assistant Examiner">
		ALLEN, CAMERON J
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

