<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7862780
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11993872
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Apparatus and method of making transformed water
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The present invention provides an apparatus and method of producing transformed water without contact between the original transformed water and the water to be transformed. This is accomplished by organizing the original transformed water into a geometric contained arrangement such that a central cavity is created that substantially surrounds the water that is to be transformed. The water to be transformed is placed into a confined vessel such as a cylindrical container or a pipe inside the central cavity for about sixty seconds. This water then becomes transformed in the same likeness of the molecular clustering of the original transformed water.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2006-06-13
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2006
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2006-06
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-01-04
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-01
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C01B5/00 | B01J19/00 | C02F1/48
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C01B5/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C01B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C01B5
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		422/129 | 423/580.1 | 210/695 | 210/223 | 210/222
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		422/129
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		422
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		L. Rey, Thermoluminescence of ultra-high dilutions of lithium chloride and sodium chloride, Physica A 323 (2003) 67-74, Elsevier Inc., New York, New York. cited by other . | J. Benveniste, et. al., The Molecular Signal Is Not Functional in the Absence of &quot;Informed&quot; Water, FASEB Journal, 1999, vol. 13, p. A163), Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology, Bethesda, MD. cited by other . | J. Benveniste, et. al., A simple and fast method for in vivo demonstration of electromagnetic molecular signaling (EMS) via high dilution or computer recording, FASEB Journal 1999, vol. 13, p. A163, Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology, Bethesda, MD. cited by other. | I Jerman, Information processing in water and fields, in Proceedings of the 6th International Multi-Conference Information Society--Cognitive Sciences, Ljubljana, Slovenia, 2003. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5711950 | US20030028070 | US6033678 | US6139855 | US6451328 | US6521248 | US20020179536 | US20040126468 | US20040251211 | US5800576 | US6103218 | US5997590 | US20040234618 | US5846397 | US6165339 | US5800779
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		16
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		WHEELER, DAVID | KOSZTOLANYI, NORA
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		WHEELER, DAVID
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Beaverton, OR
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Beaverton, OR | Beaverton, OR
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		KRAGES, II, BERT P.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		GRIFFIN, WALTER D
	</str>
	<str name="Assistant Examiner">
		YOUNG, NATASHA
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

