<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7890226
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12499709
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Apparatus and method of vessel emission management
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		An emission management system (200) for a vessel (100) adapted to travel on water. The emission management system includes a monitoring assembly (202) for monitoring an emission from the vessel. The monitoring assembly is adapted to automatically detect the emission from the vessel and generate a data set representative of a vessel location at a time the emission occurred. The emission management system also includes a data storage system (210) in communication with the monitoring assembly for recording the data set generated by the monitoring assembly.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2009-07-08
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2009-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-02-15
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-02
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F1/40
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F1/40
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		114/183R | 701/21 | 210/109 | 114/121
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		114/183R
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		114
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		&quot;Prevention of Pollution by Sewage From Ships,&quot; .COPYRGT. 2002 International Maritime Organization, &lt;http://www.imo.org/Environment/mainframe.asp?topic.sub.--id=237&gt;. cited by other . | Hurley, W.L., Jr., and K.J. Reynolds, &quot;Ballast Exchange Monitoring System Report,&quot; File No. 02110, The Glosten Associates, Incorporated, Seattle, Wash., May 2003. cited by other . | Raaymakers, S. (ed.), &quot;GloBallast Monograph Series No. 5: 1st International Ballast Water Treatment R&amp;D Symposium, Symposium Proceedings, &quot; International Maritime Organization, London, Mar. 26-27, 2001. cited by other. | &quot;Draft International Convention for the Control and Management of Ships' Ballast Water and Sediments,&quot; to be submitted to the International Conference on Ballast Water Management for Ships, BWM/CONF/2, Feb. 9-13, 2004. cited by other . | &quot;Ballast Exchange,&quot; University of California Agriculture and Natural Resources, West Coast Ballast Outreach Project, vol. 5, Spring/Sumer 2003. cited by other . | &quot;Guidelines for the Development of Garbage Management Plans,&quot; MEPC/Circ. 317, Annex, Marine Environment Protection Committee, International Maritime Organization, Jul. 10, 1996. cited by other . | &quot;International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution From Ships, 1973, as Modified by the Protocol of 1978 Relating Thereto (MARPOL 73/78),&quot; .COPYRGT. 2002 International Maritime Organization, &lt;http://www.imo.org/Conventions/contents.asp?doc.sub.--id=678&amp;topic.su- b.--id=258&gt;. cited by other . | &quot;Navigation and Navigable Waters,&quot; Title 33, Chapter I, Part 151, Subpart A, &quot;Implementation of MARPOL 73/78 and the Protocol on Environmental Protection to the Antarctic Treaty as It Pertains to Pollution From Ships,&quot; Code of Federal Regulations, revised as of Jul. 1, 2004, pp. 257-306. cited by other . | &quot;Ballast Water Treatment R&amp;D Directory,&quot; 2d ed., International Maritime Organization, London, Nov. 2004. cited by other . | Carlton, J.T., et al., &quot;Shipping Study: The Role of Shipping in the Introduction of Nonindigenous Aquatic Organisms to the Coastal Waters of the United States (Other Than The Great Lakes) and an Analysis of Control Options,&quot; Report No. CG-D-11-95, National Sea Grant College Program/Connecticut Sea Grant Project R/ES-6, Apr. 1995. cited by other . | Hay, C.H., and D. Tanis, &quot;Mid-Ocean Ballast Water Exchange: Procedures, Effectiveness and Verification,&quot; Cawthron Report No. 468, Cawthron Institute, Nelson, New Zealand, and Battelle Ocean Sciences, Duxbury, Mass., Dec. 1998. cited by other . | &quot;Glosten Ballast Management System: GBMS Console Manual,&quot; The Glosten Associates, Incorporated, Seattle, Wash., May 12, 2004. cited by other . | &quot;Prevention of Air Pollution From Ships,&quot; .COPYRGT. 2002 International Maritime Organization, &lt;http://www.imo.org/Environment/mainframe.asp?topic.sub.--id=233&gt;. cited by other . | &quot;Prevention of Pollution by Garbage From Ships,&quot; .COPYRGT. 2002 International Maritime Organization, &lt;http://www.imo.org/Environment/mainframe.asp?topic.sub.--id=297&gt;. cited by other . | &quot;Assessment of Cruise Ship and Ferry Wastewater Impacts in Alaska,&quot; Alaska Department of Environmental Conservation, Feb. 9, 2004. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		15
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US20070261626 | US3937662 | US7381338 | US5664112 | US20020174814 | US6615580 | US7059261 | US6773611 | US20050167369 | US6816088 | US20030205187 | US7273562 | US20030176971 | US20080072809 | US6687583 | US6869540 | US20080147257 | US7128009 | US20070036683 | US20050016933 | US6444119 | US7327286 | US20070006787 | US20050165518 | US20050155539 | US6826514 | US3974940 | US6823810 | US7264738 | US20010027070 | US6871490 | US20070102371 | US6652750 | US6766754 | US7374602 | US6840983 | WO2005108301
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		37
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		THE GLOSTEN ASSOCIATES, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		THE GLOSTEN ASSOCIATES, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Seattle, WA
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Seattle, WA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		REYNOLDS, KEVIN, JOHN | HURLEY, JR., WILLIAM, LEFEVRE
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		REYNOLDS, KEVIN, JOHN
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Seattle, WA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Seattle, WA | Seattle, WA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		CHRISTENSEN O'CONNOR JOHNSON KINDNESS PLLC
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		TO, TUAN C
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

