<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7980257
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12903250
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Parts washing system
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Provided is a parts washer that includes a multi-tiered basin, a cleaning fluid and a biological component, living within the fluid, that breaks down organic waste. The multi-tiered basin includes a sink member with a false bottom, and a support grid and filter are interposed between the false bottom and a bottom panel of the sink member. The false bottom, support grid, and filter are readily removable from the sink member. The tank is partially filled with the cleaning fluid and a pump and conduit assembly direct a flow of the cleaning fluid to the basin. The cleaning fluid discharged into the basin flows through a drain hole in the false bottom, through the filter and support grid, and then through a drain hole in the bottom panel of the sink member back into the tank for reuse. The cleaning fluid includes, at least, a surfactant that functions to remove organic waste from the parts being washed. The biological component within the cleaning fluid includes nonpathogenic microorganisms that break down the organic waste. The cleaning fluid is not toxic to the microorganisms. The pump and conduit assembly, in addition to aiding in the removal of organic waste, functions to aerate the cleaning fluid to maintain a proper environment for the microorganisms. A heater, thermostat, and level control assembly function to maintain the cleaning fluid within a certain temperature range so as to aid in the removal of organic waste and maintain a proper environment for the microorganisms.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2010-10-13
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2010-10
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-07-19
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-07
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B08B3/04
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B08B3/04
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B08
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B08B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B08B3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		134/201 | 134/111 | 210/611 | 435/264
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		134/201
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		134
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Order, Civil Case No. 1:04-CV-3711-JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Jun. 6, 2008). cited by other . | Rebuttal Expert Report of John B. Durkee, PhD, P.E., Civil Case No. 1:04-CV-3711-JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Mar. 31, 2008). cited by other . | Lashmett, W, Declaration of William Lashmett, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711-JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Feb. 28, 2007). cited by other . | Plaintiff's Reply Brief in Support of its Second Motion for Additional Findings and Conclusions Non-Enablement of Defendants' Prior Art References, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711-JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Sep. 7, 2010). cited by other . | Defendants' Brief in Opposition to ChemFree's Motion for Reconsideration, New Trial, or to Alter or Amend the Court's Findings of Fact or Judgment, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711 JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Jul. 28, 2010). cited by other . | Order, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711 JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (May 5, 2009). cited by other . | Defendants' First Amended Invalidity Contentions, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711 JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Oct. 14, 2005). cited by other . | Order Cvil Acion No. 1:04-CV-3711JTC In the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia, Atlanta Division (Jun. 18, 2010). cited by other . | Lashmett, B, Declaration of Brent Lashmett, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711-JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Apr. 24, 2007). cited by other. | Supplemental Expert Report of John B. Durkee, PhD P.E., Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711 JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Jan. 7, 2009). cited by other . | Defendants' Final Consolidated Invalidity Contentions, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711 JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Jan. 5, 2009). cited by other . | Defendants'Brief in Opposition to ChemFree's Second Motion for Additional Findings and Conclusions Regarding the Non-Enablement of the Prior Art, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711 JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Jul. 28, 2010). cited by other . | Defendants' Third Amended Invalidity Contentions, Civil Case No. 1:04-CV-3711-JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Aug. 22, 2007). cited by other . | Defendants. J. Walter, Inc. and J. Walter Company LTD.'S Notice Pursuant to 35 U.S.C. .sctn. 282, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711-JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Jun. 11, 2009). cited by other . | Order, Civil Case No. 1:04-CV-3711-JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Jul. 17, 2007). cited by other . | Knowlton, G, Declaration of Glenn Knowlton, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711-JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Feb. 28, 2007). cited by other . | Plaintiff's Alternative Motions for Reconsideration, to Alter or Amend Findings and Conclusions, for New Trial, and to Alter or Amend Judgment, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711 JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Jul. 6, 2010). cited by other . | Rebuttal Expert Report of Peter Adriaens Submitted in Response to the Expert Report of James L. Brickell, Civil Case No. 1:04-CV-3711-JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Jan. 2, 2009). cited by other . | Interlocutory Decision in European Opposition Proceeding, Application No. 95 936 304.5-2316 (Dec. 16, 2004). cited by other . | Bucklin, R, Declaration of Robert Bucklin, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711-JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Feb. 23, 2007). cited by other . | Expert Report of Peter Adriaens , Civil Case No. 1:04-CV-3711-JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Feb. 28, 2008). cited by other . | Defendants' Invalidity Contentions, Civil Action No. 1:04-cv-03711-JTC, United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Sep. 28, 2005). cited by other . | Plantiff's Second Motion for Additional Findings and Conclusions Non-Enablement of Defendants' Prior Art Reference, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711 JTC, in the United States District for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Jul. 23, 2010). cited by other . | Plaintiff's Reply Brief in Support of its Alternative Motions for Reconsideration, New Trial, or to Alter or Amend the Court's Findings of Fact or Judgment, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711 JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Aug. 16, 2010). cited by other . | Defendants' Amendment to Expert Report of Peter Adriaens, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711 JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Apr. 2, 2008). cited by other . | Expert Report of James L. Brickell, PhD, P.E. In Response to Initial Expert Report of Peter Adriaens, Civil Case No: 1:04-CV-3711-JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Sep. 22, 2008). cited by other . | Defendants' Second Amended Invalidity Contentions, Civil Action No. 1:04-CV-3711 JTC, in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia Atlanta Division (Oct. 19, 2005). cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		27
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5265633 | US3846615 | EP0588282 | WO19949216314 | EP0309432
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		5
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		ZYMO INTERNATIONAL, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		ZYMO INTERNATIONAL, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Fleming Island, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Fleming Island, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		MCCLURE, JAMES, C. | MCNALLY, THOMAS, W.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		MCCLURE, JAMES, C.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Norcross, GA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Norcross, GA | Norcross, GA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		DUANE MORRIS LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		STINSON, FRANKIE L
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

