<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7967992
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11339106
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Method and device incorporating granular particles and disc-shaped plastic pellets for filtering water
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A novel water flow facilitator for granular filter devices that operate under gravity and contain granular particles, further consisting of plastic pellets that are 2 to 100 times, preferably 5 to 20 times larger than the granular particles; the plastic pellets having an aspect ratio of 0.5 to 10, preferably 1 to 4; that comprise about 1 to 50%, preferably 5 to 15% of the weight of the filter media; that have a specific gravity of 0.5 to 2, preferably 0.9 to 1.5. The plastic pellets should contain antimicrobial agents that protect the granular media from microbiological growth. The plastic pellets are made from any of the following plastics: polyolefins, various kinds of polyacrylates, polyvinyl polymers, nylon, polycarbonates etc. The plastic pellets may contain fillers such as calcium carbonate, titania, silica, or alumina. The invented flow facilitator is utilized in a gravity fed granular filter device to remove contaminants such as chlorine, taste and odor-causing compounds, solvents, pesticides, dissolved organic impurities, dissolved heavy metals and non-metallic impurities such as perchlorates. The invented flow facilitator is utilized in a gravity fed granular filter device in which the media consists of activated carbon, synthetic ion exchange resins, silica, alumina, titania, green sands, iron oxides or mixtures thereof.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2006-01-25
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2006
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2006-01
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-06-28
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-06
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01D24/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01D24/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01D24
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/263 | 210/807
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/263
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6171496 | US4563161 | US3876546 | US6319400 | US4407865 | JP1999116731
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		6
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		RICURA TECHNOLOGIES, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		RICURA TECHNOLOGIES, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Hickory, NC
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Hickory, NC
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		PATIL, ARVIND, S. | CUEMAN, GLENN, F.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		PATIL, ARVIND, S.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Davidson, NC
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Davidson, NC | Huntersville, NC
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		CLEMENTS BERNARD PLLC CLEMENTS, GREGORY N.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		SAVAGE, MATTHEW O
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

