<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7943049
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11934932
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Water purification method using plant molecules
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Arsenic is a poisonous metalloid which, because of its hydroscopic nature, is primarily transported through water. Most plant species, including the nopal cactus, produce a sticky substance called mucilage. Mucilage swells in water but is insoluble and can precipitate ions, bacteria and particles from aqueous solutions. The invention includes a method of separating particulates and heavy metals such as arsenic (As) from drinking water using natural flocculants obtained from cactus mucilage. The extraction techniques and the methodology for using the cactus mucilage obtain higher As removal than conventional methods, like aluminum sulfate precipitation.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2007-11-05
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2007
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2007-11
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-05-17
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-05
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F1/62 | C02F1/54
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F1/62
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/912 | 210/911 | 210/728 | 210/730
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/912
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Garg et al., Toxicity and Accumulation of Chromium in Ceratophyllum Demersum L, Bulletin of Environmental Contamination and Toxicology (USA), 1990, vol. 44, No. 3, pp. 473-478. cited by other . | Larsen et al., The Effect of Calcium Ions on Adhesion and Competitive Exclusion of Lactobacillus ssp. And E. Coli O138, International Journal of Food Microbiology, 2007, vol. 114, pp. 113-119. cited by other . | Bacterial Water Quality Standards for Recreational Waters (Freshwater and Marine Waters Status Report), U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Jun. 2003, pp. 1-4. cited by other . | Curtis et al., Review: Domestic Hygiene and Diarrhoea--Pinpointing the Problem, Tropical Medicine and International Health, 2000, vol. 5, No. 1, pp. 22-32. cited by other . | Griffith, The Origins of an Important Cactus Crop, Opuntia Ficus-Indica (Cactaceae): New Molecular Evidence, American Journal of Botany, 2004, vol. 91, No. 11, pp. 1915-1921. cited by other . | Tu, S.; Ma, L.Q.; Fayiga, A.O.; Zillioux, E.J. 2004. Phytoremediation of Arsenic-Contaminated Groundwater by the Arsenic Hyperaccumulating fern Pteris vittata L. Int. J. Phytoremediation. 6: 35-47. cited by other . | Human Development Report 2006, Beyond Scarcity: Power, Poverty and the Global Water Crisis, United Nations Development Programme, New York, NY, 2006, pp. 2-3. cited by other . | Human Development Report 2003, Millennium Development Goals: A Compact Among Nations to End Human Poverty, United Nations Development Programme: New York, NY, 2003, pp. 17, 35, 61, 89-91, 103-107, 123-125, and 136-143. cited by other. | Unger et al., Assessing Escherichia Coli Removal in the Schmutzdecke of Slow-Rate Biofilters, Journal AWWA, 2008, vol. 100, No. 12, pp. 60-74. cited by other . | Robinson, B.; Duwig, C.; Bolan, N.; Kannathasan, M.; Saravanan, A. 1990. Toxicity and Accumulation of Chromium in Ceratophyllum demersum L. Bull. Environ. Contam. Toxicol. 44: 473-478. cited by other . | Mintz et al., Not Just a Drop in the Bucket: Expanding Access to Point-of-Use Water Treatment Systems, American Journal of Public Health, 2001, vol. 91, No. 10, pp. 1565-1570. cited by other . | Goycoolea et al., Pectins from Opuntia spp.: A Short Review, Journal of the Porfessional Association for Cactus Development, 2003, vol. 5, pp. 17-29. cited by other . | Zita et al., Effefcts of Ionic Strength on bacterial Adhesion and Stability of Flocs in a Wastewater Activated Sludge System, Applied and Environmental Microbiology, 1994, vol. 60, No. 9, pp. 3041-3048. cited by other . | Zhang, W.; Cai, Y.; Tu, C.; Ma, L.Q. 2002. Arsenic speciation and distribution in an arsenic hyperaccumulating plant. Science of the Total Environment. 300: 167-177. cited by other . | Hrudey et al., Published Case Studies of Waterborne Disease Outbreaks-Evidence of a Recurrent Treat, Water Environment Research, 2007, vol. 79, pp. 233-245. cited by other . | Miller et al., Toward Understanding the Efficacy and Mechanism of Opuntia spp. as a Natural Coagulant for Potential Application in Water Treatment, Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 2008, vol. 42, No. 12, pp. 4274-4279. cited by other . | Davis, T.A.; Ali, F.E.C.; Giannitti, E.; Volesky, B.; Mucci, A. 2004. Cadmium biosorption by S-fluitans: Treatment, resilience and uptake relative to other Sargassum spp. and brown algae. Water Quality Research Journal of Canada. 39: 183-189. cited by other . | The Millennium Development Goals Report 2007, United Nations, New York, 2007, pp. 23-26. cited by other . | Sen, A.K.; Mondal, N.G. 1990. Removal and uptake of Copper(II) by Salvinia natus from waste water. Air and Soil Pollution WAPLAC. 49: 1-6. cited by other . | Medina-Torres et al., Rheological Properties of the Mucilage Gum (Opuntia Ficus Indica), Food Hydrocolloids, 2000, vol. 14, pp. 417-424. cited by other . | Zimmels, Y.; Kirzhner, F.; Roitman, S. 2004. Use of naturally growing aquatic plants for wastewater purification. Water Environment Research. 76: 220-230. cited by other . | Misbahuddin, M.; Fariduddin, A. 2002. Water hyacinth removes arsenic from arsenic-contaminated drinking water. Arch. Environ. Health. 57: 516-518. cited by other . | Cunningham, Cactus Goo Purifies Water, Science News, 2005, pp. 1-2. cited by other . | Quick et al., Diarrhoea Prevention in Bolivia through Point-of-Use Water Treatment and Safe Storage: a Promising New Strategy, Epidemiol. Infect., 1999, vol. 122, pp. 83-60. cited by other . | Robinson, B.; Duwig, C.; Bolan, N.; Kannathasan, M.; Saravanan, A. 2003. Uptake of Arsenic by New Zealand watercress (Lepidium sativum). Science of the Total Environment. 301: 67-73. cited by other . | Sanin et al., Bioflocculation of Activated Sludge: The Role of Calcium Ions and Extracellular Polymers, Environmental Technology, 2000, vol. 21, No. 12, pp. 1405-1412. cited by other . | Young, The Mucilage of Opuntia Ficus Indica: a Natural, Sustainable, and Viable Water Treatment Technology for Use in Rural Mexico for Reducing Turbidity and Arsenic Contamination in Drinking Water, College of Engineering, University of South Florida, 2006, pp. 52-57 and pp. 62-69. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		27
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US7455863 | US5851398 | US7014776 | US5853576 | US5876484 | US20040197812 | US2117378 | US20050198707 | US2845363 | US6974896 | US6576816 | US5000857
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		12
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH FLORIDA
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH FLORIDA
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Tampa, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Tampa, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		ALCANTAR, NORMA, A. | JOSEPH, BABU | YOUNG, KEVIN
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		ALCANTAR, NORMA, A.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Tampa, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Tampa, FL | Tampa, FL | Plant, City, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		VARKONYI, ROBERT SMITH &amp; HOPEN, P.A.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		HRUSKOCI, PETER A
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

