<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7914685
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12794198
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Rocks and aggregate, and methods of making and using the same
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Compositions comprising synthetic rock, e.g., aggregate, and methods of producing and using them are provided. The rock, e.g., aggregate, contains CO.sub.2 and/or other components of an industrial waste stream. The CO.sub.2 may be in the form of divalent cation carbonates, e.g., magnesium and calcium carbonates. Aspects of the invention include contacting a CO.sub.2 containing gaseous stream with a water to dissolve CO.sub.2, and placing the water under precipitation conditions sufficient to produce a carbonate containing precipitate product, e.g., a divalent cation carbonate.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2010-06-04
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2010-06
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-03-29
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-03
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F1/52
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F1/52
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		106/738 | 95/149 | 423/220 | 106/817 | 95/241 | 210/749 | 106/463 | 210/737 | 106/464 | 423/420.2 | 95/156 | 423/419.1 | 210/702 | 423/430
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		106/738
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		106
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Kohlmann et al., &quot;Carbon Dioxide Emission Control by Mineral Carbonation: The Option for Finland&quot;; INFUB 6th European Conference on Industrial Furnaces and Boilers Estoril Lisbon Portugal, Apr. 2-5, 2002 10pp. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Feb. 2, 2010 of PCT/US09/059141. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Oct. 30, 2009 of PCT/US09/056573. cited by other . | Turner, J.A. 1999. &quot;A Realizable Renewable Energy Future.&quot; Science. 285 (5428): 687-689. cited by other . | Bond, G.M., et al. 2002. Brines as possible cation sources for biomimetic carbon dioxide sequestration. American Geophysical Union Abstract #U22A-07. cited by other . | Faverjon, F. et al. 2006. Regeneration of hydrochloric acid and sodium hydroxide from purified sodium chloride by membrane electrolysis using a hydrogen diffusion anode-membrane assembly. Journal of Membrane Science 284 (1-2): 323-330. cited by other . | Avery, G.B. et al. 2006. Carbon isotopic characterization of dissolved organic carbon in rainwater. Terrestrial and marine influences. Science Direct. 40(39): 7539-7545. Retrieved from the internet on May 20, 2010. cited by other . | Graff &quot;Just Catch--CO2 Capture Technology&quot; Aker Kvaerner; Pareto Clean Energy Tech Seminar Oct. 11, 2007 25pp. cited by other . | Nayak, V.S. &quot;Nonelectrolytic Production of Caustic Soda and Hydrochloric Acid from Sodium Chloride&quot;; Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 1996. 35: 3808-3811. cited by other . | Carbon Sequestration. National Energy Technology Laboratory, Jul. 1, 2008 (online) [retrieved on Dec. 21, 2009] &lt;URL: http://web.archive.org/web/20080701213124/http://www.netl.doe.gov/technol- ogies/carbon.sub.--seq/index.html&gt;. cited by other . | Wang, W., et al. 2005. Effects of biodegradation on the carbon isotopic composition of natural gas--A case study in the bamianhe oil field of the Jiyang Depression, Eastern China. Geochemical Journal. 39(4): 301-309. (abstract) [online] [retrieved on Feb. 29, 2009] &lt;URL: http://www/jstage.jst.go.jp/article/geochemj/39/4/39.sub.--301/.sub.--art- icle&gt; ab. cited by other . | Rosenthal, E., &quot;Cement Industry is at Center of Climate Change Debate&quot; New York Times; www.nytimes.com/2007/10/26/business/worldbusiness/26cement.htmlref=todays- paper; 4pp. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Mar. 10, 2010 of PCT/US10/022935. cited by other . | Filley, T.R. et al. 1997. Application of Isotope-Ratio-Monitoring Gas Chromatography/Mass Spectrometry to Study Carbonization Reactions of FCCU Slurry Oils. Department of Geosciences, Department of Materials Science and Engineering, The Pennsylvania State University, University Park, PA. Abstracts of Papers of the American Chemical Society. 214:65-FUEL Part 1. pp. 938-941. cited by other . | Vagin, S.P., et al. 1979. Measurement of the Temperature of Gas Media Containing Carbon Dioxide by the Laser-Probing Method. Plenum. cited by other . | Saad, N. et al. 2009. Measurement of Isotopic CO2 in Dissolved Inorganic Carbons of Water Samples from Various Origins Using Wavelength-Scanned Cavity Ring-Down Spectrophotometer. Geophysical Research Abstracts. 11. (abstract only). cited by other . | Faverjon, F. et al. 2005. Electrochemical study of a hydrogen diffusion anode-membrane assembly for membrane electrolysis. Electrochimica Acta 51 (3): 386-394. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/163,205, filed Jun. 27, 2008, Constantz, Brent R., et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Mar. 1, 2010. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Sep. 17, 2008 of PCT/US2008/068564. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/501,217, filed Jul. 10, 2009, Constantz Brent. et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Mar. 12, 2010. cited by other . | Lackner, K.S. et al. &quot;Carbon Dioxide Disposal in Carbonate Minerals.&quot; Energy. 1995. 20(11): 1153-1170. cited by other . | Huijgen, W.J.J., et al. 2003. Carbon dioxide sequestration by mineral carbonation. ECN-C-03-016; Energy Research Centre of the Netherlands: Petten; pp. 1-42. cited by other . | Huntzinger, D.N. et al.,&quot;Carbon Dioxide Sequestration in Cement Kiln Dust through Mineral Carbonation&quot;; Environmental Science &amp; Technology, vol. 43, No. 6 (2009) pp. 1986-1992. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/557,492, filed Sep. 10, 2009, Constantz, Brent R., et al. Non-Final Office Action dated May 6, 2010. cited by other . | Huijgen, W.J.J., et al. 2005. Carbon dioxide sequestration by mineral carbonation: Literature review update 2003-2004, ECN-C-05-022; Energy Research Centre of the Netherlands: Petten; pp. 1-37. cited by other . | Wilson, S.A., et al. 2009. Carbon Dioxide Fixation within Mine Wastes of Ultramafic-Hosted Ore Deposits: Examples from the Clinton Creek and Cassiar Chrysotile Deposits, Canada. Society of Economic Geologists, Inc. 104: 95-112. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Jan. 4, 2010 of PCT/US09/062795. cited by other . | Gain, E. et al. 2002. Ammonium nitrate wastewater treatment by coupled membrane electrolysis and electrodialysis. Journal of Applied Electrochemistry 32: 969-975. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/163,205, filed Jun. 27, 2008, Constantz, Brent R., et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Jan. 27, 2010. cited by other . | Horner, G. et al. 2004. Isotope selective analysis of CO2 with tunable diode laser (TDL) spectroscopy in the NIR. The Analyst. 129: 772-778. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/126,776, filed May 23, 2008, Constantz, Brent R., et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Feb. 25, 2010; 21 pp. cited by other . | Lackner, K. &quot;Carbonate Chemistry for Sequestering Fossil Carbon&quot;; Annual Review Energy Environ. 2002 27:193-232. cited by other . | Sasakawa, M., et al. Carbonic Isotopic Characterization for the Origin of Excess Methane in Subsurface Seawater. Journal of Geophysical Research, vol. 113 (abstract) [online], Mar. 11, 2008 [retrieved on Jan. 1, 2010] &lt;URL: http://www.agu.org/pubs/crossref/2008/2007JC004217.shtml&gt;. cited by other . | Horkel, K., et al. 2009. Stable isotopic composition of cryptocrystalline magnesite from deposits in Turkey and Austria. Geophysical Research Abstracts. 11. (abstract only). cited by other . | Philp, R.P. 2007. The emergence of stable isotopes in environmental and forensic geochemistry studies: a review. Environ Chem Lett. 5:57-66. cited by other . | Miljevic, N., et al. 2007. Potential Use of Environmental Isotopes in Pollutant Migration Studies. Environmental Isotopes in Pollutant Studies. 58: 251-262. cited by other . | Winschel, R.A., et al. Stable Carbon Isotope Analysis of Coal/Petroleum Coprocessing Products. Preprints of Papers, American Chemical Society, Division of Fuel Chemistry, Jan. 1, 1988, vol. 33, No. 1, pp. 114-121 [online], [retrieved on Dec. 29, 2009] &lt;URL: http://www.anl.gov/PCS/acsfuel/preprint%/20archive/Files/33.sub.--1.sub.-- -TORONTO.sub.--06-88.sub.--0114.PDF&gt;. cited by other . | Raz et al., &quot;Formation of High-Magnesium Calcites via an Amorphous Precursor Phase: Possible Biological Implications&quot;; Advanced Materials; Adv. Mater. (2000) vol. 12, No. 1; 5pp. cited by other . | Mihalcea, R.M., et al. 1998. Diode-laser absorption measurements of CO2 near 2.0 .mu.m at elevated temperatures. Applied Optics. 37(36): 8341-8347. cited by other . | Bond, G.M., et al. 2001. CO2 Capture from Coal-Fired Utility Generation Plant Exhausts, and Sequestration by a Biomimetic Route Based on Enzymatic Catalysis--Current Status (paper presented at the First National Conference on Carbon Sequestration, May 14-17, in Washington D.C., USA; Paper Sa.5. cited by other . | Aker, &quot;Aker Clean Carbon, Carbon Capture Solutions Provider&quot; Aker Clean Carbon Presentation for UN's IPCC; Jan. 24, 2008; 8pp. cited by other . | Biennier, L., et al. 2004. Multiplex integrated cavity output spectroscopy of cold PAH cations. Chemical Physics Letters. 387: 287-294. cited by other . | Mottana, A. et al. 1979. Der grosse Mineralienfuhrer, BLV Verlagsgese11schaft mbH, Munchen, XP002577921, p. 194. (In German with English Translation). cited by other . | O'Connor et al., &quot;Carbon Dioxide Sequestration By Direct Mineral Carbonation: Results From Recent Studies And Curent Status&quot;; Albany Research Center, Albany Oregon; Office of Fossil Energy, US Dept. of Energy; 1st Annual DOE Carbon Sequestration Conference, Washington DC, May 2001 12pp. cited by other . | Sheppard, S.M.F., et al. 1970. Fractionation of Carbon and Oxygen Isotopes and Magnesium between Coexisting Metamorphic Calcite and Dolomite. Contr. Mineral. And Petrol. 26. 161-198. cited by other . | Mook, W.G., et al. 1968. Isotopic Equilibrium between Shells and Their Environment. Science. 159(3817): 874-875. cited by other . | Fallick, A.E., et al. 1991. A Stable Isotope Study of the Magnesite Deposits Associated with the Alpine-Type Ultramafic Rocks of Yugoslavia. Economic Geology. 86: 847-861. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Aug. 5, 2009 of PCT/2009/048511. cited by other . | Cannell, M.G.R. 2003. &quot;Carbon sequestration and biomass energy offset: theoretical, potential and achievable capacities globally, in Europe and the UK.&quot; Biomass and Bioenergy. 24: 97-116. cited by other . | Criss, R.E. 1995. Stable Isotope Distribution: Variations from Temperature, Organic and Water-Rock Interactions. Washington University, St. Lous, Department of Earch and Planetary Sciences. American Geophysical Union. pp. 292-307. cited by other . | Christensen, L.E., et al. Measurement of Sulfur Isotope Compositions by Tunable Laser Spectroscopy of SO2. Analytical Chemistry, Nov. 17, 2007, vol. 79, No. 24, pp. 9261-9268 (abstract) [online] [retrieved on Dec. 30, 2009] &lt;URL: http://pubs.acs.org/doi/abs/10.1021/ac071040p&gt;. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Mar. 11, 2009 of PCT/2008/088246. cited by other . | O'Connor, W.K. et al. &quot;Carbon dioxide sequestration: Aqueous mineral carbonation studies using olivine and serpentine.&quot; 2001. Albany Research Center, National Engery Technology Laboratory: Mineral Carbonation Workshop, Pittsburgh, PA. cited by other . | Rakib, M. et al. 1999. Behaviour of Nafion.RTM. 350 membrane in sodium sulfate electrochemical splitting: continous process modelling and pilot scale tests. Journal of Applied Electrochemistry. 29: 1439-1448. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/375,632, filed Mar. 5, 2009, Kirk, Donald W. et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Mar. 19, 2010. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Feb. 19, 2009 of PCT/US08/88242. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Mar. 3, 2010 of EP08867440.3. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/475,378, filed May 29, 2009, Constantz Brent. et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Mar. 2, 2010. cited by other . | Sadhwani et al., &quot;Case Studies on environmental impact of seawater desalination&quot; Science Direct; http://www.sciencedirect.com/science?.sub.--ob=ArticleURL&amp;.sub.--udi=B6TF- X-4HMX97J-3&amp;.sub.--u... 3pp. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/475,378, filed May 29, 2009, Constantz Brent. et al, Final Office Action dated May 5, 2010. cited by other . | Uliasz-Bochenczyk, A. et al. &quot;Utilization of Carbon Dioxide in Fly Ash and Water Mixtures.&quot; Chemical Engineering Research and Design. 2006. 84(A9): 843-846. cited by other . | Schouten, S., et al. 2004. Stable Carbon Isotopic Fractionations Associated with Inorganic Carbon Fixation by Anaerobic Ammonium-Oxidizing Bacteria. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 70(6): 3785-3788. cited by other . | Hill et al. Mar. 18, 2006. &quot;Preliminary Investigation of Carbon Sequestration Potential in Brine from Pennsylvanis's Oriskany Sandstone Formation in Indiana County, PA&quot;; The Energy Institute and the Department of Energy &amp; Geo-Environmental Engineering. College of Engineering Research Symposium, Session 3C. 16pp. cited by other . | Goldberg et al. Jun. 2009. &quot;CO2 Mineral Sequestration Studies in US&quot;; National Energy Technology Laboratory; goldberg@netl.doe.gov; 10pp. cited by other . | Lin, C. et al. Use of Cement Kiln Dust, Fly Ash, and Recycling Technique in Low-Volume Road Rehabilitation. Transportation Research Record, 1992, No. 1345, pp. 19-27 (abstract) [online], [retrieved on Dec. 31, 2009] &lt;URL: http://pubsindex.trb.org/view.aspx?id=370714&gt;. cited by other . | Schwab, E. 2004. Calciumhydroxid, XP-002577920. Retrieved from the Internet: &lt;URL:http://www.roempp.com/prod/index1.html&gt; (In German with English Translation). cited by other . | Sial, A.N., et al. 2000. Carbon isotope fluctuations in Precambrian carbonate sequences of several localities in Brazil. An. Acad. Bras. Ci. 72(4): 539-558. cited by other . | CICCS &quot;Aims and Research&quot;; www.nottingham.ac.uk/carbonmanagement/ccs.sub.--aims.php 2pp Aug. 3, 2007. cited by other . | International Search Report dated May 6, 2010 of EP09716193.9. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/486,692, filed Jun. 17, 2009, Constantz Brent. et al, Final Office Action dated May 3, 2010. cited by other . | Uibu, M. et al.,&quot;Mineral trapping of CO2 via oil shale ash aqueous carbonation: controlling mechanism of process rate and development of continuous-flow reactor system.&quot; Oil Shale vol. 26, No. 1 (2009) pp. 40-58. cited by other . | Haywood et al., &quot;Carbon dioxide sequestration as stable carbonate minerals--environmental barriers&quot;; Environmental Geology (2001) 41:11-16; Springer-Verlag 2001. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Sep. 8, 2009 of PCT/US2009/045722. cited by other . | &quot;Biomass Burning: A Hot Issue in Global Change.&quot; National Aeronautics and Space Administration. Langley Research Center, Hampton, Virginia. Fact Sheet FS-2001-02-56-LaRC. Feb. 2001. 4 pages. cited by other . | Serizawa et al., &quot;Cell-compatible properties of calcium carbonates and hydroxyapatite deposited on ultrathin poly (vinly alcohol)-coated polyethylene films&quot;; J. Biomater. Sci. Polymer Edn., vol. 14, No. 7 (2003) pp. 653-663. cited by other . | Wen-Zhi et al., &quot;Using Electrolytic Method to Promote CO2 Sequestration in Serpentine by Mineral Carbonation&quot;; Journal of China University of Mining and Technology; vol. 36, No. 6; Nov. 2007 (Publication and English Translation). cited by other . | Justnes, H. et al. &quot;Pozzolanic, Amorphous Silica Produced from the Mineral Olivine.&quot; Proceedings of the Seventh CANMET/ACI International Conference on Fly Ash, Silica Fume, Slag And Natural Pozzolans in Concrete, 2001. SP-199-44. pp. 769-781. cited by other . | Park, A., et al. 2004. CO2 mineral sequestration: physically activated dissolution of serpentine and pH swing process. Chemical Engineering Science 59 (22-23): 5241-5247. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Jan. 13, 2010 of PCT/US09/059135. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Sep. 22, 2009 of PCT/US2009/047711. cited by other . | Rahardianto et al., &quot;High recovery membrane desalting of low-salinity brackish water: Integration of accelerated precipitation softening with membrane RO&quot;; Science Diret; Journal of Membrane Science 289 (2007) 123-137. cited by other . | Rau, G. 2004. Possible use of Fe/CO2 fuel cells for CO2 mitigation plus H2 and electricity production. Energy Conversion and Management. 45: 2143-2152. cited by other . | Noda, H., et al. 1990. Electrochemical Reduction of Carbon Dioxide at Various Metal Electrodes in Aqueous Potassim Hydrogen Carbonate Solution. The Chemical Society of Japan. 63: 2459-2462. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Dec. 14, 2009 of PCT/US09/061748. cited by other . | Wright, L.L., et al. 1993. &quot;U.S. Carbon Offset Potential Using Biomass Energy Systems.&quot; Water, Air, and Soil Pollution. 70: 483-497. cited by other . | Zedef, V., et al. 2000. Genesis of Vein Stockwork and Sedimentary Magnesite and Hydromagnesite Deposits in the Ultramafic Terranes of Southwestern Turkey: A Stable Isotope Study. 95: 429-446. cited by other. | Mook, W.G., et al. 1974. Carbon Isotope Fractionation Between Dissolved Bicarbonate and Gaseous Carbon Dioxide. 22:169-176. cited by other . | Huntzinger, D.N. et al. 2009. A life-cycle assessment of Portland cement manufacturing: comparing the traditional process with alternative technologies. Journal of Cleaner Production. 17: 668-675. cited by other . | Green Car Congress &quot;Researcher Proposes System for Capture of Mobile Source CO2 Emissions Directly from Atmosphere&quot;; www.greeencarcongress.com/2007/10/researcher-prop.html#more; Oct. 8, 2007; 4pp. cited by other . | Fouke, B.W., et al. 2000. Depositional Facies and Aqueous-Solid Geochemistry of Travertine-Depositing Hot Springs (Angel Terrace, Mammoth Hot Springs, Yellowstone National Park, U.S.A.). Journal of Sedimentary Research. 70(3): 565-585. cited by other . | Montes-Hernandez, G. et al.,&quot;Mineral sequestration of CO2 by aqueous carbonation of coal combustion fly-ash.&quot; Journal of Hazardous Materials vol. 161 (2009). pp. 1347-1354. cited by other . | McCrea, J.M. 1950. On the Isotopic Chemistry of Carbonates and a Paleotemperature Scale. The Journal of Chemical Physics. 18(6): 849-857. cited by other . | Mazrou, S., et al. 1997. Sodium hydroxide and hydrochloric acid generation from sodium chloride and rock salt by electro-electrodialysis. Journal of Applied Electrochemistry 27: 558-567. cited by other . | Huntzinger, D.N. Carbon Dioxide Sequestration in Cement Kiln Dust Through Mineral Carbonation. Michigan Technological University, 2006 [online], [retrieved on Dec. 29, 2009]. &lt;URL: http://www.geo.mtu.edu/.about.dnhuntzi/DNHuntzingerETD.pdf&gt;. cited by other . | Berg et al., &quot;A 3-Hydroxyproprionate/ 4-Hydroxybutyrate Autotrophic Carbon Dioxide Assimilation Pathway in Archea&quot;; Science 14, Dec. 2007; vol. 318, No. 5857 DOI 10.1126/science 1149976; pp. 1782-1786. cited by other . | Uibu, M. et al. &quot;CO2 mineral sequestration in oil-shale wastes from Estonian power production.&quot; Journal of Environmental Management vol. 90 (2009). pp. 1253-1260. cited by other . | &quot;Isotopic Signature&quot;, Wikipedia (2010), http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isotopic.sub.--signature, Apr. 14, 2009, 3 pp. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/475,378, filed May 29, 2009, Constantz Brent. et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Mar. 17, 2010. cited by other . | Bottomley, D.J. et al. 1999. The origin and evolution of Canadian Shield brines: evaporation or freezing of seawater? New lithium isotope and geochemical evidence from the Slave craton. Chemical Geology. 155: 295-320. cited by other . | Power, I.M., et al. 2007. Biologically induced mineralization of dypingite by cyanobacteria from an alkaline wetland near Atlin, British Columbia, Canada. Geochemical Transactions. 8: 16 pages. cited by other . | Baer, D.S., et al. 2002. Sensitive absorption measurements in the near-infrared region using off-axis integrated-cavity-output spectroscopy. Appl. Phys. B. 5 pages. cited by other . | Dickens, A. et al. 2004. Reburial of fossil organic carbon in marine sediments. Nature. 427: 336-339. Retrieved from the internet on May 20, 2010. cited by other . | O'Neil, J.R., et al. 1971. C13 and O18 compositions in some fresh-water carbonates associated with ultramafic rocks and serpentines: western United State*. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta. 35: 687-697. cited by other . | Green Car Congress &quot;PKU Researchers Carry Out Aqueous Fischer-Tropsch Reaction for First Time&quot;; www.greencarcongress.com/2007/12/pku-researchers.html; Dec. 12, 2007; 2pp. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/486,692, filed Jun. 17, 2009, Constantz Brent. et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Mar. 23, 2010. cited by other . | Schroll, E. 2002. Genesis of magnesite deposits in the view of isotope geochemistry. Boletim Paranaense de Geociencias. 50: 59-68. cited by other . | Faure, et al. 1963. The Isotopic Composition of Strontium in Oceanic and Continental Basalts: Application to the Origin of Igneous Rocks. Journal of Petrology. 4(1): 31-50. (abstract only). Http://petrology.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/abstract/4/1/31 (retrieved on Jun. 1, 2010). cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/604,383, filed Oct. 22, 2009, Constantz Brent R. et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Apr. 5, 2010. cited by other . | Webber, M.E., et al. 2001. In situ combustion measurements of CO2 by use of a distributed-feedback diode-laser sensor near 2.0 .mu.m. Applied Optics. 40(6): 821-828. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/571,398, filed Sep. 30, 2009, Constantz Brent R. et al, Non-Final Office Action dated May 3, 2010. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Oct. 19, 2009 of PCT/US2009/050223. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Mar. 11, 2009 of PCT/US2008/088318. cited by other . | Elswick, E.R., et al. 2007. Sulfur and carbon isotope geochemistry of coal and derived coal-combustion by-products: An example from an Eastern Kentucky mine and power plant. Applied Geochemistry. 22: 2065-2077. cited by other . | Cerling, T.E. 1984. The stable isotopic composition of modern soil carbonate and its relationship to climate. Earth and Planetary Science Letters. 71: 229-240. cited by other . | Sethi, S. et al. 2006. Existing &amp; Emerging Concentrate Minimization &amp; Disposal Practices for Membrane Systems. Florida Water Resources Journal. pp. 38, 40, 42, 44, 46, 48. cited by other . | Melezhik, V.A., et al. 2001. Palaeproterozoic magnesite: lithological and isotopic evidence for playa/sabkha environments. Sedimentology. 48: 379-397. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/486,692, filed Jun. 17, 2009, Constantz Brent. et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Mar. 1, 2010. cited by other . | Genders, D. 1995. Electrochemical Salt Splitting http://www.electrosynthesis.com/news/mwatts.html (accessed Feb. 5, 2009). cited by other . | Holze, S. et al. 1994. Hydrogen Consuming Anodes for Energy Saving in Sodium Sulphate Electrolysis. Chem. Eng. Technol. 17: 382-389. cited by other . | Tececo Pty Ltd, &quot;Eco-Cement&quot;; www.tececo.com/simple.eco-cement.php; Dec. 29, 2008; 6pp. cited by other . | Levy, D. &quot;Burnt biomass causes short-term global cooling, long-term warming.&quot; http://news-service.stanford.edu/news/2004/august4/biomass-84.h- tml. 3 pages. cited by other . | Quay, P.D., et al. 1992. Oceanic Uptake of Fossil Fuel CO$.sub.--2$: Carbon- 13 Evidence. Science. 256 (5053): 74-79. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/375,632, filed Mar. 5, 2009, Kirk, Donald W. et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Sep. 8, 2009. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/344,019, filed Dec. 24, 2008, Constantz, Brent R., et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Nov. 16, 2009. cited by other . | Biello, D. Cement from CO2: A Concrete Cure for Global Warming? Scientific American Aug. 7, 2008., pp. 1-3 [online] [retrieved on Dec. 29, 2009] &lt;URL: http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm&gt;. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/163,205, filed Jun. 27, 2008, Constantz, Brent R., et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Mar. 25, 2010. cited by other . | &quot;Electrochemical cell&quot;, Wikipedia (2009), http:en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electrochemical.sub.--Cell, Nov. 24, 2009, 5 pp. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/609,491, filed Oct. 30, 2009, Constantz Brent. et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Mar. 31, 2010. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Sep. 17, 2009 of PCT/US2009/050756. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/344,019, filed Dec. 24, 2008, Constantz, Brent R., et al, Non-Final Office Action dated Mar. 11, 2010. cited by other . | Allen, L.M. 1992. Boron and Sulfur Isotopic Fractionation in the Coal Combustion System. A Thesis Submitted to the Faculty of the Department of Hydrology and Water Resources. The University of Arizona. cited by other . | Shell Global Solutions, 2003. &quot;ADIP-X and Sulfinol-X--new regenerable acid-gas removal processes&quot;; Shell Global Solutions International; OG 130210370903-En(A); www.shellglobalsoultions.com 2 pp (presented at the 12th International Oil, Gas, and Petrochemicals Congress, Tehran, Iran Feb. 24-26, 2003). cited by other . | Druckenmiller et al., &quot;Carbon sequestration using brine of adjusted pH to form mineral carbonates&quot;; Elsevier; www.elsevier.com/locate/fuproc; Fuel Processing Technology 86 (2005) 1599-1614. cited by other . | Holdgate, G.R., et al. 2009. Eocene-Miocene carbon-isotope and floral record from brown coal seams in the Gippsland Basin of southest Australia. Global and Planetary Change. 65: 89-103. cited by other . | Portier et al. 2005. Modelling CO2 solubility in pure water and NaCI-type waters from 0 to 300.degree. C. and from 1 to 300 bar Application to the Utsira Formation at Sleipner. Chemical Geology. 217: 187-199. cited by other . | Huijgen, W.J.J., et al. 2006. Energy Consumption and Net CO2 Sequestration of Aqueous Mineral Carbonation. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 45: 9184-9194. cited by other . | Stanley, S.M., et al. 2002. Low-magnesium calcite produced by coralline algae in seawater of Late Cretaceous composition. PNAS. 99(24): 15323-15326. cited by other . | Green Car Congress &quot;Researchers Develop New Method for Ocean Sequestration of Carbon Dioxide Through Accelerated Weathering f Volcanic Rocks&quot;; www.greeencarcongress.com/2007/11/researchers-dev.html#more; Nov. 7, 2007; 3pp. cited by other . | Huijgen, W.J.J., et al. 2005. Mineral CO2 Sequestration by Steel Slag Carbonation. Environ. Sci. Technol. 39: 9676-9682. cited by other . | Back, M. et al.,&quot;Reactivity of Alkaline Lignite Fly Ashes Towards CO in Water.&quot; Environmental Science &amp; Technology. vol. 42, No. 12 (2008) pp. 4520-4526. cited by other . | Alexander, G. et al., &quot;Evaluation of reaction variables in the dissolution of serpentine for mineral carbonation&quot;; Elsevier; ScienceDirect Fuel 86 (2007) 273-281. cited by other . | Ehleringer, J.R., et al. 2002. Stable Isotopes. vol. 2, The Earth System: biological and ecological dimensions of global environmental change. pp. 544-550. Edited by Professor Harold A. Mooney and Dr. Joseph G. Canadell in Encyclopedia of Global Environment Change. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd. Chichester. cited by other . | International Search Report dated Feb. 24, 2010 of PCT/US09/067764. cited by other . | International Search Report dated May 21, 2010 of PCT/US09/064117. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		144
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US4107022 | US20060165583 | US20050031522 | US2329940 | US6090197 | US3374164 | US20060169593 | US6190428 | US20040231568 | US3511712 | US3686372 | US5037286 | US20050180910 | US3917795 | US6786963 | US3558769 | US20060185985 | US20050154669 | US7132090 | US4838941 | US4410606 | US20090214408 | US7452449 | US6936573 | US4450009 | US6264740 | US20020127474 | US20070163443 | US20090294366 | US7390444 | US6264736 | US20100024686 | US20080275149 | US5776328 | US20060169177 | US3511595 | US4140510 | US1678345 | US2934419 | US6518217 | US7135604 | US4217186 | US20100077691 | US20040267077 | US1897725 | US20060051274 | US20080138265 | US4106296 | US6638413 | US20020009410 | US3904496 | US20040111968 | US7427449 | US20080276553 | US20050087496 | US5470671 | US20070186820 | US20070148509 | US20070056487 | US3725267 | US6416574 | US20060105082 | US6248166 | US6180012 | US20050036932 | US4818367 | US4264367 | US20060185560 | US5766338 | US5766339 | US5849075 | US7255842 | US20060184445 | US5366513 | US20070202032 | US5569558 | US7040400 | US5364611 | US4308298 | US20100083880 | US3120426 | US3196092 | US5614078 | US20060288912 | US4370307 | US6071336 | US20090232861 | US20070261947 | US6387174 | US3963592 | US7440871 | US20080236143 | US4561945 | US6375825 | US7198722 | US20090186244 | US7282189 | US6217728 | US5897704 | US20040040671 | US3925534 | US20090143211 | US5785868 | US5855666 | US20090010827 | US20060060532 | US20030229572 | US6402831 | US20090169452 | US20070113500 | US20050232855 | US20050232856 | US3179579 | US6200381 | US3463814 | US20100063902 | US3202522 | US2383674 | US2606839 | US6024848 | US20040213705 | US4915914 | US20030126899 | US5362688 | US4026716 | US20080270272 | US5584923 | US4335788 | US5584926 | US20080223727 | US20060286011 | US6080297 | US20040219090 | US4477573 | US5536310 | US20080248350 | US6602630 | US4242185 | US5246551 | US3420775 | US5855759 | US20040052865 | US3627480 | US20100116683 | US6352576 | US20080277319 | US20060185516 | US20040126293 | US3574530 | US20050011770 | US3630762 | US5690729 | US3861928 | US6517631 | US20070266632 | US20090043687 | US3525675 | US20050238563 | US20030213937 | US20060196836 | US6309570 | US20010023655 | US3953568 | US20030017088 | US4620969 | US1865833 | US20060048517 | US3627479 | US4899544 | US4246075 | US7285166 | US5100633 | US20080031801 | US5624493 | US7347896 | US5388456 | US20090263301 | US5531821 | US20040224214 | US4147599 | US6890497 | US20050129606 | US5520898 | US6648949 | US20080059206 | US7595001 | US4164537 | US4716027 | US20070217981 | US5965201 | US20050255174 | US6475460 | US5925255 | US6059974 | US20070187247 | US5244304 | US20070092427 | US4253922 | US3970528 | US20100111810 | US6537456 | US20080178739 | US20090202410 | US20060173169 | US20060195002 | US5282935 | US20090090277 | US6235186 | US6200543 | US20040040715 | US7037434 | US20050118081 | US20090001020 | US7455854 | US5595641 | US20100084280 | US4188291 | US6280505 | US20080171158 | US20070045125 | US6495013 | US2304391 | US4036749 | US20030123930 | US5230734 | US20060057036 | US4128462 | US5846669 | US4931264 | US3466169 | US6776972 | US20090081093 | US20090081096 | US6129832 | US20010054253 | US20080245672 | US7314847 | US20070212584 | US6623555 | US20070240570 | US3864236 | US20100077922 | US20080289495 | US20030188668 | US2458039 | US6251356 | US6890419 | US20040259231 | US4069063 | US7261912 | US20040014845 | US4804449 | US4080270 | US7674443 | US20080245660 | US5531865 | US4376101 | US6755905 | US3350292 | US20080112868 | US20040228788 | US20100089142 | US20090020044 | US6712946 | US20090301352 | US3046152 | US6387212 | US4588443 | US2967807 | US20010022952 | US5547027 | US5702585 | US6841512 | US5803894 | US6908507 | US4361475 | US20040139891 | US20050002847 | US20040234443 | US6444107 | US20080245274 | EP0522382 | GB1392907 | WO2002000551 | EP1571105 | JP2006076825 | WO2008115662 | GB2032441 | WO2008108657 | DE3638317 | WO2010006242 | WO2008140821 | JP2005052762 | WO2010030826 | NL7607470 | JP1998305212 | WO2007001633 | WO2009070273 | CA1335974 | EP0591350 | GB911386 | WO2006036396 | WO2007142945 | WO2009032331 | WO2009049085 | WO2009039655 | WO2008068322 | EP1650162 | WO1993016216 | WO2003008071 | WO2008124538 | WO2005086843 | WO2007139392 | WO2007003013 | WO2008026201 | WO2009006295 | WO2008031834 | WO1996034997 | DE19631794 | WO2008101293 | WO2000009600 | WO2009036087 | GB2210035 | DE19512163 | AU20082008256636 | WO2007060149 | WO2008095057 | JP2004174370 | WO1994018119 | JP1995061842 | WO2008009523 | WO2010039903 | WO2007106372 | JP2003041388 | WO2004098740 | EP1379469 | WO2009024826 | EP1554031 | DE2653649 | WO2003068685 | WO1999013967 | WO2006134080 | WO2008142017 | WO2009086460 | EP0844905 | WO2007094691 | WO2009065031 | JP1976102357 | WO2007016271 | JP1984100280 | WO2007096671 | JP1991170363 | WO2008061305 | JP1988312988 | WO2001096243 | WO2008151060 | GB2371810 | WO2010039909 | EP0487102 | DE19523324 | WO2008018928 | JP1991020491 | DE3146326 | WO2009146436 | AU20072007100157 | WO2007140544 | EP1716911 | WO2004001731 | WO2006099599 | WO2007123917 | WO2007082505 | WO2001007365 | WO2003054508 | CA2646462 | WO2007106883 | WO2008142025 | WO2005108297 | WO2006034339 | WO2004094043 | JP2002273163 | EP0628339 | WO2007069902 | WO2005078836
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		383
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		CALERA CORPORATION
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		CALERA CORPORATION
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Los Gatos, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Los Gatos, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		CONSTANTZ, BRENT | YOUNGS, ANDREW | O'NEIL, JAMES | FARSAD, KASRA | PATTERSON, JOSHUA | STAGNARO, JOHN | THATCHER, RYAN | CAMIRE, CHRIS
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		CONSTANTZ, BRENT
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		8
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Portola, Valley, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Portola, Valley, CA | Los, Gatos, CA | Palo, Alto, CA | San, Jose, CA | Freedom, CA | San, Jose, CA | Sunnyvale, CA | San, Jose, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		DRODGE, JOSEPH W
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

