<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7910006
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11587656
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Method for electromagnetic treatment of water conferring a biological activity thereon
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The water is at the origin of an entire series of geological and climatic processes and is primarily the basis of all forms of life. Actually, it is the majority component of all living organisms (50% to 98%); the human body contains 70% of the total mass thereof. The biosphere in its entirety consists of 80% water. Although this may be one of the most highly examined liquids, its properties comprising numerous anomalies have not yet all been elucidated. It plays an essential role in the structure and metabolism of all living beings. This biological role is due to its physical and chemical properties that are out of the ordinary. Bernal and Flower established a rule defining that each oxygen atom has two hydrogen atoms as neighbors and each hydrogen bond contains one hydrogen atom. The separation of the liquid water molecules produces the formation of hydroxyl ion (OH.sup.-) and hydronium ions (H.sub.3O.sup.+), which hampers this rule. The appearance of OH.sup.- and H.sub.3O.sup.+ ions produces &quot;ionic defects&quot; in the structure of the water (Bernal, J. and Fowler, R. (1933). &quot;A Theory of Water and Ionic Solution, with Particular Reference to Hydrogen and Hydroxyl Ions.&quot; Journal of Chemical Physics 1(8): 515-548). In the absence of an electric field, there is an equilibrium between the hydroxyl ions and the hydronium ions. If an electromagnetic field that polarizes in water is sent on, these two ions move independently and the equilibrium is broken. These ionic compounds can go to be adsorbed, for example, on colloidal particles.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2005-04-29
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2005
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2005-04
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-03-22
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-03
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		A61L2/14 | C02F1/48
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		A61L2/14
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		A
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		A61
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		A61L
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		A61L2
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/243 | 210/695 | 210/222 | 422/186.01 | 204/155 | 210/748.16 | 204/663 | 204/664 | 422/186.07 | 210/748.01 | 204/554 | 204/568 | 204/557 | 210/748.19 | 204/555 | 204/564 | 204/565
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/243
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5326446 | US5939030 | WO2002058449
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		FR
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		0404588
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2004-04-29
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		VALLEE, PHILIPPE
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		VALLEE, PHILIPPE
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Paris, FR
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Paris, FR
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		YOUNG &amp; THOMPSON
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		REIFSNYDER, DAVID A
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

