<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7964100
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12013805
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Remediation of waste water
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A non-toxic waste water treatment composition is provided. The waste water treatment composition is formed from: (a) an alkanolamide; (b) an ethoxylated alkylphenol, ethoxylated aryl phenol, or combination thereof; (c) a first surfactant selected from the group consisting of: an ethoxylated alcohol, a glycerol ester, a propoxylated fatty acid, an ethoxylated fatty acid, a propoxylated alcohol, an ethoxylated alcohol, a propoxylated alkyl phenol, an ethoxylated alkyl phenol, and a combination thereof; (d) a second surfactant selected from the group consisting of: a sulfosuccinate, a sulfosuccinate derivative, an imidazoline, an imidazoline derivative, and a combination thereof; and (e) optionally, a foaming agent. Methods for forming the non-toxic composition and for treating waste water with the composition are also provided. Finally an apparatus for introducing a waste water treatment composition into a waste water system is provided. The apparatus includes tubing for delivering the waste water treatment composition to at least one spray nozzle and a swivel fitting connecting the tubing to the spray nozzle. The spray nozzle is configured to deliver the waste water treatment composition into the waste water system, and the swivel fitting permits 360 degree rotation of the spray nozzle around the tubing.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2008-01-14
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2008-01
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-06-21
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-06
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C01F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C01F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C01F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C01F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/610
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/610
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Klopotek et al., Liquid dishwashing agent, 6001 Chemical Abstracts, vol. 113, No. 8, Aug. 20, 1990. cited by other.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US20060243662 | US20020166813 | US20020170857 | US20030150801 | US20070272611 | US5908473 | WO1997043012 | PL157002
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		8
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		FOG FREE TECHNOLOGIES, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		FOG FREE TECHNOLOGIES, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		North Charleston, SC
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		North Charleston, SC
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		SPARKS, JORDAN | VIS, DAVID
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		SPARKS, JORDAN
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Sutter, Creek, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Sutter, Creek, CA | Cumming, GA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		KILPATRICK TOWNSEND &amp; STOCKTON LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BARRY, CHESTER T
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

