<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7955507
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12583501
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Functionalized green filtration media for passive underground drainfield for septic tank nutrient removal
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Methods, systems and compositions for a green sorption media for bioretention soil amendments in drainfields for on-site waste water systems filled with the green sorption media to foster an anaerobic or anoxic environment saturated. The green sorption media includes one or more recycled materials, including tire crumb, sawdust, orange peel, coconut husks, leaf compost, oyster shell, soy bean hulls and one or more naturally occurring materials including peat, sands, zeolites, and clay. The wastewater filtration system for a passive drainfield includes the green sorption material mixture, a cell including baffled compartments and a riser, the cell filled with green sorption material mixture to provide an alternating cycle of aerobic and anoxic environments, an influent distribution system to distribute the influent over the cell, and a piping system arranged for dosing the cell to sustain the functionality of the green sorption material mixture to remove nutrient content in wastewater.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2009-08-21
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2009-08
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-06-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-06
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01D11/00 | C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01D11/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01D11
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/679 | 252/180 | 210/691
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/679
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		World Health Organization (WHO), Guidelines for Drinking-Water Quality, 1st Addendum to the 3rd ed., vol. 1: Recommendations, World Health Organization, Geneva, 2006. cited by other. | Mothersill, C. L., Anderson, B. C., Watt, W.E., Marsalek, J., Biological Filtration of Stormwater: Firld Operations and Hardwood forest Ecosystems. Biogeochemistry, 1996, pp. 541-562, vol. 35. No. 3. cited by other . | Hsieh, C. H., Davis, A. P., Engineered Bioretention for Removal of Nitrate from Storm Water Runoff, Diffuse Pollution Conference Dublin, Ireland, 2003. cited by other . | Savage, A. J., Tyrrel, S. F., Compost Liquir Bioremediation using waste materials as biofiltration media, Biosource Technology, 2005, pp. 557-564, vol. 96. cited by other . | Darbi, A., Viraraghavan, T., Butler, R., Corkal, D., Batch Studies on nitrate Removal from Portable Water, Water South Africa, 2002, pp. 319-322, vol. 28, No. 3. cited by other . | Sengupta, S., Ergas, S. J., Autotrophic Biological Denitrification with Elemental Sulfur or Hydrogen for Complete Removal of Nitrate-Nitrogen from a Septic System Wastewater, Report Submitted to The NOAA/UNH cooperative Institute for Costal and Estuarine Enviormental Technology (CICEET). 2008. cited by other . | Forbes, M.G. Dickson, K.L., Saleh, F., Doyle, R.D. , Hudak, P.,Waller, W. T., Recovery and Fractionation of Phosphate Retained by Lightweight Expanded Shale Masonry Sand used as Media in Subsurface Flow Treatment Wetlands, Environmental Science and Technology, 2005, pp. 4621-4627, vol. 39, No. 12. cited by other . | Gungor, K., Unlu, K., Nitrate Removal Efficiencies of Soil Aquifer Treatment Columns, Turkish J. Eng. Env. Sci., 2005, pp. 159-170, vol. 29. cited by other . | Kim, H., Seagren, E. A., Davis, A. P., Engineered Bioretention for removal of Nitrate from Storm Water Runoff, in WEFTEC 2000 Conference Proceedings on CDROM Research Symposium, Nitrogen Removal, Session 19, Anaheim CA, Oct. 2000. cited by other . | Florida Depatment of Health, Wekiva Basin Onsite Sewage Treatment and Disposal System Study. Department of onsite Sewage Program. available at the internet at: http://www.doh.state.fl.us/enviorment/////ostda/wekiva.wekivastudyrtp.pdf- , 2004. cited by other . | Clark, S., Pitt, R., Broan, D., Effect of Anaerobiosis on fiber Media Pollutant Retention, Presented at the Engineering Foundation and the American Society of Civil Engineers Conference on Information &amp; Monitoring needs for Evaluating the Mitigation effects of BMP's, Snowmass, Co, 2001. cited by other . | Debusck, T. A., Langston, M. A., Schwegler, B. R., Davidson, S., An Evaluation of Filter Media for Treating Storm Water Runoff, Proceeding of the Fifth Biennial Stormwater Research Conference, 1997. pp. 82-29. cited by other . | Korkusuz, E.A.,Beklioglu, M., Demirer, G. N., Use of Blast Furnace Granulated Slag as a substrate in Vertical Flow Reed Beds: Field Application, Bioresource Technology, 2007, pp. 2089-2101, vol. 98. cited by other . | Lisi, R.D., Park, J. K., Siter, J. C., Mitigating Nutrient Leaching with a Sub-Surface Drainage Layer of Granulated Tires. Waste Management, 2004, pp. 831-839, vol. 24, No. 8. cited by other . | Peterjohn, W. T., Adams, M. B., Gilliam, F. S., Symptoms of Nitrogen Saturation in Two Central Appalachian Hardwood Forest Ecosystems. Biochemistry, 1996, pp. 507-522, vol. 35. cited by other . | Birch, G.F., Fazeli, M.S., Matthai, C., Efficiency of an Infiltration Basin in Removing Contaminants from Urban Stormwater, Environment Monitoring and Assessment. 2005, pp. 22-38, vol. 101. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		16
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5823711 | US5750026 | US5509230 | US20050161407 | US7288190 | US6214229 | US5014462 | US20060124540 | US20040112809 | US6969469 | US6458179 | US5958239
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		12
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		UNIVERSITY OF CENTRAL FLORIDA RESEARCH FOUNDATION, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		UNIVERSITY OF CENTRAL FLORIDA RESEARCH FOUNDATION, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Orlando, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Orlando, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		WANIELISTA, MARTIN, P. | CHANG, NI-BIN | MAKKEASORN, AMMARIN
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		WANIELISTA, MARTIN, P.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Winter, Park, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Winter, Park, FL | Winter, Springs, FL | Winter, Springs, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		STEINBERGER, BRIAN S. WOOD, PHYLLIS K. LAW OFFICES OF BRIAN S. STEINBERGER, P.A.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		PRINCE, FRED
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

