<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7906464
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12120159
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Compositions and methods for the removal of oil-based filtercakes
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A method of servicing a wellbore comprising providing a composition comprising a mutual solvent precursor, an acid precursor, and an aqueous fluid, and contacting the composition with oil wet solids in the wellbore. A method of servicing a wellbore comprising introducing an oil-based fluid into a wellbore, wherein the oil-based fluid forms oil wet solids in the wellbore, contacting the oil wet solids in the wellbore with a composition comprising a mutual solvent precursor; an acid precursor and an aqueous fluid, and allowing the oil wet solids to become water wet. A method of servicing a well bore comprising contacting a composition comprising a formate ester with oil wet solids in the well bore under conditions wherein the formate ester hydrolyzes to release formic acid, wherein the formic acid catalyzes the hydrolysis of additional formate ester, and wherein all or a portion of the formate ester converts at least a portion of the oil-wet solids to water-wet solids.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2008-05-13
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2008-05
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-03-15
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-03
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C09K8/60 | C23G1/06 | C09K8/74 | C09K8/584 | C09K8/524 | C02F5/10
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C09K8/60
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C09
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C09K
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C09K8
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		507/266 | 507/261 | 507/252 | 507/262 | 507/235 | 507/239 | 507/269
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		507/266
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		507
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Heller, Jorge, et al., &quot;Poly(ortho esters)--from concept to reality,&quot; Biomacromolecules, Sep./Oct. 2004, pp. 1625-1632, vol. 5, No. 5, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Vichaibun, Virun, et al., &quot;A new assay for the enzymatic degradation of polylactic acid,&quot; 2003, pp. 297-300, vol. 29, ScienceAsia. cited by other . | Hellweg, Thomas, &quot;Phase structures of microemulsions,&quot; Current Opinion in Colloid &amp; Interface Science, 2002, pp. 50-56, vol. 7, Elsevier Science Ltd. cited by other . | Designation: G111-97, &quot;Standard guide for corrosion tests in high temperature or high pressure environment, or both,&quot; Dec. 1997, pp. 1-5 plus 1 license agreement page, ASTM International. cited by other . | Halliburton brochure entitled &quot;Musol.RTM. A: mutual solvent,&quot; 1998, 2 pages, Halliburton Energy Services, Inc. cited by other . | Whistler, Roy L., et al., &quot;Distribution of formyl groups in amylose monoformate,&quot; Aug. 20, 1959, pp. 4427-4429 plus 1 cover page, vol. 81, The Journal of the American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Davison, J. M., et al., &quot;Oil-based muds for reservoir drilling: their performance and cleanup characteristics,&quot; SPE 58798, SPE International Symposium on Formation Damage, Lafayette, Louisiana, Feb. 23-24, 2000, pp. 1-11, Society of Petroleum Engineers. cited by other . | Sinclair, Richard G., &quot;Slow-release pesticide system: polymers of lactic and glycolic acids as ecologically beneficial, cost-effective encapsulating materials,&quot; Oct. 1973, pp. 955-956, vol. 7, No. 10, Environmental Science and Technology. cited by other . | SYNPERONIC PE/L64 Safety Data Sheet, Version 3, Nov. 22, 2005, 6 pages, ICI Group of Companies. cited by other . | Foreign communication from a related counterpart application--International Search Report and Written Opinion, PCT/GB2009/001183, Jul. 15, 2009, 10 pages. cited by other . | Foreign communication from a related counterpart application--International Search Report and Written Opinion, PCT/GB2009/002156, Feb. 5, 2010, 8 pages. cited by other . | Reid, E. Emmet, &quot;Esterification,&quot; Sep. 1954, pp. 1801-1808, vol. 46, No. 9, Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. cited by other . | Halliburton brochure entitled &quot;N-Flow(SM) AO Stimulation Service,&quot; Aug. 2005, 2 pages, Halliburton Communications. cited by other . | Colon, A. Alberto, et al., &quot;The hydrolysis of some alkyl lactates. II. &quot;Neutral&quot; and acid hydrolyses,&quot; Dec. 5, 1953, pp. 6074-6075 plus 1 publication page, The Journal of the American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Dechy-Cabaret, Odile, et al., &quot;Controlled ring-opening polymerization of lactide and glycolide,&quot; Chemical Reviews, 2004, pp. A to Z plus AA to AD, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Yin, Mao, et al., &quot;Preparation and characterization of substituted polylactides,&quot; Macromolecules, Nov. 16, 1999, pp. 7711-7718, vol. 32, No. 23, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Howard, William L., et al., &quot;Chelating agents,&quot; pp. 764-795, vol. 5. cited by other . | Mikhailov, M., et al., &quot;An experimental investigation of drilling-fluid filter-cake removal by acid jetting,&quot; SPE 112373, SPE International Symposium and Exhibition on Formation Damage Control, Lafayette, Louisiana, Feb. 13-15, 2008, pp. 1-9, Society of Petroleum Engineers. cited by other . | Woodbridge, R. G., Jr, &quot;Notes on cellulose esters,&quot; 1909, pp. 1067-1071 plus 1 cover page, vol. 31, The Journal of the American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Quintero, L., et al., &quot;One-step acid removal of an invert emulsion,&quot; SPE 94604, SPE European Formation Damage Conference, Scheveningen, The Netherlands, May 25-27, 2005, pp. 1-9, Society of Petroleum Engineers. cited by other . | Bowmer, C. T., et al., &quot;The ecotoxicity and the biodegradability of lactic acid, alkyl lactate esters and lactate salts,&quot; Chemosphere, 1998, pp. 1317-1333, vol. 37, No. 7, Elsevier Science Ltd, Great Britain. cited by other . | Halliburton brochure entitled &quot;Musol.RTM.: mutual solvent,&quot; Feb. 2007, 2 pages, Halliburton Communications. cited by other . | Halliburton, &quot;SurgiFrac(SM) service: a quick and cost-effective method to help boost production from openhole horizontal completions,&quot; Oct. 2002, 2 pages, Halliburton. cited by other . | Love, T.G., et al., &quot;Selectively placing many fractures in openhole horizontal wells improves production,&quot; SPE 50422, SPE International Conference on Horizontal Well Technology, Calgary, Alberta, Canada, Nov. 1-4, 1998, pp. 1-8, Society of Petroleum Engineers, Inc. cited by other . | Zignani, M., et al., &quot;Subconjunctival biocompatibility of a viscous bioerodable poly(ortho ester),&quot; 1998, pp. 277-285, John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc. cited by other . | Reid, E. Emmet, &quot;Esterification,&quot; Sep. 1953, pp. 1936-1943, vol. 45, No. 9, Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. cited by other . | Office Action (Final) dated Nov. 16, 2009 (8 pages), U.S. Appl. No. 11/622,907, filed Jan. 12, 2007. cited by other . | Mabey, W., et al., &quot;Critical review of hydrolysis of organic compounds in water under environmental conditions,&quot; Stanford Research Institute, Menlo Park, California, 1978, pp. 383-410, vol. 7, No. 2, J. Phys. Chem. Ref. Data. cited by other . | Biehn, G.F., et al., &quot;Polyvinyl alcohol as an emulsifying agent,&quot; pp. 1449-1453, vol. 40, No. 8, Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. cited by other . | Halliburton brochure entitled &quot;CobraJet Frac(SM) service: cost-effective technology that can help reduce cost per BOE produced, shorten cycle time and reduce capex,&quot; 2 pages, Halliburton Communications. cited by other . | Baroid Fluid Services brochure entitled &quot;N-FLOW.TM. filter cake breaker systems,&quot; Jan. 2007, 2 pages, Halliburton. cited by other . | Patent application entitled &quot;Microemulsifiers and Methods of Making and Using Same,&quot; by Ryan van Zanten, et al., filed Sep. 26, 2008 as U.S. Appl. No. 12/239,442. cited by other . | Norman. Lewis R., et al., &quot;Temperature-stable acid-gelling polymers: laboratory evaluation and field results,&quot; Nov. 1984, pp. 2011-2018, Journal of Petroleum Technology. cited by other . | Special Products Material Safety Data Sheet entitled &quot;GS 22 Series (89A, 89B, 91A, 91B, 92A, 92B, 94A, 94B),&quot; Version 1.0, Nov. 10, 2005, 5 pages, Special Products. cited by other . | Baroid Fluid Services brochure entitled &quot;GELTONE.RTM. II viscosifier,&quot; 2006, 1 page, Halliburton. cited by other . | Office Action dated Feb. 12, 2008 (8 pages), U.S. Appl. No. 11/536,833, filed Sep. 29, 2006. cited by other . | Heller, J., et al., Release of norethindrone from poly(ortho esters), Mid-Aug. 1981, pp. 727-731, vol. 21, No. 11, Polymer Engineering and Science. cited by other . | Toncheva, V., et al., &quot;Use of block copolymers of poly(ortho esters) and poly(ethylene glycol) micellar carriers as potential tumour targeting systems,&quot; Journal of Drug Targeting, 2003, pp. 345-353, vol. 11, No. 6, Taylor &amp; Francis Ltd. cited by other . | Chiang, Y., et al., &quot;Hydrolysis of ortho esters: further investigation of the factors which control the rate-determining step,&quot; XP002322842, 1 page. cited by other . | Baroid Fluid Services brochure entitled &quot;BARACARB.RTM. bridging agent,&quot; Apr. 2005, 2 pages, Halliburton. cited by other . | Baroid Fluid Services brochure entitled &quot;LE SUPERMUL.TM. emulsifier,&quot; 2006, 1 page, Halliburton. cited by other . | Ng, S. Y., et al., &quot;Synthesis and erosion studies of self-catalyzed poly(ortho ester)s,&quot; Macromolecules, 1997, pp. 770-772, vol. 30, No. 4, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Akzo Nobel Material Safety Data Sheet entitled &quot;ETHOMEEN.RTM. SV/12,&quot; May 7, 2003, 6 pages, Akzo Nobel Surface Chemistry LLC, Akzo Nobel Chemicals Ltd. cited by other . | Notice of Allowance dated Aug. 11, 2010 (83 pages), U.S. Appl. No. 12/239,442, filed Sep. 26, 2008. cited by other . | Tarkow, Harold, et al., &quot;The reaction of formic acid with carbohydrates. II. Polysaccharides: A new method for determining accessibility,&quot; Feb. 1952, pp. 266-271, vol. 56. cited by other . | Cantu, Lisa A., et al., &quot;Laboratory and field evaluation of a combined fluid-loss-control additive and gel breaker for fracturing fluids,&quot; SPE Production Engineering, Aug. 1990, pp. 253-260, Society of Petroleum Engineers. cited by other . | Office Action dated May 21, 2008 (21 pages), U.S. Appl. No. 11/622,898, filed Jan. 12, 2007. cited by other . | Malm, Carl J., et al., &quot;Hydrolysis of cellulose esters,&quot; Jan. 1966, pp. 81-87, vol. 5, No. 1, I&amp;EC Process Design and Development. cited by other . | Purac America Inc. Material Safety Data Sheet for PURASOLV ML plus Purac product line datasheets, http://hazard.com/msds/f2/cbj/cbjlq.html, Dec. 13, 1991, 6 pages. cited by other . | Kajiyama, Tetsuto, et al., &quot;Improved synthesis with high yield and increased molecular weight of poly (a,.beta.-malic acid) by direct polycondensation,&quot; Biomacromolecules, 2004, pp. 169-174, vol. 5, No. 1, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Siskin, Michael, et al., &quot;Aqueous organic chemistry. 1. Aquathermolysis: comparison with thermolysis in the reactivity of aliphatic compounds,&quot; Energy &amp; Fuels, 1990, pp. 475-482, vol. 4, No. 5, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Todd, Brad, et al., &quot;An innovative system for complete cleanup of a drill-in fluid filter cake,&quot; SPE 86494, SPE International Symposium and Exhibition on Formation Damage Control, Lafayette, Louisiana, Feb. 18-20, 2004, pp. 1-9, Society of Petroleum Engineers. cited by other . | Kellog, David R., &quot;The effect of neutral salts on hydrolysis by water,&quot; 1909, pp. 886-900 plus 1 publication page, vol. 31, The Journal of the American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Wolff, I. A., et al., &quot;Starch formate,&quot; Jul. 20, 1957, pp. 3860-3862 plus 1 cover page, vol. 79, The Journal of the American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Rosano, Henri L., et al., &quot;Microemulsion systems,&quot; 1987, 2 pages, Marcel Dekker, Inc., USA. cited by other . | Ingram, Stephen, et al., &quot;Enhancing and sustaining well production: Granite Wash, Texas Panhandle,&quot; SPE 106531, SPE Production and Operations Symposium, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, Mar. 31-Apr. 3, 2007, pp. 1-11, Society of Petroleum Engineers. cited by other . | Tarkow, Harold, et al., &quot;The reaction of formic acid with carbohydrates. I. The reaction of formic acid with sugars,&quot; Feb. 1952, pp. 262-266, vol. 56. cited by other . | Office Action (Final) dated Nov. 13, 2008 (22 pages), U.S. Appl. No. 11/622,907, filed Jan. 12, 2007. cited by other . | Office Action dated Mar. 19, 2008 (13 pages), U.S. Appl. No. 11/622,907, filed Jan. 12, 2007. cited by other . | Office Communication (Examiner's Answer) dated Sep. 14, 2009 (10 pages), U.S. Appl. No. 11/622,898, filed Jan. 12, 2007. cited by other . | Cordes, E. H., et al., &quot;Mechanism and catalysis for hydrolysis of acetals, ketals, and ortho esters,&quot; 1974, pp. 581-603, vol. 74, No. 5, Chemical Reviews. cited by other . | Albertsson, Ann-Christine, et al., &quot;Aliphatic polyesters: synthesis, properties and applications,&quot; Advances in Polymer Science, 2002, pp. 1-161 plus 2 Preface pages, vol. 157, Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg. cited by other . | Heller, Jorge, et al., &quot;Poly(ortho esters) for the pulsed and continuous delivery of peptides and proteins,&quot; Controlled Release and Biomedical Polymers Department, SRI International, Menlo Park, California, pp. 39-56. cited by other . | Office Action dated Jun. 22, 2007 (11 pages), U.S. Appl. No. 11/622,898, filed Jan. 12, 2007. cited by other . | Simmons, Tara L., et al., &quot;Poly(phenyllactide): synthesis, characterization, and hydrolytic degradation,&quot; Biomacromolecules, 2001, pp. 658-663, vol. 2, No. 3, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Penny, G., et al., &quot;The application of microemulsion additives in drilling and stimulation results in enhanced gas production,&quot; SPE 94274, SPE Production and Operations Symposium, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, Apr. 17-19, 2005, pp. 1-9, Society of Petroleum Engineers. cited by other . | Stefanidis, Dimitrios, &quot;General base catalysis of ester hydrolysis,&quot; Jul. 14, 1993, pp. 6045-6050 plus 1 cover page and 1 publication page, vol. 115, No. 14, Journal of the American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Office Action (Final) dated Dec. 27, 2007 (10 pages), U.S. Appl. No. 11/622,898, filed Jan. 12, 2007. cited by other . | Yin, Mao, et al., &quot;Synthesis and properties of polymers derived from substituted lactic acids,&quot; 2001, pp. 147-159, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Baroid Fluid Services brochure entitled &quot;N-FLOW(SM) services,&quot; 1 page, Halliburton. cited by other . | Ahmad, M., et al., &quot;Ortho ester hydrolysis: direct evidence for a three-stage reaction mechanism,&quot; XP002322843, 1 page. cited by other . | Designation: G 111-97 (Reapproved 2006), &quot;Standard guide for corrosion tests in high temperature or high pressure environment, or both,&quot; May 2006, pp. 1-5 plus 1 license agreement page, ASTM International. cited by other . | Malm, C. J., et al., &quot;Evaluating cellulose acetylation reactivity,&quot; Apr. 1957, pp. 763-768, vol. 49, No. 4, Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. cited by other . | Williams, Roger J., et al., &quot;The relation between the hydrolysis equilibrium constant of esters and the strengths of the corresponding acids,&quot; May 1928, pp. 1267-1271, vol. 50. cited by other . | Kumar, Promod, et al., &quot;Handbook of microemulsion science and technology.&quot; cited by other . | Gradzielski, M., &quot;Effect of the cosurfactant structure on the bending elasticity in nonionic oil-in-water microemulsions,&quot; Langmuir, 1998, pp. 6037-6044, vol. 14, No. 21, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Todd, B., et al., A chemical `trigger` useful for oilfield applications, SPE 92709, SPE International Symposium on Oilfield Chemistry, Houston, Texas, Feb. 2-4, 2005, pp. 1-7, Society of Petroleum Engineers, Inc. cited by other . | Office Action dated Sep. 10, 2010 (9 pages), U.S. Appl. No. 11/622,907, filed Jan. 12, 2007. cited by other. | Holland, John M., et al., &quot;Hydrolysis of alkyl acetates in a phosphate-buffered aqueous medium,&quot; Mar. 1961, pp. 463-466, vol. 65. cited by other . | Skrabal, Anton, et al., &quot;The hydrolysis rate of orthoformic acid ethyl ether,&quot; Chemical Institute of the University of Graz, Jan. 13, 1921, pp. 1-38 plus 1 cover page, Translated from German by the McElroy Translation Company, Job No. 415-104489. cited by other . | McDaniel, B. W., et al., &quot;Evolving new stimulation process proves highly effective in level 1 dual-lateral completion,&quot; SPE 78697, SPE Eastern Regional Meeting, Lexington, Kentucky, Oct. 23-25, 2002, pp. 1-11, Society of Petroleum Engineers Inc. cited by other . | Peterson, Marvin L., et al., &quot;Esterification,&quot; An I/EC Unit Processes Review, Sep. 1960, pp. 807-811, vol. 52, No. 9, Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. cited by other . | Stepan Product Bulletin entitled &quot;Amphosol.RTM. LB,&quot; Jan. 2006, 3 pages, Stepan. cited by other . | Schwach-Abdellaoui, K., et al., &quot;Hydrolysis and erosion studies on autocatalyzed poly(ortho esters) containing lactoyl-lactyl acid dimers,&quot; Macromolecules, 1999, pp. 301-307, vol. 32, No. 2, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Katritzky, Alan R., et al., Aquathermolysis: reactions of organic compounds with superheated water, Acc. Chem. Res., 1996, pp. 399-406, vol. 29, No. 8, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Daccord, Gerard, et al., &quot;Acidizing physics,&quot; Reservoir Stimulation, pp. 13-1 to13-13, Dowell Schlumberger. cited by other . | Funkhouser, Gary P., et al., &quot;Synthetic polymer fracturing fluid for high-temperature applications,&quot; SPE 80236, SPE International Symposium on Oilfield Chemistry, Houston, Texas, Feb. 5-7, 2003, pp. 1-6, Society of Petroleum Engineers Inc. cited by other . | Ng, S. Y., et al., &quot;Development of a poly(ortho ester) prototype with a latent acid in the polymer backbone for 5-fluorouracil delivery,&quot; Journal of Controlled Release, 2000, pp. 367-374, vol. 65, Elsevier Science B.V. cited by other . | Notice of Allowance dated Sep. 26, 2008 (4 pages), U.S. Appl. No. 11/536,833, filed Sep. 29, 2006. cited by other . | Kunieda, Hironobu, et al., &quot;Effect of added salt on the maximum solubilization in an ionic-surfactant microemulsion,&quot; Langmuir, 1996, pp. 5796-5799, vol. 12, No. 24, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Heller, J., et al., Poly(ortho ester)s--their development and some recent applications, European Journal of Pharmaceutics and Biopharmaceutics, 2000, pp. 121-128, vol. 50, Elsevier Science B.V. cited by other . | Foreign communication from a related counterpart application--International Search Report, PCT/GB2007/003754, Mar. 13, 2008, 3 pages. cited by other . | Skrabal, Anton, &quot;On the kinetics of acid and basic catalysis,&quot; Chemical Institute of the University, Gras, 1928, pp. 687-696, Aberdeen: The University Press. cited by other . | Todd, Brad, et al., &quot;Laboratory device for testing of delayed-breaker solutions on horizontal wellbore filter cakes,&quot; SPE 68968, SPE European Formation Damage Conference, The Hague, The Netherlands, May 21-22, 2001, pp. 1-9, Society of Petrolelum Engineers, Inc. cited by other . | Gotch, Albert J., et al., &quot;Formation of single-phase microemulsions in toluene/water/nonionic surfactant systems,&quot; Langmuir, 2008, pp. 4485-4493, vol. 24, No. 9, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Bumajdad, Ali, et al., &quot;Properties of mixed alcohol--zwitterionic surfactant films in quaternary water-in-oil microemulsions,&quot; Langmuir, 2003, pp. 7219-7225, vol. 19, No. 18, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Myers, R. Thomas, et al., &quot;The rate of saponification of acetates of unsaturated alcohols,&quot; Apr. 1952, pp. 461-463, vol. 56. cited by other . | Malm, C. J., et al., &quot;The action of fatty acids on cellulose,&quot; Jan. 1929, pp. 274-278 plus 1 publication page, vol. 51, The Journal of the American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Office Action (Final) dated Nov. 10, 2008 (13 pages), U.S. Appl. No. 11/622,898, filed Jan. 12, 2007. cited by other . | Kellogg, David R., &quot;The effect of neutral salts on hydrolysis by water,&quot; 1909, pp. 403-405 plus 1 publication page, vol. 31, The Journal of the American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Filachione, E. M., et al., &quot;Preparation of methyl lactate,&quot; Apr. 1945, pp. 388-390, vol. 37, No. 4, Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. cited by other . | Office Action dated Feb. 10, 2009 (9 pages), U.S. Appl. No. 11/622,907, filed Jan. 12, 2007. cited by other . | Heller, Jorge, et al., &quot;Poly(ortho esters): synthesis, characterization, properties and uses,&quot; Advanced Drug Delivery Reviews, 2002, pp. 1015-1039, vol. 54, Elsevier Science B.V. cited by other . | Halliburton brochure entitled &quot;Cobra Frac(SM) service: coiled tubing fracturing--cost-effective method for stimulating untapped reserves,&quot; 2000, 2 pages, Halliburton Energy Services, Inc. cited by other . | Schwach-Abdellaoui, K., et al., &quot;Control of molecular weight for auto-catalyzed poly(ortho ester) obtained by polycondensation reaction,&quot; International Journal of Polymer Anal. Charact., 2002, pp. 145-161, vol. 7, Taylor &amp; Francis. cited by other . | Whitfill, Donald L., &quot;Session 5: fluid evaluation and selection for minimal damage,&quot; Keynote Paper, SPE European Formation Damage Conference, Amsterdam, May 21-22, 2001, pp. 1-4, Society of Petroleum Engineers, Inc. cited by other . | Matsuyama, Kiyoshi, et al., &quot;Environmentally benign formation of polymeric microshperes by rapid expansion of supercritical carbon dioxide solution with a nonsolvent,&quot; Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 2001, pp. 4149-4155, vol. 35, No. 20, American Chemical Society. cited by other . | Chatterji, J., et al., &quot;Applications of water-soluble polymers in the oil field,&quot; Journal of Petroleum Technology, Nov. 1981, pp. 2042-2056, The Society of Petroleum Engineers of AIME. cited by other . | Rothen-Weinhold, A., et al., &quot;Release of BSA from poly(ortho ester) extruded thin strands,&quot; Journal of Controlled Release, 2001, pp. 31-37, vol. 71, Elsevier Science B.V. cited by other . | Baroid Fluid Services brochure entitled &quot;RHEMOD.TM. L viscosifier/suspension agent,&quot; 2006, 1 page, Halliburton. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		110
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US20060169450 | US2206187 | US6790811 | US20030130133 | US6326458 | US20080110618 | US4829100 | US5325923 | US4793416 | US6454003 | US6291013 | US5698322 | US5142023 | US6566310 | US5359026 | US3986355 | US20050272613 | US6218342 | US20070169938 | US6569814 | US20060065397 | US7093658 | US5360068 | US3828854 | US5203834 | US5496557 | US6710019 | US5888944 | US6279656 | US7032663 | US7131491 | US6686328 | US4894231 | US3548945 | US20040138068 | US6323307 | US5247059 | US5985800 | US5152781 | US3948672 | US6214773 | US5791415 | US6330917 | US6861394 | US20060041028 | US6981552 | US6114410 | US20050028976 | US3955993 | US4863980 | US5723416 | US3272650 | US7096947 | US5849401 | US4785884 | US20060229212 | US7168489 | US20060169182 | US7112557 | US5295542 | US5464060 | US20080287324 | US5330005 | US5034139 | US7353879 | US3998272 | US7134496 | US7264051 | US6143698 | US5905061 | US3364995 | US7322412 | US4172066 | US5505787 | US2050392 | US6681856 | US6702023 | US7166560 | US7000701 | US7066258 | US4267887 | US4843118 | US7314850 | US4068718 | US7216705 | US20070173416 | US20050183741 | US6554071 | US5607905 | US5909774 | US20030230407 | US4822500 | US2703316 | US6209646 | US20060185848 | US5977030 | US20030147965 | US6004400 | US6543276 | US7132389 | US4387769 | US5977031 | US6209643 | US6432155 | US3868998 | US3968840 | US6172011 | US4809783 | US6328105 | US4694905 | US6818594 | US3481404 | US4136739 | US7380606 | US6840318 | US6763888 | US5762138 | US4632876 | US4836940 | US6029755 | US6828280 | US20060118300 | US5783527 | US6983798 | US6599863 | US6691805 | US5499678 | US6123159 | US6770293 | US5475080 | US20040070093 | US5363916 | US5386874 | US6908888 | US6908887 | US6953090 | US6508305 | US5697440 | US6978838 | US6608006 | US3630285 | US3173484 | US4715967 | US5908073 | US4961466 | US7101829 | US6169058 | US6311773 | US7125826 | US20060016596 | US4502540 | US5990050 | US7261156 | US6716797 | US20050059557 | US6949491 | US5996693 | US20050059556 | US5251697 | US6494263 | US6422314 | US3784585 | US5396957 | US5492177 | US6761218 | US5833000 | US7204312 | US7080688 | US4498995 | US20060283597 | US7204311 | US7093664 | US6837309 | US7238646 | US7140438 | US20050209107 | US7265079 | US7159659 | US7052901 | US6047772 | US7178594 | US5613558 | US7303019 | US7219731 | US7267466 | US6357527 | US20080169102 | US5604186 | US7303014 | US7044220 | US6527051 | US3302719 | US7021377 | US7178596 | US6959767 | US6390195 | US20080169103 | US7044224 | US6589917 | US6422326 | US6620437 | US4848467 | US6764981 | US7256159 | US20050130848 | US20040072696 | US20040176478 | US5161615 | US4010071 | US20060105918 | US4772346 | US3998744 | US6896058 | US7156174 | US1922154 | US5964291 | US6258859 | US20060105917 | US5439055 | US7021383 | US3195635 | US20010016562 | US3836465 | US6135987 | US2863832 | US5979557 | US7069994 | US20080076682 | US6221920 | US7195068 | US5765642 | US7205264 | US7147067 | US6806233 | US5594095 | US6806235 | US5402846 | US6308788 | US7049272 | US6793018 | US4713183 | US5484881 | US6852173 | US6509301 | US5501276 | US20050277554 | US5591700 | US20050034861 | US7306037 | US6881709 | US20060183646 | US2059459 | US5536807 | US3960736 | US5813466 | US7036587 | US7036585 | US7036586 | US7151077 | US7098171 | US5304620 | US6886635 | US6488091 | US4716964 | US6669771 | US5082056 | US20070100029 | US6488763 | US5853048 | US6024170 | US4817721 | US6987083 | US4299825 | US6817414 | US6485947 | US6300286 | US4957165 | US6667279 | US5216050 | US20050257932 | US6989354 | US6028113 | US20080078549 | US4506734 | US20080009423 | US6737385 | US7165617 | US7267170 | US6877563 | US5602083 | US6148917 | US5893416 | US6578630 | US6110875 | US6401819 | US6387986 | US5670473 | US6983801 | US3912692 | US2681889 | US4767706 | US6394185 | US5249628 | US6202751 | US3366178 | US20070027253 | US20070298977 | US20060172893 | US20060172894 | US6793025 | US20060172895 | US6904971 | US20060172891 | US4265673 | US5916849 | US6123965 | US4470915 | US7228904 | US2910436 | US5487897 | US5555936 | US20060234873 | US7153902 | US2238671 | US4169798 | US6364945 | US5373901 | US3819525 | US7063151 | US6260622 | US5678632 | US5799734 | US6162766 | US4460052 | US20060032633 | US5497830 | US4797262 | US6691780 | US7172022 | US6189615 | US4252421 | US20060258543 | US20040231845 | US6302209 | US20060258544 | US7299869 | US6380138 | US20060108150 | US4521316 | US6131661 | US20040170836 | US7299874 | US5213446 | US4986353 | US4986354 | US4526695 | US4986355 | US20060276345 | US6242390 | US7007752 | US7514390 | US7222672 | US3455390 | US5924488 | US5512071 | US6793730 | US4886354 | US5460226 | US20060046938 | US7066260 | US5314031 | US6405809 | US6883608 | US6997259 | GB2163790 | WO1997011845 | WO2003027431 | WO2008045734 | WO1995009879 | WO1993015127 | WO1994007949 | WO2001042387 | JP2004181820 | GB2116966 | WO2006109016 | WO2002055843 | WO2004007905 | GB2109034 | GB2412389 | WO2004038176 | WO2004037946 | WO2000008112 | WO2002012674 | EP0510762 | WO2005095755 | WO1994008078 | EP1413710 | EP0278540 | WO2008038033 | WO2006093863 | WO1994008090 | WO2001094744 | GB2032491 | WO2001002698 | WO2001087797 | WO2006029019 | EP0879935 | WO2000057022 | WO1999027229
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		409
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Duncan, OK
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Duncan, OK
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		DAVIDSON, ERIC
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		DAVIDSON, ERIC
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Aberdeen, GB
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Aberdeen, GB
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		RODDY, CRAIG W. CONLEY ROSE, P.C.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		KUGEL, TIMOTHY J.
	</str>
	<str name="Assistant Examiner">
		ADMASU, ATNAF
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

