<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7993110
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11899905
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Steam-generator and gas-compressor systems using water-based evaporation coolants, sealants and lubricants
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A gas/air compressor system used for compressing a gas/air stream of air, oxygen, oxygen-enriched air and other combustible gases and delivering a moderate-to-high temperature, moderate-to-high pressure fluid to a pipeline connected to one or more injection wells. Fuel with cooling water is injected downhole for combustion in the compressed gas/air stream to be used for in-situ-retorting of oil shale, volatile coal beds, tar sands, heavy oil and other hydrocarbon or carbonaceous deposits. A preferred embodiment of the compressor system includes a compressor housing with a male screw rotor having helical lobes received in helical grooves in a female screw rotor. The housing includes a gas/air inlet for receiving the gas/air stream therein and a series of water/mineral injectors for injecting a water/mineral slurry into the rotating screw rotors. The water/mineral slurry acts as a sealant, a lubricant and also a coolant for male and female screw rotors during the compression cycle. The slurry is non-combustible and non-reactive to combustion-supporting gases. Also, the housing includes a gas/air outlet for discharging the compressed gas/air stream into the pipeline connected to the injection wells used in the in-situ-retorting process.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2007-09-08
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2007
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2007-09
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-08-09
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-08
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		F04B3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		F04B3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		F04
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		F04B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		F04B3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		417/297 | 210/748.01 | 62/179 | 417/251
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		417/297
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		417
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6506027
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		HILL, GILMAN, A.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		HILL, GILMAN, A.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Englewood, CO
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Englewood, CO
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		CRABTREE, EDWIN H. PIZARRO, RAMON L.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		GRIFFIN, WALTER D
	</str>
	<str name="Assistant Examiner">
		ALLEN, CAMERON J
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

