<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7959806
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12111099
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Mine influenced water remediation using bioremediation substrate
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A new and improved method for treating mine influenced water (MIW) or other environmental contamination is disclosed. A number of electron donors are disclosed, including chitin complex-containing materials. The chitin complex-containing materials may modify the pH and reductive-oxidation potential of the contaminated media within the subsurface or within a treatment cell to facilitate metal removal through biological, chemical, and physical means, or a combination thereof. Bioremediation enhancing agents such as yeast products may also be used to facilitate microbial treatment of the contaminated sources. The yeast products may work with microbes to improve the rate of contaminant removal and promote microbial growth.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2008-04-28
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2008-04
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-06-14
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-06
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C01F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C01F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C01F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C01F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/631 | 210/743 | 210/601 | 210/688
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/631
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Williams, P.E. et al; Effects of the inclusion of yeast culture Saccharomyces cerevisiae plus growth medium) in the diet of dairy cows on milk yield and forage degradation and fermentation patterns in the rumen of steers; J. Anim. Sci. 1991; 69; pp. 3016-2036. cited by other . | PCT/US2008/ 057250,Invitation to Pay Additional Fees and Partial International Search Report, mailed Jul. 23, 2008; 4 pages. cited by other . | PCT/US2008/061808 International Search Report and Written Opinion, mailed Aug. 7, 2008; 14 pages. cited by other . | Callaway, E.S. &amp; Martin, S.A.; &quot;Effects of a Saccharomyces cerevisiae Culture on Ruminal Bacteria that Utilize Lactate and Digest Cellulose&quot;, Nutrition, Feeding, and Calves; J. Dairy Sci 1997; 80; pp. 2035-2044. cited by other . | Laus, R. et al., Reduction of Acidity and Removal of Metal Ions From Coal Mining Effluents Using Chitosan Microspheres, ScienceDirect, Journal of Hazardous Materials, 2007, pp. 471-474. cited by other . | T. Miller-Webster, et al.; &quot;Influence of Yeast Culture on Ruminal Microbial Metabolism in Continuous Culture&quot;; J. Dairy Sci 2002; 85; pp. 2009-2014. cited by other . | Rockne, K.J. &amp; Reddy, K.R.; &quot;Bioremediation of Contaminated Sites&quot;; Oct. 2003; International e-Conference on Modern Trends in Foundation Engineering: Geotechnical Challenges and Solutions; pp. 1-22. cited by other . | Brennan R.A. et al., Biodegradation of Tetrachloroethene by Chitin Fermentation Products in a Continuous Flow Column System Journal Of Environmental Engineering, Jun. 2006, pp. 664-673. cited by other . | Moret, A, Rubio, J., Sulphate and Molybdate Ions Uptake By Chitin-Based Shrimp Shells, ScienceDirect, Minerals Engineering, 2003, pp. 715-722. cited by other . | Vera, S.M. et al., Evaluation of Different Polymeric Organic Materials for Creating Conditions That Favor Reductive Processes in Groundwater, (2001) Bioremediation Journal 5(3): 169-181. cited by other . | Nisbet, D.J. &amp; Martin, S.A.; &quot;Effect of a Saccharomyces cerevisiae culture on lactate utilization by the ruminal bacterium Selenomonas ruminantium&quot;; J. Anim. Sci. 1991; 69; pp. 4628-4633. cited by other . | Passive Remediation of Acid Mine Drainage Using Chitin, Rachel A. Brennan, Mar. 1, 2006, 7 pages. cited by other . | Daubert, L.N. &amp; Brennan, R.A., A Laboratory Investigation of Passive Acid Mine Drainage Treatment Using Chitin (URE Poster) Apr. 2006, 1 page. cited by other.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		13
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US20070051676 | US5200343 | US6562235 | US5464771 | US7045339 | US5840571 | US5071754 | US4585482 | US5587317 | US20050239189 | US5264018 | US6589776 | US5006250 | US5766929 | US6472198 | US5602296 | US5910245 | US6783678 | US5434241 | US5554290 | US7138059 | US5658795 | US6264841 | US5753122 | US5277815 | US5089123 | US6420594 | US4401569 | US6001252 | US6265205 | US5993658 | US5833855 | US20060000783 | US5342769 | US5516688 | US5932472 | US5395419 | US5560904 | US4156647 | WO2001032715 | EP075110981694 | WO1999066080 | WO1999024367
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		43
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		JRW BIOREMEDIATION, LLC (LENEXA, KS), THE PENN STATE RESEARCH FOUNDATION
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		JRW BIOREMEDIATION, LLC (LENEXA, KS), THE PENN STATE RESEARCH FOUNDATION
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		University Park, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		University Park, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		SIECZKOWSKI, MICHAEL, R. | SMITH, DONOVAN, N. | WILKE, WAYNE, H. | BRENNAN, RACHEL
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		SIECZKOWSKI, MICHAEL, R.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Lenexa, KS
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Lenexa, KS | Parkville, MO | Leawood, KS | Port, Matilda, PA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		LATHROP &amp; GAGE LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BARRY, CHESTER T
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

