<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7922008
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12501216
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Water filter materials and water filters containing a mixture of microporous and mesoporous carbon particles
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A filter and filter material for providing or treating potable water is provided. The filter includes a housing having an inlet and an outlet, a filter material disposed within the housing, the filter material formed at least in part from a mixture of a plurality of mesoporous and microporous activated carbon particles. Preferably, at least some of the mesoporous activated carbon filter particles are coated with a cationic polymer, and even more preferably, at least some of the particles are coated with a cationic polymer and silver or a silver containing material. Kits comprising filters and information relating to the reduction, killing or removal of bacteria, viruses, microbials, and TTHM are also provided.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2009-07-10
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2009-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-04-12
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-04
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01D35/00 | B01D39/14 | B01D39/00 | B01D27/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01D35/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01D35
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/501 | 210/504 | 210/503 | 210/506 | 210/505 | 210/508 | 210/507 | 210/502.1
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/501
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Daniels, S. S., &quot;The Adsorption of Microorganisms onto Solid Surfaces: A Review,&quot; Developments in Industrial Microbiology, pp. 211-243, Aug. 29-Sep. 4, 1971. cited by other . | Isbister, J.D., et al., &quot;Increasing ARCAT.RTM. Test Sensitivity for Examination of Potable Waters,&quot; Project Summary, United States Environmental Protection Agency, Research and Development 3 pgs. (May 1982). cited by other . | Burchell, T.D., et al., &quot;The effect of Neutron Irradiation on the Structure and Properties of Carbon-Carbon Composite Materials,&quot; Effects of Ratioation on Materials: 16.sup.th International Symposium, ASTM STP 1175, American Society for Testing and Materials, Philadelphia, 1993. cited by other . | Wei, G.C., et al., &quot;Carbon-Bonded Carbon Fiber Insulation for Radioisotope Space Power Systems,&quot; Ceramic Bulletin, vol. 64, No. 5, pp. 691-699 (1985). cited by other . | Preston, D.R., et al., &quot;Removal of Viruses from Tapwater by Fiberglass Filters Modified with a Combination of Cationic Polymers,&quot; Wat. Sci. Tech.,. vol. 21, No. 3, pp. 93-98 (1989). cited by other . | Jagtoyen, M. et al., &quot;Activated carbons from yellow poplar and white oak by H.sub.3PO.sub.4 activation,&quot; Carbon, vol. 36, No. 7-8, pp. 1085-1097 (1998). cited by other . | Moreno-Castilla, C., et al., &quot;The Creation of Acid Carbon Surfaces by Treatment with (NH.sub.4).sub.2S.sub.2O.sub.8&quot;, Carbon, vol. 35, No. 10-11, 1619-1626 (1997). cited by other . | Moreno-Castilla, C., et al., &quot;The Creation of Acid Carbon Surfaces By Treatment with (NH.sub.4).sub.2S.sub.2O.sub.8&quot;, Carbon, vol. 35, No. 10-11, 1619-1926 (1997). cited by other . | Kxindustries, L. P. Technical Data: Ceramikx; http://www.kxindustries.com/matrikx/ceramiks.htm; pp. 1-3, 2002: KX Industries L.P. cited by other . | Jagtoyen, M. et al., &quot;Novel Activated Carbon Materials for Water Treatment,&quot; The European Carbon Conference &quot;Carbon 96&quot;, Newcastle, UK Jul. 1996. cited by other . | Menedez, J.A., et al., &quot;On the Difference Between the Isoelectric point and the Point of Zero Charge of Carbons&quot;, Carbon, vol. 33, No. 11, 1655-1657, (1995). cited by other . | Cuno, Process Filtration Products, Product Information, Zeta Plus VIROSORB.RTM. 1MDS, pp. 2 (1989). cited by other . | Sakoda, A., et al., &quot;Adsorption of Viruses in Water Environment onto Solid Surfaces,&quot; Wat. Sci. Tech., vol. 35, No. 7, pp. 107-114 (1997). cited by other . | Abotsi, Godried, &quot;Interfacial Properties of Coal: A Guide to Catalyst Loading and Dispersion for Coal Conversion&quot;, Energia, vol. 7, No. 5, 3-5, (1996). cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 09/574,456, filed May 19, 2000, Tremblay et al. cited by other . | Kimber, G.M., et al., &quot;Fabrication of Carbon Fibre Composites for Gas Separation,&quot; Gas. Sep. Purif., vol. 10, No. 2, pp. 131-136 (1996). cited by other . | Ma, J., et al., &quot;Evaluation of MK Filters for Recovery of Enteroviruses from Tap Water,&quot; Applied and Environmental Microbiology, vol. 60, No. 6, pp. 1974-1977 (Jun. 1994). cited by other . | Hercules Product Data, Polycup.RTM. Resins and KYMENE.RTM. 2064, Hercules Incorporated, Wilmington, DE 10 pages (date unkown). cited by other . | Gregg, S.J., et al., &quot;Mesoporous solids: the Type IV isotherm&quot;, Adsorption, Surface Area and Porosity, 1982, 137-143, 2nd Edition, Academic Press, Inc. cited by other . | Franz, M., et al., &quot;Effect of Chemical Surface Heterogeneity on the Adsorption Mechanism of Dissolved Aromatics on Activated Carbon&quot;, Carbon, vol. 28, No. 13, 1807-1819, (2000). cited by other . | Derbyshire&lt; F., et al., &quot;Carbon Fiber Composite Molecular Sieves for Gas Separation,&quot; Eighth CIMTEC, Florence, Italy, Jun. 28-Jul. 2, 1994. cited by other . | Goyal, S. M., et al., &quot;Concentration of Bacteriophage Lysates by Filter Chromatography,&quot; Journal of Virological Methods, vol. 1, pp. 79-85 (1980). cited by other . | United States Environmental Protection Agency, Office of Research and Development, &quot;Stormwater Treaatment at Critical Areas: Evaluation of Filtration Methods,&quot; EPA/600/R-00/010, pp. 14, Oct. 1999. cited by other . | Evans, M. J. B., et al., &quot;The Production of Chemically-Activated Carbon,&quot; Carbon, vol. 37, pp. 269-274 (1999). cited by other . | Abotsi, Godfried, &quot;Interfacial properties of Coal: A Guide to Catalyst Loading and Dispersion for Coal Conversion&quot;, Energia, vol. 7, No. 5, 3-5, (1996). cited by other . | Sobsey, M.D., et al., &quot;Evaluating Adsorbent Filter Performance for Enteric Virus Concentrations in Tap Water,&quot; Research and Technology, pp. 542-548 (Oct. 1981). cited by other . | Menendez, J.A., et al., &quot;On the Difference Between the Isoelectric Point and the Point of Zero Charge of Carbons&quot;, Carbon, vol. 33, No. 11, 1655-1657, (1995). cited by other . | Newcombe, G., et al., &quot;Granular actiated carbon: importance of surface properties in the adsorption of naturally occurring organics&quot;, Colloids and Surfaces A: Physiochemical and Engineering Aspects, 1993, 65-71, vol. 78. cited by other . | Powell, T.M., et al., &quot;Comparative Adsorption of a Model Bacteriophage by Activated Carbon,&quot; University of Kentucky Dept. of Civil Engineering and Center for Applied Energy Research, pp. 685-690. cited by other . | Hercules Product Information, Hercules MSDS--Kymene 450 wet strength resin, 20 pages (Jan. 29, 1998). cited by other . | LeChevallier, M.W., et al., &quot;Disinfection of Bacteria Attached to Granular Activated Carbon,&quot; Applied and Environmental Microbiology, vol. 48, No. 5, pp. 918-923 (1984). cited by other . | Zerda, K.S., et al., &quot;Adsorption of Viruses to Charge--Modified Silica,&quot; Applied and Environmental Microbiolgoy, vol. 49, No. 1, pp. 91-95 (Jan. 1985). cited by other . | Sobsey, M.D., et al., &quot;Improved Electopositive Filters for Concentrating Viruses from Large Volumes of Water,&quot; Presents at the International Symposium on Viruses and Wastewater Treatment, pp. 107 (Sep. 15-17, 1980). cited by other . | Moore, R.S., et al., &quot;Improved Methods for Poliovirus Recovery from Water with Electropositive Adsorbent Filters,&quot; Annu. Meet. Am. Soc. Microbiol., paper Q55, 14 pages (1982). cited by other . | Ryoo, R., et al., &quot;Synthesis of Highly Ordered Carbon Molecular Sieves via Template--Mediated Structural Transformation,&quot; The Journal ofo Physical Chemistry B, vol. 103, Nu. 37, pp. 7743-7746 (1999). cited by other . | Dimitris Ioannis Collias, Declaration under 37 CFR .sctn.1.132, Apr. 1, 2004. cited by other . | Sobsey, M.D., et al., &quot;Concentration of Poliovirus from Tap Water Using Positively Charged Microporous Filgers,&quot; Applied and Environmental Microbiology, vol. 37, No. 3, pp. 588-595 (Mar. 1979). cited by other . | World Health Organization--Geneva, 1996 &quot;Chapter 2--Microbiolgical Aspects: Introducction,&quot; Guidelines for drinking--water quality, Second edition, vol. 2, Health Criteria and other supporting information, cover page and pp. 9-12. cited by other . | Hurst, C. J., et al., &quot;Differential Effects of Tretrazolium Dyes upon Bacteriophage Plaque Assay Titers,&quot; Applied and Environmental Microbiologoy, vol. 60, No. 9, pp. 3462-3465 (Sep. 1994). cited by other . | Gerba, C.P., et al., &quot;Removal of Poliovirus and Rotavirus from Tapwater by a Quaternary Ammonium Resin,&quot; Water Res., vol. 18, No. 1, pp. 17-19 (1984). cited by other . | Kaneko, K., et al., &quot;Microporosity and Adsorption Characteristics Against NO, SO.sub.2 and NH.sub.3 of Pitch Based Activated Carbon Fibers,&quot; Carbon, vol. 26, No. 3, pp. 327-332 (1988). cited by other . | Newcombe, G., et al., &quot;Granular activated Carbon: importance of surface properties in the adsorption of naturally occurring organics&quot;, Colloids and Surfaces A: Physiochemical and Engineering Aspects, 1993, 65-71, vol. 78. cited by other . | Bautista-Toledo, I. et al., &quot;Activated carbons as Adsorbents of Bacteria,&quot; Conference Proceedings for Eurocarbon 98, Strasbourg, France Jul. 5-9, 1998. cited by other . | Jasra, R.V., et al., &quot;Separation of Gases by Pressure Swing Adsorption,&quot; Separation Science and Technologoy, vol. 26, No. 7, pp. 885-930 (1991). cited by other . | Dorfner, K., &quot;2.1--Synthetic Resin Ion Exchangers,&quot; Ion Exchangers Properties and Applications, Cover page and pp. 16-35 (1972). cited by other . | Ceramikx:All--Carbon, Sub-Micron Performance; http://www.kxindustriescom; pp. 1-2, 2005, KX Industries, L.P. cited by other . | Hou, K. et al., &quot;Capture of Latex Beads, Bacteria, Endotoxin, and Viruses by Charge Modified Filters,&quot; Applied and Environmental Microbiology, vol. 40, No. 5, pp. 892-896 (Nov. 1980). cited by other . | Ryu, S.K., &quot;Porosity of Activated Carbon Fibre,&quot; High Temperatures--High Pressures, vol. 22, pp. 345-354 (1990. cited by other . | Vaughn, J.M., et al., &quot;Chapter 10: Virus Inactivation by Disinfectants,&quot; IV Disinfecction, pp. 217-241 (date unknown). cited by other . | Babic, B.M., et al., &quot;Point of Zero Charge and Intrinsic Equilibrium Constants of Activated Carbon Cloth&quot;, Carbon, vol. 37, No. 3, 477-481, (Feb. 22, 1999). cited by other . | Ceramikx:All--Carbon, Sub-Micron Performance; http://www.kxindustries.com; pp. 1-2, 2005, KX Industries, L.P. cited by other . | Hill, Jr., W.F., et al., &quot;Detection of Viruses in Water: Sensitivity of the Tentative Standard Method for Drinking Water,&quot; Applied and Environmental Microbiology, vol. 31, No. 2, pp. 254-261 (Feb. 1976). cited by other . | http://www.waterfilters.net/KX-Matrikx-20-185-125-083-cermikx-SC-Water-Fil- ter.sub.--p.sub.--12... &quot;KX Matrikx Ceramikx SC 20-185-125-083 Water Filter&quot;, Jan. 6, 2010. cited by other. | Gerba, C.P., &quot;Applied and Theortetical Aspects of Virus Adsorption to Surfaces,&quot; Advances in Applied Microbiology, vol. 30, pp. 133-168 (Copyright .COPYRGT. 1984). cited by other . | Goyal, S.M., &quot;Simple Method for Concentration of Bacteria from Large Volumes of Tap Water,&quot; Applied and Environmental Microbiology, vol. 40, No. 5, pp. 912-916 (Nov. 1980). cited by other . | Westvaco Products On-Line, &quot;Wood-based Activated Carbons&quot;, (2 pgs.), downloaded Jul. 2001. cited by other . | Gregg, S.J., et al., &quot;Mesoporous solids: the Type IV isotherm&quot;, Adsorption, Surface Area And Porosity, 1982, 137-143, 2.sup.nd. Edition, Academic Press, Inc. cited by other . | Barrett, Joyner, and Halenda (BJH) Process, &quot;The Determination of Pore Volume and Area Distributions in Porous Substances I. Computations from Nitrogen Isotherns,&quot; J. Amer. Chem. Soc., vol. 73, pp. 373-380 (1951). cited by other . | Openko, N., et al., &quot;Application of Carbon Materials in Water Purification,&quot; Conference Proceedings for Eurocarbon '98, Strasbourg, France Jul. 5-9, 1998. cited by other . | Report of Task Force, &quot;Guide Standard and Protocol for Testing Microbiological Water Purifiers&quot;, United States Environmental Protection Agency, (submitted Apr. 1986), revised Apr. 1987, 1-39. cited by other . | Nupen, E.M., et al., &quot;The Recovery of Viruses from Drinking--Water by Means of an In-Line Electropositive Cartridge Filter,&quot; National Institute for Water Research, Council for Scientific and Industrial Research, pp. 1-7 (date unknown). cited by other . | Westvaco Products On-Line, &quot;Wood-based Activated Carbons&quot;, (2 pgs), downloaded Jul. 2001. cited by other . | Powell, T., et al., &quot;Investigating the Effect of Carbon Shape on Virusa Adsorption,&quot; Environmental Science and Technology, vol. 34, No. 11, pp. 2779-2783 (2000). cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		63
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5702498 | US4172796 | US5128036 | US5128034 | US4482641 | US3770625 | US5527451 | US4997553 | US20040164018 | US5972253 | US0041321 | US3550782 | US20080093303 | US0826654 | US4842724 | USD323203 | US4361486 | US0025398 | USD418198 | US1363589 | USD256944 | US3888958 | USD347462 | USD363760 | US6337015 | US5116502 | USD421089 | US6270658 | USD293367 | US5795843 | USD326706 | USD240731 | US5183607 | US5133878 | US20020150686 | US5665224 | US4391712 | USD356625 | US4673504 | US5147533 | US20040251190 | US6024899 | US5686893 | US2987187 | US5035802 | US3678098 | US4352884 | US6099735 | US5992684 | US4681677 | USD357058 | US5296148 | US4775465 | USD324721 | US6120685 | US5658372 | US6120683 | USD236265 | USD236263 | USD303703 | US6120682 | USD236264 | USD336760 | US5004535 | USD360332 | US1752060 | US4853117 | US5976363 | US5521008 | US4504389 | US5324434 | USD437913 | USD405868 | US4585554 | US2701792 | USD405867 | US6241899 | US5464531 | US5051189 | US5447626 | US20030096703 | US3847787 | US4595497 | US4448695 | US4769148 | USD429943 | US3268444 | US5487917 | US6241893 | US4578150 | US5203803 | US20040040906 | US5580444 | US4708803 | US5705269 | US4722508 | USD227886 | US6328881 | US20020170618 | US6264830 | US5587089 | US6057262 | US5525214 | US5804280 | US4277333 | US3886093 | US4822765 | US3686151 | USD229178 | US5707518 | USD323017 | US5772896 | US2811258 | US5281309 | USD353440 | USD405156 | US5393419 | USD173603 | US5248417 | US4880535 | USD395705 | US4778596 | US5656160 | US6881348 | US4609466 | US3184064 | US4021343 | US5324424 | US4014792 | USD236829 | US5290442 | US5049270 | USD170472 | US4368123 | US1806977 | US5277805 | US4645567 | USD370521 | US5935426 | US5957034 | USD242043 | US5468387 | US4623451 | USD234357 | US5322625 | USD234356 | US4552863 | USD288115 | US4808302 | USD196108 | US5082557 | US3692180 | US5698091 | USD242249 | US5091164 | US4623467 | US6145670 | US6491811 | USD424660 | US5744236 | US6491815 | USD410726 | US5349992 | US5922378 | US6139726 | US4772455 | US5328613 | USD465018 | US1579158 | US3352424 | US5679248 | US5679243 | US6630016 | US4654075 | US4205055 | US5310593 | US4983288 | USD426418 | US5114042 | US5582717 | US4430226 | USD314607 | US5518613 | USD466602 | USD440255 | US5308703 | US5882507 | US5730863 | US6827854 | US6245229 | US5282972 | US3856676 | USD249057 | US4523995 | US0673722 | USD407462 | USD377388 | US3814642 | USD389004 | US2633990 | USD328777 | US5238559 | US6423212 | US5705067 | US20030136728 | USD249055 | US5989736 | USD249054 | USD249053 | USD383192 | USD136021 | US4670144 | US3939074 | US5316673 | USD249275 | US3898188 | US4983717 | US3972818 | US7615152 | USD386242 | USD268866 | US5989425 | US4086166 | US1621684 | US4473474 | US4696742 | USD208752 | USD318092 | USD318093 | US4828698 | US3853761 | USD350870 | US6228255 | US5078864 | US5395509 | US4389311 | US5204310 | US4321288 | USD422679 | US5813245 | USD330587 | US5626749 | US5813246 | US4879027 | US5111966 | US5681459 | US5160608 | US4045553 | US5069782 | US20030106851 | US0963324 | US1782850 | US4885085 | US5238570 | US4885081 | US6565749 | USD128316 | US4657674 | USD306754 | US6030698 | US5131277 | USD309494 | USD319864 | US4626346 | US4340479 | US3871950 | US4147631 | US2268076 | US5443739 | US5928588 | US4396512 | US3419645 | US3428089 | US5855788 | US5037550 | USD372515 | US6228803 | US4573464 | US5068030 | US4340480 | US4772508 | US6303031 | US5543054 | USD446840 | USD309487 | US5431813 | USD351014 | US4830223 | USD274930 | US4292417 | US4759844 | US5106500 | US4683054 | US4190532 | US20020033365 | US5834114 | US4190537 | US5762787 | US5766453 | US4678565 | US5645719 | US4019986 | USD454615 | US5715699 | US4152262 | US5039402 | US20010032823 | US5676824 | US0543922 | US5776339 | US4670482 | US5371221 | US4859340 | US4969991 | US5645720 | US5928558 | US5348647 | US0034658 | US5376279 | US5817231 | US5817237 | US5907958 | US5750026 | US20040129617 | US4969996 | USD416307 | USD235143 | US5855796 | US5904854 | US5435909 | USD402745 | US5990041 | USD258462 | US3342335 | US6001249 | US5356531 | US5466378 | US6579445 | US5922803 | US6155432 | USD312679 | US5505120 | US5562824 | US6177319 | US4936984 | US4366068 | US6402949 | USD216978 | US4831011 | US0611691 | US5017292 | USD249701 | US5762797 | US4309247 | US5795475 | US5449456 | US20020060177 | US6660166 | US20020148785 | US5560393 | USD390629 | US4830744 | USD143545 | US3863458 | USD307173 | US5565100 | USD234843 | US0009622 | US4007114 | US6428708 | US4816149 | US6013180 | US4923091 | USD406314 | US2335458 | US5143889 | US3558276 | US5331037 | USD282767 | US3333703 | USD227565 | US2750080 | US6214224 | US4606828 | USD253715 | US5800707 | USD409715 | US5368197 | USD358460 | US5997734 | US4968440 | US20020134714 | US4434206 | US5024764 | USD290638 | USD235206 | US5957339 | US4572785 | USD319288 | US4752389 | USD290386 | US5037547 | US5187237 | US5223132 | US5189092 | US5607595 | US4181694 | US6370884 | US5658457 | US4978650 | US6361686 | US5928503 | US3283040 | USD292429 | US5928506 | US4722964 | USD377515 | US5785848 | US5670124 | US4049550 | USD307933 | US6077588 | USD251380 | US5188727 | US5709794 | US0531838 | USD358868 | US2372340 | US0590020 | US3591010 | US6258266 | US6258265 | US3950253 | US20040159596 | USD314226 | USD372295 | US6428687 | USD296000 | USD278650 | US5108590 | US5567311 | US4743366 | US1674203 | USD403406 | US4576929 | US5620790 | US4734394 | US3539009 | USD318315 | US20020170921 | US4744895 | US5193892 | US5227238 | US4915839 | US5110468 | US3950267 | US3784649 | USD372760 | US5460792 | US4515692 | USD304363 | US6391191 | USD301913 | USD221850 | US20020014461 | USD438282 | US5445729 | US5688588 | USD378883 | US5853572 | US4283283 | US20020172637 | USD76391 | US5900138 | USD297349 | US5122265 | US6045694 | US4734208 | US6123844 | US5454944 | US20020074294 | US5662779 | US5261792 | US6123837 | USD340967 | US5232590 | US4305782 | US5833849 | US5755957 | USD321550 | US5268093 | US6436282 | US4704324 | US3670892 | US5478465 | US20020043491 | US5639374 | US4946600 | US5900141 | US5900143 | US4686037 | US4399035 | US0967905 | US6270822 | US5112477 | USD93910 | US6103114 | USD352200 | US20030217963 | USD289429 | US3572553 | US4252650 | USD240624 | US5502978 | US5773143 | US4994184 | US20030038084 | US4081370 | US5083442 | US3931009 | US0602883 | US5536396 | USD449758 | US5536395 | USD295887 | US5536394 | US4110219 | USD296352 | US4776952 | US5662792 | USD133177 | US3242073 | US5643444 | US3700623 | US4698164 | US1043933 | USD113679 | USD232550 | US5446005 | USD398367 | US5776385 | US3314897 | USD332131 | USD331446 | USD344322 | USD296463 | US4749484 | US4981591 | US6274041 | USD437402 | US4695375 | US3278560 | US20020011434 | US1539775 | WO1999010076 | DE3738231 | EP0947231 | SU1717538 | GB2238532 | WO2004076361 | EP1419109 | FR2557807 | WO2000043319 | WO1988007500 | WO1993017725 | DE9312279 | JP1983131187 | EP0798003 | DE19650191 | WO2002014228 | GB2250281 | WO2000000266 | WO1992012784 | EP0364111 | WO1998043796 | DE3511389 | WO2001074725 | WO1997030938 | WO1996030309 | DE931227939 | JP1998052616 | WO2000035559 | EP0490317 | JP1995080449 | EP0616975 | WO1996030310 | RU2064429 | GB1202215 | JP1993253478 | JP1998076254 | RU2034789 | JP2000281445 | JP1996099080 | DE2357585 | FR2788511 | EP0792676 | WO1995024256 | GB1163426 | FR2331515 | DE4028529 | EP0563027 | WO1995005237 | GB1546409 | JP1989304095 | WO1999007456 | WO2000000437 | WO1995009129 | WO2000001624 | WO2000001626 | GB2311775 | WO2000001625 | EP0439005 | JP1993049921 | RU2070438 | WO2002068234 | WO2003068686 | DE10016365 | WO1991001786 | EP0367389 | EP0668243 | WO2002085794 | DE19717579 | WO2002098536 | WO2000037363 | WO1993023336 | GB1470874 | GB191594 | WO2000025887 | WO2001044120 | JP1992277080 | WO2006008324 | WO2003022745 | EP0891952 | EP0880986 | EP0366539 | WO1998012489 | DE4116128 | FR2743285 | EP0285321 | JP1998139645 | WO2001012559 | WO2002083266 | WO1997034832 | GB2029255 | WO1994023827 | WO1999047226 | WO1997038941 | WO1992012864 | WO1994010091 | JP1992247233 | GB2257429 | GB2051770 | WO1999010069 | EP0551864 | WO2000037385 | EP1106228 | DE3020615 | WO2000037950 | DE3914940 | WO2002100509
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		660
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		THE PROCTER &amp; GAMBLE COMPANY
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		THE PROCTER &amp; GAMBLE COMPANY
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Cincinnati, OH
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Cincinnati, OH
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		BAHM, JEANNINE, REBECCA | PEARKS, ANDREW, THOMAS | VIDAL, GUILLERMO, MATIAS | COLLIAS, DIMITRIS, IOANNIS | MITCHELL, MICHAEL, DONOVAN | ASTLE, ROBERT, E. | FAYE, KATHARINE, L., K. | GOVERNAL, ROBERT, ANDREW | HAMLIN, THOMAS, J. | LUCHT, REBECCA, A. | PATEL, HEMANG
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		BAHM, JEANNINE, REBECCA
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		11
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Milford, OH
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Milford, OH | Cincinnati, OH | Cincinnati, OH | Mason, OH | Cincinnati, OH | Middlefield, CT | Moodus, CT | Middletown, CT | Vemon, CT | Rocky, Hill, CT | Wallingford, CT
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		CLAY, CYNTHIA L. ZERBY, KIM WILLIAM
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		KIM, JOHN
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

