<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US7964102
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12219992
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Titanium composition for water treatment and method
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A personally portable water purification compound prepared in unit dosage form such as tablets, packages and the like and having titanium dioxide (TiO.sub.2) in the form of fine particles, and adsorbed chlorine held at the surface of the titanium dioxide particles; and a titanium based coagulant; the compound being prepared in a plurality of unit dose size packages, for personal use by individuals. Also disclosed is a method of preparing a personally portable water purification compound consisting of the steps of heating titanium dioxide particles up to a temperature between about 260-500.degree. C., passing a cold dry gaseous chlorine flow around the titanium dioxide particles; and cooling the titanium dioxide during the treatment. Also disclosed is a method of purifying water containing contaminants and bacteria consisting of the steps of segregating a predetermined volume of the water, introducing a first predetermined quantity of titanium dioxide particles activated with adsorbed chlorine, simultaneously introducing a second predetermined quantity of a titanium coagulant, agitating the water and releasing the chlorine from the titanium dioxide particles, the chlorine destroying the bacteria, allowing the water to stand for a predetermined dwell time, during which the titanium dioxide without chlorine attracts contaminants, and after which the titanium coagulant forms flocs into masses heavier than water which masses settle out, leaving the water purified.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2008-07-31
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2008-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-06-21
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-06
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01D21/01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01D21/01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01D21
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/754 | 210/764 | 210/723 | 210/192
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/754
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5681475 | US20090291987 | US5023012
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		STREMILOVA, NINA, N. | STREMILOV, SERGUEI, V.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		STREMILOVA, NINA, N.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		St., Petersburg, RU
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		St., Petersburg, RU | Concord, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BARRY, CHESTER T
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

