<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US8067554
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11/807558
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Ion exchange chromatography of GLP-1, analogs and derivatives thereof
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The present invention relates to an ion exchange chromatography process for purifying GLP-1 or an analog or a derivative thereof from a mixture containing said GLP-1 and related impurities, and to an industrial method including such ion exchange chromatography process.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2007-05-29
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2007
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2007-05
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-11-29
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-11
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		A61K38/26 | A23J3/00 | C07K14/605 | A61P5/50 | B01D15/04
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		A61K38/26
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		A
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		A61
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		A61K
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		A61K38
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		530/416 | 530/308 | 530/324 | 210/638
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		530/416
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		530
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		English Language Machine Translation of Japanese Patent JP 10059867, published Mar. 3, 1998. cited by other . | Berks, B.C et al., Bio Chem, vol. 263, pp. 261-266 (1989). cited by other . | Tateshi, K., Diabetes Research and Clinical Practice, 1994, vol. 25, No. 1, pp. 43-49. cited by other . | Brange et al., &quot;Chemical stability of insulin&quot; 5. Isolation, characterization and identification of insulin transformation Acta Pharm Nord., vol. 4. No. 4. pp. 223-232 (1992). cited by other . | Final Office Action in U.S. Appl. No. 09/671,461, filed Sep. 27, 2000 by Arne Staby, sent from the USPTO on Nov. 19, 2003. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 09/691,461, filed Sep. 27, 2000, Arne Staby. cited by other . | Final Office Action for U.S. Appl. No. 11/358,676, filed Feb. 21, 2006 by Thomas Budde Hansen, sent from the USPTO on May 12, 2009. cited by other . | Kroeff, E.P., et al., Journal Chromatography, vol. 461, pp. 45-61 (1989). cited by other . | Orskov, C etal., Journal Biological Chemistry, vol. 264 (22), pp. 12826-12829 (1989). cited by other . | Abstract of Japanese Patent JP 10059867; Activation of Blood coagulation Factor VII-by ion exchange purification of a solution containing Factor VII, 1998. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 09/522,694, filed Mar. 10, 2000, Arne Staby. cited by other . | M. Raida et al. &quot;Liquid Chromatography and Electrospray Mass Spectrometric Mapping of Peptides from Human Plasma Filtrate&quot; Journ of America Society of Mass Spectrometry, vol. 10. pp. 45-54 (1999). cited by other . | Johnson et al., Basic Liquid Chromatography, pp. 116-148 (1978). cited by other . | Abstract of Japanese Patent JP 10059866; Preparation of blood coagulation factor VII and/or activated blood coagulation factor VII-by developing solution containing factor VII with anion exchange resin, 1998. cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 09/523,785, filed Mar. 13, 2000, Arne Staby. cited by other . | Non-final Office Action in U.S. Appl. No. 10/176,410, filed Jun. 18, 2002 by Arne Staby, sent from the USPTO on Dec. 29, 2006. cited by other . | Schmidt et al, &quot;Glucagon-like peptide-1 but not glucagons-like peptide-2 stimulates insulin release from isolated rat pancreatic islets&quot; Diabetologia, vol. 28. 28, pp. 704-707 (1985). cited by other . | S. Bjoern et al., (Sep. 1986), Novo Research Institute, Novo Alle, DK-2880, Bagsvaerd, Denmark &quot;Activiation of Cuagulation of Factor VII to VIIA Research Disclosure&quot;, Research Disclosure, No. 26960, pp. 564-565. cited by other . | Buhl, T. et al., Journal Biological Chem, vol. 263(18), pp. 8621-8624 (1988). cited by other . | Namba, M. et al., Biomed Res., vol. 11(4), pp. 247-254 (1990). cited by other . | Abstract of Dizdaroglu et al., &quot;Separation of Peptides by Hight Performance Liquid Chromatography On A Weak Anion Exchange Bonded Phase&quot; Journal of Chromatography. vol. 237, pp. 417-428 (1982). cited by other . | Szepesi et al., Normal Phase Dynamic (Solvent-Generated) Molecular Complexation Chromatography Using Anionic Ion Exchangeers: II. Separation of Optical Isomers, Journal of Chromatography, 1982, vol. 244, pp. 33-48. cited by other . | Snyder, L.R., et al., Biological Chem Samples, pp. 478-536 (1997). cited by other . | Noe, B. D et al., Peptides, vol. 7, pp. 331-336 (1986). cited by other . | English Language Machine Translation of Japanese Patent Publication JP8337600, published Dec. 24, 1996. cited by other . | English Language Abstract of European Patent EP 0849277, published Jun. 24, 1998. cited by other . | Bataille et al., &quot;Isolation of glucagon-37 (bioactive enteroglucagon/oxyntomodium) from porcine jejuno-ileum&quot;, Sep. 1982, FEBS Letters, vol. 146, No. 1, pp. 73-78. cited by other. | U.S. Appl. No. 11/358,676, filed Feb. 21, 2006, Hansen et al. cited by other . | Non-final Office Action in U.S. Appl. No. 09/671,461, filed Sep. 27, 2000 by Arne Staby, sent from the USPTO on Jan. 11, 2006. cited by other . | Supplemental Notice of Allowability for U.S. Appl. No. 11/358,676, filed Feb. 21, 2006 by Thomas Budde Hansen, sent from the USPTO on May 27, 2010. cited by other . | Kagaku et al., Activation of Coagulation of Factor VII to VIIa Research Disclosure, pp. 564-565 (Sep. 1986). cited by other . | Conlon, J.M. et al., Gen Comp Endocrinol, vol. 60, pp. 398-405 (1985). cited by other . | Non-final Office Action in U.S. Appl. No. 10/176,410, filed Jun. 18, 2002 by Arne Staby, sent from the USPTO on Sep. 17, 2004. cited by other . | Huskins et al., &quot;Halibut Muscle 3-Phosphoglycerate Kinase. Chemical and Physical Properties of the Enzyme and Its Subtract Complexes&quot; Biochemestry, vol. 21 pp. 4180-4189 (1982). cited by other . | Suda, K. et al., Biomed Res., vol. 9(3), pp. 39-45 (1988). cited by other . | Rojas, F. J. et al., Endocrinology, vol. 113, pp. 711-719 (1983). cited by other . | Mollerup, I et al., Encyclopedia of Bioprocess Tech, pp. 1491-1498 (1999). cited by other . | Lamy et al., Archives of Biochemistry and Biophysics, vol. 193, No. 1, pp. 140-149 (Mar. 1979). cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 10/176,410, filed Jun. 18, 2002, Arne Staby. cited by other . | Walker, P.R. et al., Biological Chemistry, vol. 25, pp. 3839-3845 (1986). cited by other . | Non-final Office Action in U.S. Appl. No. 09/671,461, filed Sep. 27, 2000 by Arne Staby, sent from the USPTO on Feb. 11, 2003. cited by other . | Boysen, R.I. et al., Journal of Biological Chemistry, vol. 277(1), pp. 23-31 (2002). cited by other . | English Language Abstract for Russian Patent RU2122549, published Nov. 27, 1998. cited by other . | Senderoff, R. et al., &quot;Consideration of Conformational Transitions and Racemization During Process Development of Recombinant Glucagon-Like-Peptide-1,&quot; Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences, 1998, vol. 87, No. 2, pp. 183-189. cited by other . | Sakaguchi et al., &quot;Invention of the Retention Volume Order of Enantiomers Caused by the Concentration of Eluent&quot;, Bulletin of the Chemical Society of Japan, 1983, vol. 56, pp. 1407-1409. cited by other . | English Language Machine Translation of Japanese Patent JP 10059866, published Mar. 3, 1998. cited by other . | Ohboshi et al., Molecular Forms of Immunoreactive Glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) in plasma. Biomedical Research, vol. 9 (Suppl. 3), pp. 47-51, 1988. cited by other . | Kamisoyama, H. et al., Animal Science Journal, vol. 71, pp. 428-431 (2000). cited by other . | Abstract of Stadalius et al., &quot;Predicting Bandwidth In The High Performance Liquid Chromatographic Separation of Large Biomolecules II. A General Model For The Four Common High Performance Liquid Chromatography Methods&quot; Journal of Chromatography, vol. 387, pp. 21-40 (1987). cited by other . | Kreymann et al., &quot;Isolation and characterisation of GLP-1 (7-36) amide from rat intestine,&quot; FEBS Letters, vol. 242 (1), Dec. 1988. cited by other . | Thum, A. et al., Exp Clin Endocrinol Diabetes, vol. 110(3), pp. 113- (2002). cited by other . | Schau, O., Interlaken Conference on Adv.. 2003. cited by other . | Notice of Allowance for U.S. Appl. No. 11/358,676, filed Feb. 21, 2006 by Thomas Budde Hansen, sent from the USPTO on Apr. 13, 2010. cited by other . | Final Office Action in U.S. Appl. No. 10/176,410, filed Jun. 18, 2002 by Arne Staby, sent from the USPTO on May 19, 2006. cited by other . | Non-final Office Action in U.S. Appl. No. 09/671,461, filed Sep. 27, 2000 by Arne Staby, sent from the USPTO on May 31, 2005. cited by other . | Stuber, W. et al., &quot;Synthesis and Photolytic Cleavage of Bovine Insuling B22-30 on a Nitrobenzoylglycyl-Poly(ethyleneglycol) Support&quot;, International Journal of Peptide and Protein Research, 1983, vol. 22, pp. 277-283. cited by other . | Notice of Allowance in U.S. Appl. No. 09/671,461, filed Sep. 27, 2000 by Arne Staby, sent from the USPTO on Oct. 2, 2006. cited by other . | English Language Abstract for Danish Patent DK155887, published May 29, 1989. cited by other . | Non-final Office Action in U.S. Appl. No. 09/671,461, filed Sep. 27, 2000 by Arne Staby, sent from the USPTO on Jan. 9, 2006. cited by other . | Guzzetta, A. Reverse Phase HPLC Basics for LC/MS, http://www.ionsource.com/tutorial/chromatography/rphplc.htm , pp. 1-10 (2008). cited by other . | Notice of Allowance for U.S. Appl. No. 11/358,676, filed Feb. 21, 2006 by Thomas Budde Hansen, sent from the USPTO on Dec. 10, 2009. cited by other . | Non-final Office Action in U.S. Appl. No. 10/176,410, filed Jun. 18, 2002 by Arne Staby, sent from the USPTO on Jul. 14, 2005. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		62
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US4909941 | US6268343 | US20030103980 | US5101103 | US20010021767 | US20030027996 | US3907676 | US4617376 | US5344918 | US20030144471 | US6113911 | US4129560 | US4361510 | US5977297 | US5606031 | US5101013 | WO2001004156 | WO1990000177 | WO1990000176 | WO2000055203 | WO2000041548 | WO1999025727 | WO1990010018 | WO1998008872 | EP0708179 | WO1998008871 | EP0849277 | WO1996032414 | WO1987006941 | WO1990011296 | EP0207727 | WO2002046227 | EP0206792 | EP0699686 | WO1991011457 | EP0305760 | RU2122549 | DK155887
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		38
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		DK | DK
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		199900361 | 200000082
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		1999-03-15 | 2000-01-19
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		NOVO NORDISK A/S
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		NOVO NORDISK A/S
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Bagsvaerd, DK
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Bagsvaerd, DK
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		STABY, ARNE
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		STABY, ARNE
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Bagsv.ae, butted.rd, DK
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Bagsv.ae, butted.rd, DK
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		BRIGNATI, MICHAEL J.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		KOSSON, ROSANNE
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

