<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US8080164
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12/815626
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Environmentally-neutral processing with condensed phase cryogenic fluids
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Systems, methods and apparatus are provided for utilizing a substantially condensed phase cryogenic fluid for the purpose of remediation and retrieval of, e.g., spilled crude oil and other &quot;oil spill&quot;-related products from marine/aquatic and terrestrial environments. In some implementations, systems and apparatus are provided for applying a substantially condensed phase cryogenic fluid to a volume of spilled oil, and further having structure for collecting the spilled oil. Some implementations are environmentally-neutral. Substances other than oil may be remediated as well.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2010-06-15
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2010
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2010-06
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-12-20
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-12
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		E02B15/04
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		E02B15/04
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		E
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		E02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		E02B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		E02B15
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/923 | 62/533 | 210/744 | 62/66 | 210/776 | 210/747.5 | 210/774 | 210/742 | 62/540
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/923
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Office Action of Feb. 17, 2009 re U.S. Appl. No. 11/839,0776, filed Aug. 15, 2007. cited by other . | Roberts; Leslie and Enserink, Martin; Did they Realy Say . . . Eradication?; Science vol. 318; Dec. 7, 2007; p. 1544-1545. cited by other . | Aigner, et al: Incurring Carbon Debs in Biofuels Production; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 319; Feb. 29, 2008; pp. 1157. cited by other . | Tanaka &amp; Koga, &quot;Formation of ice nanotube with hydrophobic guests inside carbon nanotube,&quot; The Journal of Chemical Physics 123:094706, Jun. 2005. cited by other . | Eichhornia Crassipes (mart.) Solms-Laub.; Waterhyacinth p. 48-49. cited by other . | Koga &amp; Tanaka, &quot;Phase diagram of water between hydrophobic surfaces,&quot; The Journal of Chemical Physics, 122:104711, Oct. 2005. cited by other . | Bhattacharjee, Yudhijit; Panel Provides Peer Review of Intelligence Research; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 318; Dec. 7, 2007; pp. 1538. cited by other . | Enserink, Martin; The Mosquito Paradox; ScienceNOW Daily News; Jul. 17, 2008, pp. 1-4. cited by other . | Biorefineries; The Biomass Economy; NREL/JA-810-31967; Jul. 2002 p. 1-4. cited by other . | Whitesides, George M. et al.; &quot;Don't Forget Long-Term Fundamental Research in Energy&quot;; Science vol. 315; Feb. 9, 2007 p. 796-798. cited by other . | Marland, Greg et al.; &quot;The Carbon Benefits of Biofuels&quot; Science vol. 318 Nov. 16, 2007; pp. 1065-1068. cited by other . | Dr. Faustino L. Orach-Meza and Dr. Tom Okurut; Background to the Preparatin of the Second Phase of the Lake Victoria Environmental Management Project (LVEMP-II); Regional Stakeholders' Workshop on Launching of the Preparation of the LVEMP Phase Two (LVEMP-II); Jan. 2005; 1-22. cited by other . | Clery, Daniel; A Sustainable Future, If we pay up front; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 315; Feb. 9, 2007; pp. 782-783. cited by other . | Kintisch, Eli; The Greening of Synfuels; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 320; Apr. 18, 2008; pp. 178-179. cited by other . | Zelkowitz; Rachel; &quot;Bells Ring for First U.S. Carbon Auction&quot;; ScienceNOW Daily News; Sep. 29, 2008; pp. 1-2. cited by other . | Mervis, Jeffrey; Tax Credit Extension is Silver Lining for Science; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 322; Oct. 10, 2008; pp. 181. cited by other . | Metz, B et al.; IPPC, 2007: Summary for Policymakers. In: Climate Change 2007: Mitigation. Contribution of Working Group III to the Fourth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change; Cambridge University Press, Cambridge UK. cited by other . | Cho, Adrian; Profile: James Dumesic--Catalyzing the Emergence of a Practical Biorefinery; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 315; Feb. 9, 2007; pp. 795. cited by other . | Grom, Jackie; Malaria Forecast Varies by Temperature; Findings, The Science Magazine news Blog; Feb. 15, 2009. cited by other . | Service, Robert F.; Profile: Daniel Nocera--Hydrogen Economy? Let sunlight Do the Work; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 315; Feb. 9, 2007; pp. 789. cited by other . | NREL; &quot;From Biomass to Biofuels; How Biofuels are Produced&quot;; National Renewable Energy Laboratory; Mar. 2007; pp. 1-6. cited by other . | Notice of Allowance of Aug. 25, 2009 re U.S. Appl. No. 11/839,247, filed Aug. 15, 2007. cited by other . | Financial Products Offered by the African Development Bank; Brochure of ADP Group dated Jun. 24, 2005 (pp. 1-37). cited by other . | Holm, L.G. et al.; The worlds worst weeds; CAB International abstract database; pp. 1-3 (article 1). cited by other . | Himmel, Michael E. et al.; Biomass Recalcitrance: Engineering Plants and Enzymes for Biofuels Production; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 315; Feb. 9, 2007, pp. 804-807. cited by other . | Bernstein, Lenny et al.; Climate Change 2007 Synthesis Report Summary for Policymakers p. 1-22. cited by other . | Notice of Allowance of Jun. 29, 2009 re U.S. Appl. No. 11/839,077, filed Aug. 15, 2007. cited by other . | Koenig, Robert; Meeting of Research Leaders Spotlights African Development, Disaster Planning; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 322; Oct. 10, 2008; pp. 178-179. cited by other . | Butunyi, Cosmas; Kenya: Fresh Worries over Hyacinth that Sunk in Lake Victoria; AllAfrica.com; Sep. 16, 2008; pp. 1-2. cited by other . | Koga et al., &quot;Ice nanotube: What does the unit cell look like?,&quot; Journal of Chemical Physics 113(12):5037, Nov. 2000. cited by other . | Schrag, Daniel P.; Preparing to Capture Carbon; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 315; Feb. 9, 2007;pp. 812-813. cited by other . | Putt, Ron; Submitted by Center for Microfibrous materials Manufacturing (CM3) Department of Chemical Engineering; Auburn University, &quot;Algae as a Biodiesel Feedstock: A Feasibility Assessment&quot;; pp. 1-47, Nov. 2007. cited by other . | Eichhornia Crassipes (mart.) Solms-Laub.; Waterhyacinth; James A. Duke. Handbook of Energy Crops. Unpublished 1983 p. 1-7. cited by other . | The Marrakech Process; Providing Solutions to Climate Change Mitigation through Sustainable Consumption and Production; United Nations Department of Economic and Social Affairs United Nations Environment Programme. cited by other . | Ghazarian, V. et al.; Universal molecule injector in liquid helium: Pulsed cryogenic doped helium droplet source; Review of Scientific Instruments; vol. 73, No. 10; Oct. 2002; pp. 3606-3613. cited by other . | Bai et al., &quot;Ab initio studies of quasi-one-dimensional pentagon and hexagon ice nanotubes,&quot; Journal of Chemical Physics 118(9):3913-3916, Mar. 1, 2003. cited by other . | Bhattacharjee, Yudhijit; Pioneers to Feed Africa; Science vol. 318 Nov. 23, 2007 pp. 1223. cited by other . | Bates, B.C., et al.; Climate Change and Water. Technical Paper of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, IPCC Secretariat, Geneva, 210pp. cited by other . | Dodds, David R. et al.; &quot;Chemicals from Biomass&quot;; Science vol. 318; Nov. 23, 2007; pp. 1250-1251. cited by other . | Kintisch, Eli; The Greening of Synfuels; Science vol. 320; Apr. 18, 2008; p. 306-308. cited by other . | Office Action of Apr. 2, 2009 re U.S. Appl. No. 11/839,338, filed Aug. 15, 2007. cited by other . | Souda, &quot;Hydrophobic hydration of alkanes: Its implication for the property of amorphous solid water,&quot; Journal of Chemical Physics 121(18):8676, Nov. 2004. cited by other . | Non-Native Invasive Aquatic Plants in the United States Center for Aquatic and Invasive Plants, University of Florida and Sea Grant; Eichhornia Crassipes (Mart.) Solms; Water Hyacinth pp. 1-6. cited by other . | USPTO Office Action dated May 24, 2010 re: U.S. Appl. No. 12/549,674. cited by other . | Office Action of Mar. 25, 2009 re U.S. Appl. No. 11/839,233, filed Aug. 15, 2007. cited by other . | Ward, Marsha D.W. et al; et al; Benefits and Risk in Malaria Control; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 310; Oct. 7, 2005; pp. 49. cited by other . | Parry, M.L. et al.; IPCC, 2007: Summary for Policymakers. In: Climate Change 2007: Impacts, Adaptation and Vulnerability. Contribution of Working Group II to the Fourth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change; Cambridge University Press, Cambridge UK. cited by other . | TheBioenergySite News Desk; Potential of Water Hyacinth in Biofuel Production; Nov. 13, 2008; pp. 1-2. cited by other . | Nyanza Gulf Communities (Kenya), et al., (Plaintiffs) vs. The World Bank, and Lake Victoria Environmental Management Project (LVEMP), et al. (Defendants); Sep. 1999; 1-10. cited by other . | PCT International Preliminary Report on Patentability(PCT/US2009/038280), Oct. 2010. cited by other. | Dodds, David R. and Gross, Richard A.; Chemicals from Biomass; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 318; Nov. 23, 2007; pp. 1250-1251. cited by other . | Biological Control of Invasive Plants; University of Florida; Aquatic, Wetland and Invasive Plant Information Retrieval System. cited by other . | Service, Robert F.; Profile: Jay Keasling--Rethinking Mother Nature's Choices; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 315; Feb. 9, 2007; pp. 793. cited by other . | Alternative Fuels: Biodiesel; http://www.epa.gov/smartway; EPA420-f06-044; Oct. 2006; pp. 1-2. cited by other . | Solomon, S., D et al.; Climate Change 2007, The Physical Science Basis; IPPC. 2007; Contribution of Working Group I to the Fourth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change; Canbridge University Press, Cambridge UK and NY USA 996pp p. 1-10. cited by other . | Scott, Elinor et al.; &quot;Biomass in the manufacture of industrial products--the use of proteins and amino acids&quot;; Appl Microbiol Biotechnol (2007) 75: 751-762. cited by other . | Office Action of Mar. 25, 2009 re U.S. Appl. No. 11/839,196, filed Aug. 15, 2007. cited by other . | Kintisch, Eli; Profile: Clint Chapple--How to Make Biofuels Truly Poplarwww.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 315; Feb. 9, 2007; pp. 786. cited by other . | Whitesides, George M. and Crabtree, George W.; Don't Forget Long-Term Fundamental Research in Energy; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 315; Feb. 9, 2007; pp. 796. cited by other . | Holm, L.G. et al.; The worlds worst weeds; CAB International abstract database; pp. 1-3 (article 2). cited by other . | NREL; &quot;Research Advances Cellulosic Ethanol; Enabling total control of ethanol production&quot;; National Renewable Energy Laboratory; Mar. 2007; pp. 1-8. cited by other . | Potocnik, Janez; Renewable Energy Sources and the Realities of Setting an Energy Agenda; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 315; Feb. 9, 2007; pp. 810-811. cited by other . | Dr. Faustino L. Orach-Meza and Dr. Tom Okurut; Background to the Preparation of the Second Phase of the Lake Victoria Environmental Management Project (LVEMP-II); Regional Stakeholders' Workshop on Launching of the Preparation of the LVEMP Phase Two (LVEMP-II); Jan. 2005; 1-36. cited by other . | PCT/US2009/038280 International Search Report dated May 26, 2010. cited by other . | Kintisch, Eli; Tropical Biofuels Getting Less and Less Green; ScienceNOW Daily News; Jul. 9, 2008; pp. 1-3. cited by other . | The Oil Drum Mission Statement Peak Oil Overview; Nov. 2008; C:\Documents and Settings\jsm\Local Settings\Temporary Internet Files\OLK35\Oil Drum.sub.--Energy and Our Future.htm (pp. 1-9); this work licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 United States License. cited by other . | Remick, Dr. Robert J.; Many Pathways to Renewable Hydrogen; Power Gen: Renewable Energy and Fuels 2008 conference held Feb. 19-21, 2008 in Las Vegas, Nevada; p 1-23. cited by other . | Ogoch, Ojwang; Un in Sh56m Kisumu Conservation Project; Capital Business; Feb. 12, 2009; Capital Business Capital Group Limited. cited by other . | Cho, Adrian; &quot;Profile: James Dumesic--Catalyzing the Emergence of a Practical Biorefinery&quot;; Science vol. 315 Feb. 9, 2007; p. 795. cited by other . | Aquatic, Wetland and Invasive Plant Particulars and Photographs, University of Florida Center for Aquatic and Invasive Plants. cited by other . | Supplemental Notice of Allowability of Aug. 6, 2009 re U.S. Appl. No. 11/839,077, filed Aug. 15, 2007. cited by other . | International Search Report for PCT/US2007/076145, dated Oct. 29, 2009. cited by other . | Clery, Daniel; Profile: Steven Koonin--Guilding an Oil Tanker Into Renewable Waters; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 315; Feb. 9, 2007; pp. 790. cited by other . | Goldemberg; Jose; Ethanol for a Sustainable Engergy Future; www.sciencemag.org; Science; vol. 315; Feb. 9, 2007; pp 808-810. cited by other . | Aquarius Systems; The Solution re LVEMP Lake Victoria Environmental Management Project; pp. 1-3. cited by other . | Roberts; Leslie; New Malaria Plan Called Ambitious by Some, Unrealistic by Others; Science vol. 322; Oct. 3, 2008; p. 26-27. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		76
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US20060283977 | US4575426 | US4129431 | US6006644 | US3766583 | US3700108 | US6269763 | US4114552 | US3800715 | US2330508 | US5160638 | US4356094 | US6945187 | US5948266 | US4153555 | US4043140 | US4031707 | US4223536 | US4157016 | US6233949 | US3614873 | US3338414 | US5143629 | US5071545 | US4960347 | US3979953 | US4153537 | US4060487 | US4456536 | US3643804 | US5632150 | US5045216 | US4420400 | US5137558 | US4491484 | US5075014 | US4061569 | US4409034 | US4492001 | GB2007747 | WO2002077563 | WO1999004101 | PCT/US1920/07076145
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		43
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		DE, STRULLE, RONALD
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		DE, STRULLE, RONALD
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Carmel, NY
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Carmel, NY
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		FISH &amp; RICHARDSON P.C.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		UPTON, CHRISTOPHER
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

