<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US8048317
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11301627
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Generation of free radicals, analytical methods, bacterial disinfections, and oxidative destruction of organic chemicals using zero valent iron and other metals
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Disclosed are methods for chemical analysis, bacterial disinfection, oxidative destruction and/or mineralization of organic compounds comprising using zero-valent iron and/or zero-valent iron-containing bimetallic compounds, preferably in acidic solution and/or in the presence of oxygen.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2005-12-13
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2005
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2005-12
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-11-01
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-11
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F1/72
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F1/72
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		422/28 | 210/763 | 210/764 | 210/909 | 210/908 | 424/646
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		422/28
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		422
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Cabrera, et al., Acid Mine-Water and Agricultural Pollution in a River Skirting the Donana National Park (Guadiamar River. South West Spain), Water Res. (1984), vol. 18, No. 12, pp. 1469-1482. cited by other . | Alfaro, G., et al., Liquid Analysis by Dry-Extract Near-Infrared Reflectance on Fiberglass, Appl. Spectrosc., (1990) vol. 44, pp. 979-986. cited by other . | Kanel, et al., Removal of Arsenic(III) from Groundwater by Nanoscale Zero-Valent Iron, Environ. Sci. Technol., (2005), vol. 39, pp. 1291-1298. cited by other . | Deutsch, et al., Ascorbate and Dehydroascorbate Measurements in Aqueous Solutions and Plasma Determined by Gas Chromatography-Mass Spectrometry, Anal. Chem., (1993), vol. 65, pp. 321-326. cited by other . | Lobry De Bryuyn, et al., Contributions a la Connaissance Des Corps Aromatiques Nitres, (1985), Amsterdam, pp. 150-155. cited by other . | Barbeni, et al., Chemical Degradation of Chlorophenols with Fenton's Reagent, Chemosphere (1987) vol. 16, Nos. 10-12, pp. 2225-2237. cited by other . | Fleming, et al., Integrated Zero-Valent Iron and Dark Oxidation Processes for In-Situ Remediation of Explosives in Groundwater, U.S. Army Engineer Research and Development Center, Waterways Experiment Station. cited by other . | Matheson, et al., Reductive Dehalogenation of Chlorinated Methanes by Iron Metal, Eviron. Sci. Technol., (1994), vol. 28, pp. 2045-2053. cited by other . | Giangiacomo, et al., Near Infrared Spectrophotometric Determination of Individual Sugars in Aqueous Mixtures, Journal of Food Science, (1986), vol. 51, No. 3, pp. 679-683. cited by other . | Kosugi, et al., Formation of Yellow, Orange, and Red Pigments in the Reaction of Alk-2-enals with 2-Thiobarbituric Acid, Analytical Biochemistry, (1987), vol. 165, pp. 456-464. cited by other . | Kishida, et al., Specific Determination of Ascorbic Acid with Chemical Derivatization and High-Performance Liquid Chromatography, Anal. Chem., (1992), vol. 64, pp. 1505-1507. cited by other . | Pachla, et al., Analytical Methods for Determining Ascorbic Acid in Biological Samples, Food Products, and Pharmaceuticals, J. Assoc. Off. Anal. Chem., (1985), vol. 68, No. 1, pp. 1-12. cited by other . | Lima de Souza, C., Degradation of Reactive Corantes for the System Metallic Iron/Hydrogen Peroxide, Quim. New (2005), vol. 28 in the, 2 Sao Paulo Sea. cited by other . | Lanza, et al., Application for Near Infrared Spectroscopy for Predicting the Sugar Content of Fruit Juices, Journal of Food Science, (1984), vol. 49, pp. 995-998. cited by other . | Deutsch, et al., Variation in Ascorbic Acid Oxidation Routes in H2O2 and Cupric Ion Solution as Determined by GC/MS, Anal. Chem. (1994), vol. 66, pp. 345-350. cited by other . | Gharsallah, N., Production of Single Cell Protein From Olive Mill Wastewater by Yeasts, Environmental Technology, (1993), vol. 14, pp. 391-395. cited by other . | Ghauch, A., Degradation of Benomyl, Picloram, and Dicamba in a Conical Apparatus by Zero-Valent Iron Powder, Chemosphere (2004), vol. 43, pp. 1109-1117. cited by other . | Li, et al., Quantitative Analysis of Individual Sugars and Acids in Orange Juices by Near-Infrared Spectroscopy of Dry Extract, J. Agric. Food Chem., (1996), vol. 44, pp. 2252-2259. cited by other . | Mukhopadhyay, et al., Ascorbic Acid Prevents Lipid Peroxidation and Oxidative Damage of Proteins in Guinea Pig Extrahepatic Tissue Microsomes, Molecular and Cellular Biochemistry, (1995), vol. 142, pp. 71-78. cited by other . | Bergendahl, et al., Fenton's oxidation of MTBE with zero-valent iron, Water Research 38 (2004), pp. 327-334. cited by other . | Arya, S., Colorimetric Determination of Ascorbic Acid in Pharmaceutical Preparations and Biological Samples, Mikrochim. Acta, (1997) vol. 127, pp. 45-49. cited by other . | Slater, T, Free-Radical Mechanisms in Tissue Injury, Biochem J. (1984), vol. 222, pp. 1-15. cited by other . | Martin-Fernandez, et al., Subnanosecod Polarized Microfluorimetry in the Time Domain: An Instrument for Studying Receptor Trafficking in Live Cells, Review of Scientific Instruments, (1998), vol. 69, No. 2, pp. 540-543. cited by other . | Morales, et al., Hydrogenation of Phenol by the Pd/Mg and Pd/Fe Bimetallic Systems under Mild Reaction Conditions, Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. (2002), vol. 41, pp. 3071-3074. cited by other . | Tyre, et al., Treatment of Four Biorefractory Contaminants in Soils Using Catalyzed Hydrogen Peroxide, J. Environ. Qual., (1991), vol. 20, pp. 832-838. cited by other . | Cheeseman, K., et al., An Introduction to Free Radical Biochemistry, Br. Med. Bull., (1993), vol. 29, No. 3, pp. 481-493. cited by other . | Joo, et al., Oxidative Degradation of the Carbothioate Herbicide, Molinate, Using Nanoscale Zero-Valent Iron, Environ. Sci. Technol. (2004) vol. 38, pp. 2242-2247. cited by other . | Frei, et al., Ascorbate is an Outstanding Antioxidant in Human Blood Plasma, Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA, (1989), vol. 86, pp. 6377-6381. cited by other . | Martin, et al., Kinetic Study of an Anaerobic Fluidized Bed System Used for the Purification of Fermented Olive Mill Wastewater, J. Chem. Tech., (1993), vol. 56, pp. 155-162. cited by other . | Sanjust, et al., Olive Milling Wastewater as a Medium for Growth of Four Pleurotus Species, Applied Biochemistry and Biotechnology, (1991), vol. 31, pp. 223-235. cited by other . | Mukhopadhyay, et al., NADPH-Initiated Cytochrome P450-mediated Free Metal Ion-independent Oxidative Damage of Microsomal Proteins, The Journal of Biological Chemistry, (1994), vol. 269, No. 18, pp. 13390-13397. cited by other . | McClure, et al., Two-Dimensional Correlation of Fourier Transform Near-Infrared and Fourier Transform Raman Spectra I: Mixtures of Sugar and Protein, Applied Spectroscopy, (1996), vol. 50, pp. 467-475. cited by other . | Ghauch, A., et al., Rapid Treatment of Water Contaminated with Atrazine and Parathion with Zero-Valent Iron, Chemosphere, (1999), vol. 39, No. 8, pp. 1309-1315. cited by other . | Burbano, et al., Oxidation kinetics and effect of pH on the degradation of MTBE with Fenton reagent, Water Research 39 (2005), pp. 107-118. cited by other . | Trifiro, et al., Use of Iron Chromatography for Monitoring Microbial Spoilage in the Fruit Juice Industry, Journal of Chromatography A, (1997), vol. 770, pp. 243-252. cited by other . | Vogel, et al., Transformations of Halogenated Aliphatic Compounds, Environ. Sci. Technol., (1987), vol. 21, No. 8, pp. 722-736. cited by other. | Joo, et al., Quantification of the Oxidizing Capacity of Nanoparticulate Zero-Valent Iron, Environ. Sci. Technol. (2005), vol. 39, pp. 1263-1268. cited by other . | Hamdi, et al., Future Prospects and Constraints of Olive Mill Wastewaters Use and Treatment: A Review, Bioprocess Engineering, (1993), vol. 8, pp. 209-214. cited by other . | Gutteridge, J, Reactivity of Hydroxyl and Hvdroxyl-Like Radicals Discriminated by Release of Thiobarbituric Acid-Reactive Material from Deoxy Sugars. Nucleosides and Benzoate, Biochem. J., (1984), vol. 224., pp. 761-767. cited by other . | Dong, C., Destruction of Hazardous Organic Contaminants by Advanced Oxidation Processes, A dissertation submitted to the Faculty of the University of Delaware, (Summer 1993), pp. 1-232. cited by other . | Hall, et al., Mechanochemical Reaction of DDT with Calcium Oxide, Environ. Sci., (1996), vol. 30, No. 12, pp. 3401-3407. cited by other . | Kissinger, et al., Determination of Ascorbic Acid and Dehydroascorbic Acid Using Liquid Chromatography with Ultraviolet and Electrochemical Detection, Food Technology, (1987), pp. 108-111. cited by other . | Lau, et al., Background Correction Method for the Determination of Ascorbic Acid in Soft Drinks. Fruit Juices and Cordials Using Direct Ultraviolet Spectrophotometry, Analyst, (1986), vol. 111, pp. 665-670. cited by other . | Cheng I., et al., Electrochemical Dechlorination of 4-Chlorophenol to Phenol, Environ. Sci. Technol, (1997), vol. 31, pp. 1074-1078. cited by other . | Sayles, et al., DDT, DDD, and DDE Dechlorination by Zero-Valent Iron, Environ. Sci. Technol., (1997), vol. 31, pp. 3448-3454. cited by other . | Bowers, et al., Treatment of Toxic or Refractory Wastewaters with Hydrogen Peroxide. Wat. Sci. Tech. (1989) vol. 21, Brighton, pp. 477-486. cited by other . | Sultan, et al., Flow Injection of Colorimetric Method for the Assay of Vitamin C in Drug Formulations Using Tris, 1-10-Phenanthroline-Iron(III) Complex as an oxidant in Sulfuric Acid Media, Talanta, (1994), vol. 41, No. 1, pp. 125-130. cited by other . | Fridovich, Irwin, Superoxide Radical: An Endogenous Toxicant, Ann. Rev. Pharmacol. Toxicol. cited by other . | Gauch, A., et al., Reductive Degradation of Carbaryl in Water by Zero-Valent Iron, Chemosphere (2001), vol. 42, pp. 419-424. cited by other . | Ferreira, et al., Sensitive Spectrophotometric Determination of Ascorbic Acid in Fruit Juices and Pharmaceutical Formulations Using 2-(5-Bromo-2-Pyridylazo)-5-Diethylaminophenol (Br-PADAP), (1997), Fresenius J. Anal. Chem., vol. 357, pp. 1174-1178. cited by other . | Kim, Hie-Joon, Determination of Total Vitamin C by Ion Exclusion Chromatography with Electrochemical Detection, (1989), Anal. Chem., vol. 72, pp. 681-686. cited by other . | Deutsch, et al., Microfluorometric Assay for Vitamin C, Journal of the A.O.A.C., (1965), vol. 48, No. 6, pp. 1248-1256. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		52
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5534154 | US7897049 | US5975800 | US5935609 | US5198118 | US3640821 | US5616253 | US6306641 | US5266213 | US6787034 | US5149437 | US6221262 | US20070256713 | US4382865 | US20030173306 | US20060249465 | US5178768 | US6207073 | US7507345 | US5352369 | US6942807 | US7008964 | US20030196966 | US5975798 | US7128841 | WO2005028378 | WO2005003797
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		27
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		UNIVERSITY OF HAWAII
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		UNIVERSITY OF HAWAII
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Honolulu, HI
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Honolulu, HI
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		RIMA, JAMIL | LI, QING, X. | AOUEZOVA, LIZETTE
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		RIMA, JAMIL
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Beirut, LB
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Beirut, LB | Honolulu, HI | Beirut, LB
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		KNOBBE, MARTENS, OLSON &amp; BEAR, LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		HRUSKOCI, PETER A
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

