<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US8021556
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11651436
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Method of clarifying industrial wastewater for the reduction of organic waste content using cationic dispersion polymers combined with powdered activated carbon and anionic flocculent polymers
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A method is provided for clarifying wastewater containing contaminants including soluble organic compounds and insoluble organic compounds. The wastewater is treated with a paculant admixture including a cationic coagulant polymer and powdered activated carbon. The cationic coagulant polymer is polydiallydimethylammonium chloride, poly quaternary amine, and/or a starch-based organic polymer. After an at least 2 second delay, a flocculent is added to the wastewater to achieve (i) microcoagulation of the cationic coagulant polymer with the contaminants to form coagulated particles having an effective mass and cationic charge to react with an anionic flocculent to be added thereafter, and (ii) absorption of the soluble organic compounds on the powdered activated carbon. The anionic flocculent as added and reacted with the coagulated particles to form a sludge, containing agglomerated particles including the coagulated particles and powdered activated carbon, of sufficient size for mechanical removal. The sludge is removed to provide clarified wastewater.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2007-01-09
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2007
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2007-01
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-09-20
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-09
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F1/56 | C02F1/28
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F1/56
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/734 | 210/735 | 210/727 | 210/714 | 210/694 | 210/666 | 210/731
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/734
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US4737293 | US4274968 | US7291275 | US7160470 | US6319412 | US4668404 | EP0001291295
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		7
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		DAVIS, STUART, G. | DAVIS, ROBERT, A.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		DAVIS, STUART, G.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Fernandina, Beach, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Fernandina, Beach, FL | Carmel, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		BERENATO &amp; WHITE, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		HRUSKOCI, PETER A
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

