<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US8057682
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12/667384
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Green synthesis of nanometals using plant extracts and use thereof
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The present invention relates to methods of making and using and compositions of metal nanoparticles formed by green chemistry synthetic techniques. For example, the present invention relates to metal nanoparticles formed with solutions of plant extracts and use of these metal nanoparticles in removing contaminants from soil and groundwater and other contaminated sites. In some embodiments, the invention comprises methods of making and using compositions of metal nanoparticles formed using green chemistry techniques.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2009-05-18
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2009-05
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-11-15
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-11
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/688
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/688
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Adventus Group. Groundwater Solutions. Accessed Apr. 15, 2007, www.adventusgroup.com/solutions/groundwater.shtml. cited by other . | Sun Y, Xia Y. Shape-Controlled Synthesis of Gold and Silver Nanoparticles. Science 2002, 298: 2176. cited by other . | Niu S-F, Liu Y, Xu X-H, Lou Z-H. Removal of hexavalent chromium from aqueous solution by iron Nanoparticles. J. Zhejiang Univ Sci B 2005, 6(10): 1022-1027. cited by other . | International Search Report and Written Opinion issued in International Application No. PCT/US2008/011235, mailed on Dec. 19, 2008. cited by other . | Das, SK, Butler, R M. Mechanism of the Vapor Extraction Process for Heavy Oil and Bitumen. J Petroleum Sci. and Eng. 1998. 21: 43-59. cited by other . | Shiau. BJ, Sabatini DA, Harwell JH. Solubilization and mobilization of DNAPLs using direct food additive (edible) surfactants. Ground Water 1994, 32: 561-569. cited by other . | Song H, Rioux RM, Hoefelmeyer JD, Komor R, Niesz K, Grass M, Yang P, Somorjai GA. Hydrothermal Growth and Mesaporous SBA-15 Silica in the Presence of PVP-Stabilized PT Nanoparticles: Synthesis, Characterization, and Catalytic Properties J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2006, 128: 3027. cited by other . | Zeveloff J, Inventor Sues Soil Remediation Co. Over Patents. Portfolio Media. Inc., Oct. 2008, New York NY. cited by other . | Powell RM, Puls RW, Hightower SK, Sabatini DA. Coupled Iron Corrosion and Chromate Reduction: Mechanisms for Subsurface Remediation. Environ. Sci. Technol. 1995, 29: 1913-1922. cited by other . | Interstate Technology &amp; Regulatory Council Dense Nonaqueous Phase Liquids Team, Technical and Regulatory Guidance for Surfactant/Cosolvent Flushing of DNAPL Source Zones, Apr. 2003. cited by other . | Jafvert CT, Technology Evaluation Report: Surfactants/Cosolvents. Dec. 1996, Gound-Wter Remediation Analysis Center, Pittsburgh, PA. cited by other . | Bergendahl J, Thies T. Fenton's Oxidation of MTBE with Zero-valent Iron. 2004. Water Research. 38:327-334. cited by other . | Beal DR, Faircloth H, Tackling Tough Groundwater Contaminants: the presence of dense non-aqueous-phase liquids (DNAPLs) in the sub-surfaces requires some unconventional approaches to site investigation and remediation, Chemical Engineering, Mar. 2002, 91-94. cited by other . | USDA 2007. Oxygen Radical Absorbance Capacity (ORAC) of Selected Foods-2007. Nutrient Data Laboratory, Beltsville Human Nutrition Research Center, Agricultural Research Service. cited by other . | Kotterman MJ, Rietberg HJ, Hage A, Field JA. Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon oxidation by white-rot fungus Bjerkandera sp. Strain BOS55 in the presence of non-ionic surfactants. Biotechnology and Bioengineering 1997, 57: 220-227. cited by other . | Zhang W-X. Nanoscale iron particles for environmental remediation: An overview. J. Nanoparticle Research 2003, 5: 323-332. cited by other . | Falta RW. Using Phase Diagrams to Predict the Performance of Cosolvent Floods for NAPL Remediation. Ground Water Monit. Rem. 1998, 18(3): 227-232. cited by other . | Arcadis. Perchlorate. www.arcadis-us.com. cited by other . | Ponder SM, Darab JG, Mallouk TE. Remediation of Cr(VI) and Pb(II) aqueous solutions using supported, nanoscale zero-valent iron. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2000, 34: 2564-2569. cited by other . | House DA, Kinetics and Mechanism of Oxidations by Peroxydisulfate, Chemistry Review 1962, 62: 185-200. cited by other . | Anastas PT, Warner JC. Green Chemistry: Theory and Practice, Oxford University Press, Inc: New York. 1998. cited by other . | Jawitz, JW, Annable, MD, Rao, PSC, Rhue, RD. Field Implementation of a Winsor Type 1 Surfactant. Alcohol Mixture for in Situ Solubilization of a Complex LNAPL as a Single-Phase Microemulsion. 1998. Environ. Sci. Technol., 32:523-530. cited by other . | Narayan A, Landstrom L, Boman M. Laser-assisted synthesis of ultra small metal nanoparticles. Appl. Surf Sci 2003, 137: 208. cited by other . | Wang CC, Chen DH, Huang TC, Synthesis of palladium nanaparticles in water-in-oil microemulsions. Colloids ad Surfaces A: Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects 2001, 189: 145. cited by other . | Nadagouda et al., &quot;Green Synthesis of AU Nanostructures at Room Temperature Using Biodegradable Plant Surfactants,&quot; Crystal Growth and Design, vol. 9, No. 11, 2009. cited by other . | International Search Report and the Written Opinion of the International Searching Authority for PCT/US2007/007517, Nov. 27, 2008. cited by other . | Jain et al. Synthesis of Plant-Mediated Silver Nanoparticles Using Papaya Fruit Extract and Evaluation of their Anti Microbial Activities. 2009. Digest Journal of Nanomaterials and Biostructures. 4(3):557-563. cited by other . | Ponder S, Darab JG, Bucher J, Caulder D, Craig I, Davis L, Edelstein N, Lukens W, Nitsche H, Rao L, Shuh DK, Mallouk TE. Surface chemistry and electrochemistry of supported zerovalent iron nanoparticles in the remediation of aqueous metal contaminants. Chem. Mater. 2001, 13(2): 479-486. cited by other . | Roote, Diane S. Technology Status Report In Situ Flushing: Ground-Water Remediation Technologies Analysis Center, Pittsburg, PA, Nov. 1998. cited by other . | International Search Report for International Application No. PCT/US2009/044402, mailed Apr. 12, 2010. cited by other . | Wei JJ, Xu XH, Liu Y. Kinetics and mechanism of dechlorination of o-chlorophenol by nanoscale. Pd/Fe. Chem Res Chinese U. 2004;20:73-76. cited by other . | Office Action in U.S. Appl. No. 12/893,826 mailed on Jun. 17, 2011. cited by other. | Wiley BJ, Chen Y, McLellan JM, Xiong Y, Li Z-Y, Ginger D, Xia Y. Synthesis and Optical Properties of Silver Nanobars. Nano Letters 2007, 4: 1032. cited by other . | Uyeda R. Studies of Ultrafine Particles in Japan: Crystallography, Methods of Preparation and Technological Applications. Prog. Mater. Sci. 1991, 35: 1. cited by other . | International Search Report and Written Opinion issued in International Application No. PCT/US2008/11229, mailed on Dec. 9, 2008. cited by other . | Ankamwar et al. Biosynthesis of Gold and Silver Nanoparticles Using Umbilica Officinalis Fruit Extract, Their Phase Transfer and Transmetallation in an Organic Solution. 2005. Journal Nanoscience and Nanotechnology, 5(10):1665-1671. cited by other . | Liang CJ, Bruell CJ, Marley MC, Sperry KL Persulfate oxidation for in situ remediation of TCE I: Activated by ferrous ion with and without a persulfate-thiosulfate redox couple. Chemosphere 2004, 55(9), 1213-1223. cited by other . | Li Zhaohui, Surfactant-enhanced oxidation of trichloroethylene by permanganate- proof of concept. Chemosphere 2004, 54:419-423. cited by other . | Choi CW, Kin SC, Hwang SS, Choi BK, Ahn HJ, Lee MY, Park SH, Kim SK. Antioxidant activity and free radical scavenging capacity between Korean medicinal plants and flavonoid by assay-guided comparison. Plant Science 2002, 16: 1161-1168. cited by other . | Luong HV, Lin HK. Controlling Fenton reaction for soil remediation. Analytical Letters 2000, 33(14), 3051-3065. cited by other . | Kumar A, Vemula PK, Ajayan PM, John G., Silver Nanoparticle-Embedded Antimicrobial Paints Based on Vegetable Oil, Nature Materials 2008, 7: 236-241. cited by other . | Sundstrom DW, Allen JS, Fenton SS, Salimi FE, Walsh KJ, Treatment of Chelated Iron and Copper Wastes by Chemical Oxidation, J Environ Sci Health 1996, A31: 1215. cited by other . | Peters, S.M. et al. A Laboratory Study on the Degradation of Gasoline Contamination Using Fenton's Reagent , Proceedings 54th Canadian Geotechnical Conference, 2001 An Earth Odyssey, p. 1170-1177. cited by other . | Yen GC, Chen F. Antioxidant activity of various tea extracts in relation to their antimutagenicity. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry 1995, 45: 27-32. cited by other . | Juliano LM, Griffiths RR. A critical review of caffeine withdrawal: empirical validation of symptoms and signs, incidence, severity, and associated features. Psychopharmacology 2004, 176, 1. cited by other . | Raveendran P, Fu J, Wallen SL. Completely &quot;Green&quot; Synthesis and Stabilization of Metal Nanoparticles, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2003, 125: 13940. cited by other . | Pirkanniemi K, Sillanpaa M, Sorokin A. Degradative Science of the Total Environment 2003, 307: 1-3, 11-18. cited by other . | Kislenko VN, Berlin AA, Litovchenko NV, Kinetics of Oxidation of Glucose by Persulfate Ions in the Presence of Mn (II) Ions, Kinetics and Catalysis 1997, 38(3): 391-396. cited by other . | Florida Chemical Company, Material Safety Data Sheet for Citrus Burst 3. Jul. 2007, Winter Haven, FL. cited by other . | Sweeny, KH. 1981 b. The Reductive Treatment of Industrial Wastewater: I. Process Description. American Institute of Chemical Engineers, Symposium Series, Water-1980 Ed. GF Nennett, 209(77): 72-78. cited by other . | Nadagouda MN, Varma RS. Green and Controlled Synthesis of Gold and Platinum Nanomaterials Using Vitamin B2: Density-Assisted Self Assembly of Nanospheres, Wires and Rods, Green Chem. 2006, 8: 516. cited by other . | Kile, DE, Chiou, CT. Water Solubility Enhancements of DDT and Trichlorobenzene by Some Surfactants Below and Above the Critical Micelle Concentration. Environ. Sci. Technol. 1989, 23:832-838. cited by other . | Liang CJ, Bruell CH, Marley MC, Sperry, KL. Thermally activated persulfate oxidation of trichloroethylene (TCE) and 1,1,1-trichloroethane (TCA) in aqueous systems and soil slurries. 2003. Soil &amp; Sediment Contamination 2003, 12(2): 207-228. cited by other . | Du J, Han B, Liu Z, Liu Y, Kang DJ. Control Synthesis of Silver Nanosheets, Chainlike Sheets, and Microwires via a Simple Solvent-Thermal Method. Crystal Growth and Design 2007, 7: 900. cited by other . | Xiong Y, Cai H, Wiley BJ, Wang J, Kim MJ, Xia Y. Synthesis and Mechanistic Study of Palladium Nanobars and Nanorods. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2007, 129: 3665. cited by other . | Kolthoff IM, Medalia AI, Raaen HP The Reaction Between Ferrous Iron and Peroxides IV Reaction with Potassium Sulfate, Journal of American Chemical Society 1951, 73: 1733-1739. cited by other . | Xu Y, Zhang W. Subcolloidal Fe/Ag particles for reductive dehalogenation of chlorinated benzenes. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2000, 39(7): 2238-2244. cited by other . | Chang M, Shu H, Yu H. An Integrated technique using Zero Valent Iron and UV/H202 Sequential Process form Complete Decolorization and Mineralization of C.I. Acid Black 24 Wastewater. Journal of Hazardous Materials 2006, B 138: 574-581. cited by other . | Nadagouda MN, Varma RS. Preparation of novel metallic and bimetallic cross-linked poly (vinly alcohol) nanocomposites under microwave irradiation. Macromolecular Rapid Communications 2007, 28: 465-472. cited by other . | Zheng Z, Obbard JP. Polycyclic Aromatic Hydrocarbon Removal from Soil by Surfactant Solubilization and Phanerochaete chrysosporium Oxidation. J. Environ. Qual. 2002, 31: 1842-1847. cited by other . | Dahl JA, Maddux LS, Hutchison JE, Toward Greener Nanosynthesis, Chem. Rev. 2007, 107: 2228. cited by other . | Martel R, Gelinas P. Surfactant solutions developed for NAPL recovery in contaminated aquifers. Ground Water 1996, 34: 143-154. cited by other . | Martel R, Gelinas PJ, Desnoyers JE, Masson A. Phase Diagrams to Optimize Surfactant Solutions for Oil and DNAPL Recovery in Aquifers, Ground Water 1993, 31: 789-800. cited by other . | Wang X, Li Y. Monodisperse nanocrystals: general synthesis, assembly, and their applications. Chem Commun Camb 2007, 28: 2901-2910. cited by other . | Schramm et al. The Influence of Interfacial tension in the recovery of bitumen by water-based conditioning and flotation of Athabasca oil sands. Fuel Processing Technology 2003, 80: 101-118. cited by other . | Nadagouda MN, Varma RS. A Greener Synthesis of Core (Fe, Cu)-Shell (Au, Pt, Pd and Ag) Nanocrystals Using Aqueous Vitamin C, Crystal Growth and Design 2007, 7(12): 2582-2587. cited by other . | Wang C-B, Zhang W. Synthesizing nanoscale iron particles for rapid and complete dechlorination of TCE and PCBs. Environ. Sci. Technol. 1997, 31(7): 2154-2156. cited by other . | Regenesis. Enhanced Aerobic Bioremediation, Accessed Apr. 15, 2007, www.regenesis.com/products/enhAer/. cited by other . | Wiley B, Herricks T, Sun Y, Xia Y. Polyol synthesis of silver nanoparticles: Use of chloride and oxygen to promote the formation of single-crystal, truncated cubes &amp; tetrahedrons. Nano Letters 2004, 4: 1733-1739. cited by other . | Sweeny, KH. 1981 a. The Reductive Treatment of Industrial Wastewater: II. Process Applications. American Institute of Chemical Engineers, Symposium Series, Water-1980 Fd. G.F. Nennett. 209(77): 67-71. cited by other . | Frankel AJ, Owsianiak, LM, Wuerl, BJ, Horst, JF. In-Situ Anaerobic Remediation of Perchlorate-Impacted Soils. Arcadis US. cited by other . | Goi et al. Combined chemcial and biological treatment of oil contaminated soil. Chemosphere. Pergamon Press. Oxford. GB. 2006. vol. 63:10. 1754-1763. cited by other . | Guha S, Jaffe PR. Biodegradation kinetics of phenanthrene partitioned into the micellar phase of nonionic surfactants. Env. Sci. &amp; Tech. 1996, 30: 605-611. cited by other . | Stone JW, Sisco PN, Goldsmith EC, Baxter SC, Murphy CJ. Using gold nanorods to probe cell-induced collagen deformation. Nano Letters 2007, 7: 116. cited by other . | Collins, John and Hoag, George. Coelution Technologies and Surfactant-Enhanced in Situ Oxidation as new breakthrough technologies in the treatmen of toxic subsurface contaminants. 11th Annual Green Chemistry and Engineering Conference. 2007. Retrieved Mar. 25, 2009. http://acs.confex.com/acs/green07/techprogram/P42826.htm. cited by other . | Swe, MM, Yu, LE, Hung, KC, Chen, BH. Solubilization of Selected Polycyclic Aromatic Compounds by Nonionic Surfactants. Journal of Surfactants and Detergents. 2006, 9:3, 237-244. cited by other . | Diallo et al. Solubilization of nonaqueous phase liquid hydrocarbons in micellar solution of dodecyl alcohol ethoxylates . Environ. Sci. Technol. 1994. 1829-1837. cited by other . | Chen J, McLellan JM, Siekkinen AY, Xiong Y, Li ZY, Xia Y. Facile synthesis of gold-silver nanocages with controllable pores on the surface. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2006, 128: 14776. cited by other . | Baruwati, B. and Varma, R. High Value Products from Waste: Grape Pomace Extract- A Three-in-One Package for the Synthesis of Metal Nanoparticles. ChemSisChem. 2:1041-1044. published online on Oct. 19, 2009. cited by other . | International Search Report and Written Opinon for PCT/US2008/008905 mailed May 7, 2009. cited by other . | Georgetti SR, Casagrande R, Di Mambro, VM, Azzolini, AECS, Fonseca, MJV. Evaluation of the Antioxidant of Different Flavonoids by the Chemiluminescence Method. AAPA PharmSci. 2003. 5(2) Article 20. cited by other . | Carvel DD, Cartwright RT Innovative heavy oil contaminant remediation at typical MGP remediation sites. 2005. Unpublished data from web sites: http://www.mecx.net/services1.html. cited by other . | Yeom IT, Ghosh MM. Mass transfer limitation in PAH-contaminated soil remediation. Water Sci. Tech 1998, 37: 111-118. cited by other . | Edwards, DA, Luthy, RG, Lly, Z. Solubilization of Polycyclic Hydrocarbons in Micellar Nonionic Surfactant Solutions. 1991 Environ. Sci. Technol. 25:127-133. cited by other . | EOS Remediation Inc. Emulsified Edible Oils for Anaerobic Bioremediation. Accessed Apr. 15, 2007, www.eosremediation.com. cited by other . | Office Action issued by the USPTO for U.S. Appl. No. 12/680,103 on Jul. 15, 2010. cited by other . | Adventus Group. Products: Overview for Accelerated Bioremediation. Accessed Apr. 15, 2007, www.adventusgroup.com/products/technologies.shtml. cited by other . | Boussahel R, Harik D, Mammar M, Lanara-Mohamed S. Degradation of Obsolete DDT by Fenton Oxidation with Zero-Valent Iron., Desalination 2007, 206: 369-372. Presented at the EuroMed 2006 Conference on Desalination Strategies in South Mediterranean Countries, Montpellier, France May 21-25, 2006. cited by other . | Chun H, Scriven LE. Hydrodynamic model of steady movement of a solid/liquid/fluid contact line. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 1971, 35: 85-101. cited by other . | Moschopedis SE. et al. Surface-active materials from Athabasca oil sands. Fuel processing Technology 1980, 3: 55-61. cited by other . | International Search Report and Written Opinion for PCT/US08/011228 mailed May 28, 2009. cited by other . | Huang K, Couttenye RA, Hoag G. Kinetics of heat-assisted persulfate exidation of methyl tert-butyl ether (MTBE). Chemosphere 2002, 49(4), 413-420. cited by other . | Naik RR, Stringer SJ, Agarwal G, Jones SE, Stone MO. Nature Mater. 2002, 1: 169. cited by other . | Schrick B, Blough J, Jones A, Mallouk TE. Hydrodechlorination of trichloroethylene to hydrocarbons using bimetallic nickel-iron nanoparticles. Chem. Mater. 2002, 14(12): 5140-5147. cited by other . | Wiley B, Sun Y, Xia Y. Synthesis of silver nanostructures with controlled shapes and properties. Acc. Chem. Res 2007. 40: 1067. cited by other . | Nadagouda MN, Varma RS. Green synthesis of silver and palladium nanoparticles at room temperature using coffe and tea extract. Royal Society of Chemistry. Green Chem 2008, 10: 859-862. cited by other . | He F, Zhao D. Preparation and characterization of a new class of starch-stabilized bimetallic nanoparticles for degradation of chlorinated hydrocarbons in water. Environ Sci Technol. 2005, 39: 3314-3320. cited by other . | Nadagouda MN, Varma RS. Green Chem. 2007, 9: 632. cited by other . | Gillham RW, O'Hannesin SF. Enhanced degradation of halogenated aliphatics by zero-valent iron. Ground Water 1994, 32(6): 959-967. cited by other . | Regenesis. Remediation Products. Accessed Apr. 15, 2007, www.regenesis.com. cited by other . | Coutteneye RA, Huang KC, Hoag GE, Suib SL. Evidence of Sulfate Free Radical (SO4-'') Formation under Heat-assisted Persulfate Oxidation of MTBE. Proceedings of the 19th Petroleum Hydrocarbons and Organic Chemicals in Ground Water: Prevention, Assessment, and Remediation, Conference and Exposition, Atlanta, GA, United States, Nov. 5-8, 2002, 345-350. cited by other . | Zhang W, Wang C, Lien H. Treatment of chlorinated organic contaminants with nanoscale bimetallic particles. Catal. Today 1998, 40(4): 387-395. cited by other . | Zhang H, Jin Z-H, Han L, Qin C-H. Synthesis Of nanoscale zero-valent iron supported on exfoliated graphite for removal of nitrate. Transactions of Nonferrous Metals Society of China 2006, 16(1): s345-s349. cited by other . | Block, PA, Brown RA, Robinson, D. Novel activation technologies for sodium persulfate in situ chemical oxidation. Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on the Remediation of Chlorinated and Recalcitrant Compounds, Monterey, CA, May 2004. Batelle Press, Columbus, OH. 2004. cited by other . | Wu X, Beecher GR, Holden JM, Haytowitz DB, Gebhardt SE, Prior RL. Lipophilic and hydrophilic antioxidant capacities of common foods in the United States. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry 2004, 52: 4026-4037. cited by other . | Blum YD, Kambe N, Chaloner-Gill B, Chiruvolu S, Kumar S, MacQueen DB. Naoncomposites by Covalent Bonding between Inorganic Nanoparticles and Polymers. Materials Research Society Symposium Proceedings 2001, 676: 1.8.1. cited by other . | Nadagouda MN, Varma RS. Crystal Growth and Design 2007, 7(4): 686-690. cited by other . | Nadagouda MN, Varma RS. Microwave Assisted Shape Controlled Bulk Synthesis of Ag and Fe Nanorods in Poly(ethylene glycol) Solutions, Crystal Growth and Design 2008, 8(1): 291-295. cited by other . | Regenesis. Chemical Oxidation. Accessed Apr. 15, 2007, www.regenesis.com/products/chemOx/. cited by other . | Murphy CJ, Gole AM, Hunyadi SE, Orendorff CJ. One-Dimensional Colloidai Gold and Silver Nanostructures. Inorg Chem 2006, 45(19): 7544-7554. cited by other . | Nadagouda MN, Varma RS. Synthesis of thermally stable carboxymethyl cellulose/metal biodegradable nanocomposites for potential biological applications. Biomacromolecules. 2007, 8(9): 2762-2767. cited by other . | Flaming JE, Knox RC, Sabatini DA, Kibbey TC, Surfactant Effects on Residual Water and Oil Saturations in Porous Media. 2003, Vadose Zone Journal 2:168-176. cited by other . | Hatano T, Kagawa H, Yasuhara T, Okuda T. Two new flavonoids and other constituents in licorice root: their relative astringency and radical scavenging effect. Chem. Phar. Bull. 1998, 36: 2090-2097. cited by other . | Fang J, You H, Kong P, Yi Y, Song X, Ding B. Dendritic Silver Nanostructure Growth and Evolution in Replacement Reaction. Crystal Growth and Design 2007, 7: 864. cited by other . | Watlington, K. Emerging Nanotechnologies for Site Remediation and Wastewater Treatment. A report for the US Environmental Protection Agency, Aug. 2005, 1-47. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		115
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6261986 | US6003206 | US6019888 | US20080190865 | US4338185 | US5641020 | US20060275757 | US5000872 | US4360061 | US5546134 | US3640821 | US6099206 | US6352387 | US7056061 | US6881490 | US5948242 | US6127319 | US6474908 | US6315494 | US4368111 | US7037946 | US5622641 | US20060175266 | US6623211 | USR40734 | US4229281 | US5919487 | US4470899 | US6242663 | US20030175081 | US20070119786 | US4405015 | US7226966 | US6881709 | US6689485 | US4474616 | US6913419 | US6664298 | US20070212562 | US4353806 | US20060210815 | US7008964 | US6869535 | US7066254 | US6019548 | US7128841 | US7431775 | US20050077242 | US4068717 | US6158924 | US6777449 | US20020179530 | US20080003687 | US3938590 | US5968249 | US20050199556 | US7708496 | US20080047906 | US7301066 | US20030059926 | US7364386 | US20050191131 | US4968412 | US20080044539 | US6387278 | US5399350 | US20070256985 | US20050009170 | US20070256713 | US6039882 | US4389399 | US6321595 | US7021863 | US5602090 | US7141162 | US20090250404 | US5009773 | US20090074875 | US7186673 | US4101172 | US5849201 | US5340467 | US20060046297 | US20080264876 | US4321147 | US6261463 | US6866764 | US6726406 | US7192092 | US5319966 | US5788738 | US6945734 | US20050197267 | US7175717 | US6719902 | US6511954 | US7334965 | US20020011442 | US6274048 | US7229950 | US20070116524 | US5143598 | US5905036 | WO2009042224 | WO1998025857 | WO2006055054 | WO2009042223 | WO2009042228 | EP0706427 | WO2003068324 | WO2009114145 | WO2007126779 | WO2006008354 | WO1993025714 | WO2009140694 | WO1995001232 | WO2003101541 | WO2005095031 | WO2007047946 | EP1151807 | WO2009014697
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		121
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		VERUTEK TECHNOLOGIES, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		VERUTEK TECHNOLOGIES, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Bloomfield, CT
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Bloomfield, CT
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		HOAG, GEORGE, E. | COLLINS, JOHN, B. | VARMA, RAJENDER, S. | NADAGOUDA, MALLIKARJUNA, N.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		HOAG, GEORGE, E.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Bloomfield, CT
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Bloomfield, CT | Bloomfield, CT | Cincinnati, OH | Cincinnati, OH
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		VENABLE LLP GOLLIN, MICHAEL A. GENIESER, LARS H.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		BARRY, CHESTER
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

