<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US8002984
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12641783
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Green sorption material mixes for water treatment
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Media compositions for use in wastewater treatment, stormwater treatment, CSO treatment and greenroof stormwater management systems as filtration media, plant growth media or pollutant retention media. Media composition includes at least one of a recycled material selected from a group consisting of tire crumb, wood sawdust and paper and a naturally occurring material selected from a group consisting of sand, limestone, sandy clay, expanded clay, organics used for processing geothermal water, organics used for agricultural drainage basins and filtration, and organics for aquaculture drainage and organics used for silviculture and forest drainage, and organics used as growing media.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2009-12-18
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2009-12
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-08-23
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-08
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/32 | C02F1/28
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/32
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/602 | 210/679 | 210/691
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/602
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		World Health Organization (WHO), Guidelines for Drinking-Water Quality, 1st Addendum to the 3rd ed., vol. 1: Recommendations, World Health Organization, Geneva, 2006. cited by other. | Mothersill, C. L., Anderson, B. C., Watt, W.E., Marsalek, J., Biological Filtration of Stormwater: Firld Operations and Hardwood forest Ecosystems. Biogeochemistry, 1996, pp. 541-562, vol. 35. No. 3. cited by other . | Birch, G.F., Fazeli, M.S., and Mathai, C., Efficiency of an infiltration Basin in Removing Contaminants from Urban Stormwater, Environmental Monitoring and Assessment, 2005 , pp. 22-38, vol. 101. cited by other . | Hsieh, C. H., Davis, A. P., Engineered Bioretention for Removal of Nitrate from Storm Water Runoff, Diffuse Pollution Conference Dublin, Ireland, 2003. cited by other . | Savage, A. J., Tyrrel, S. F., Compost Liquir Bioremediation using waste materials as biofiltration media, Biosource Technology, 2005, pp. 557-564, vol. 96. cited by other . | Forbs, M. G., Dickson, K. L., Saleh, F., Doyle, R. D., Hudak, P., and Waller, W.T., Recovery and Fractionation of Phosphate Retained by Lightweight Expanded Shale and Masonry Sand used as Media in Subsurface Flow Treatment Wetlands, Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 2005, pp. 4621-4627, vol. 39, No. 12. cited by other . | Sengupta, S., Ergas, S. J., Autotrophic Biological Denitrification with Elemental Sulfur or Hydrogen for Complete Removal of Nitrate-Nitrogen from a Septic System Wastewater, Report Submitted to the NOAA/UNH cooperative Institute for Costal and Estuarine Enviormental Technology (CICEET). 2008. cited by other . | Gungor, K., Unlu, K., Nitrate Removal Efficiencies of Soil Aquifer Treatment Columns, Turkish J. Eng. Env. Sci., 2005, pp. 159-170, vol. 29. cited by other . | Kim, H., Seagren, E. A., Davis, A. P., Engineered Bioretention for removal of Nitrate from Storm Water Runoff, in WEFTEC 2000 Conference Proceedings on CDROM Research Symposium, Nitrogen Removal, Session 19, Anaheim CA, Oct. 2000. cited by other . | Clark, S., Pitt, R., and Broan, D., Effect of Anaerobiosis on Filter Media Pollutant Retention, Presented at the Engineering Foundation and the American Society of Civil Engineers Conference on Information and Monitoring Needs for Evaluating the mitigation effects of BMP's, Snowmass, Co. 2001. cited by other . | Korkusuz, E.A.,Beklioglu, M., Demirer, G. N., Use of Blast Furnace Granulated Slag as a substrate in Vertical Flow Reed Beds: Field Application, Bioresource Technology, 2007, pp. 2089-2101, vol. 98. cited by other . | Lisi, R. D. Park, J. K., Siter, J. C., Mitigating Nutrient Leaching with a Sub-Surface Drainage Layer of Granulated Tires. Waste Management, 2004, pp. 831-839, vol. 24, No. 8. cited by other . | Debusk, T.A., Langston, M.A. Schwegler, B.R., and Davidson, S., An evaluation of Filter Media for Treating Storm water runoff, Proceeding of the fifth Biennial Storm Water Research conference1997, pp. 82-89. cited by other . | Peterjohn, W. T., Adams, M. B., Gilliam, F. S., Symptoms of Nitrogen Saturation in Two Central Appalachian Hardwood Forest Ecosystems. Biochemistry, 1996, pp. 507-522, vol. 35. cited by other . | Darbi, A., Viaraghavan, T., Butler, R., and Corkal, D., Batch Studies on Nitrate Removal from Portable water, Water South Africa, 2002, pp. 319-322, vol. 28, No. 3. cited by other . | Florida Department of Health, Wekiva Basin Onside Sewage Treatment and Disposal System Study, Department of Osite Sewage Program, available at the internet at: http://www.doh.state.fl.us/enviorment////ostds/wekiva/ wekivastudyrtp.pdf, 2004. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		16
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US8252182
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6652743 | US5733453 | US7288190 | US6214229 | US5014462 | US5707527 | US20060124540 | US5958239 | US6458179 | US6969469 | US5823711 | US5509203 | US5750026 | US20050161407 | US20040112809
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		15
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		UNIVERSITY OF CENTRAL FLORIDA RESEARCH FOUNDATION, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		UNIVERSITY OF CENTRAL FLORIDA RESEARCH FOUNDATION, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Orlando, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Orlando, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		WANIELISTA, MARTIN | CHANG, NI-BIN
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		WANIELISTA, MARTIN
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Winter, Park, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Winter, Park, FL | Winter, Springs, FL
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		STEINBERGER, BRAIN S. WOOD, PHYLLIS K. LAW OFFICES OF BRIAN S.STEINBERGER, P.A.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		PRINCE, FRED
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

