<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US8076117
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US11/083196
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Microbial biofilm removal methods and systems
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		Methods, kits, and systems for removing microbial biofilms from surfaces of objects (such as, e.g., explanted medical devices) are disclosed. The methods, kits, and systems rely on the use of acoustic energy in the presence of microbubbles to enhance biofilm removal while retaining viability of the microorganisms in the biofilm. The microbubbles may be provided in a variety of manners such as, e.g., vortexing a liquid, obtaining a suspension that includes pre-formed protein-stabilized microbubbles, etc.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2005-03-17
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2005
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2005-03
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-12-13
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-12
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C11D3/20 | C12N1/00 | C11D3/02 | B08B6/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C11D3/20
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C11
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C11D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C11D3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		510/109 | 510/108 | 435/243 | 134/1.1 | 134/1 | 510/161
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		510/109
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		510
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Rediske et al., &quot;Pulsed Ultrasound Enhances the Killing of Escherichia coli Biofilms by Aminoglycoside Antibiotics in Vivo,&quot; Antimicrob. Agents Chemother., Mar. 2000;44(3):771-772. cited by other . | Donlan et al., &quot;Biofilms: Survival Mechanisms of Clinically Relevant Microorganisms,&quot; Clin. Microbiol. Rev., Apr. 2002;15(2):167-193. cited by other . | Pitt et al., &quot;Ultrasonic Enhancement of Antibiotic Action on Gram-Negative Bacteria,&quot; Antimicrob. Agents Chemother., Nov. 1994;38(11):2577-2582. cited by other . | Reitz, &quot;The Sound of Sterilization,&quot; Medical Design News, Jul./Aug. 2003:32-34. cited by other . | Maki et al., &quot;A Semiquantitative Culture Method for Identifying Intravenous-Catheter-Related Infection,&quot; N. Engl. J. Med., Jun. 9, 1977;296(23):1305-1309. cited by other . | Trampuz et al., &quot;Removal of 3-day-old Staphylococcus epidermidis Biofilm from Stainless Steel (SS) and Polymethylmethacrylate (PMMA) Coupons,&quot; American Society for Microbiology Conference on Biofilms 2003, Nov. 1-6, 2003, Victoria, B.C., Canada, Abstract #73(A), 1 pg. cited by other . | Ogden et al., &quot;Principles of Shock Wave Therapy,&quot; Clin. Orthop. Rel. Res., Jun. 2001;387:8-17. cited by other . | Tollefson et al., &quot;Surface Biofilm Disruption. Enhanced Recovery of Microorganisms from Vascular Prostheses,&quot; Arch. Surg., Jan. 1987;122:38-43. cited by other . | Yang et al., &quot;Evaluation of Biofilm Image Thresholding Methods,&quot; Wat. Res., 2001;35(5):1149-1158. cited by other. | Greenleaf et al., &quot;Artificial Cavitation Nuclei Significantly Enhance Acoustically Induced Cell Transfection,&quot; Ultrasound Med. Biol., 1998;24(4):587-595. cited by other . | Trampuz et al., &quot;Molecular and Antibiofilm Approaches to Prosthetic Joint Infection,&quot; Clin. Orthop. Rel. Res., Sep. 2003;414:69-88. cited by other . | Tunney et al., &quot;Detection of Prosthetic Hip Infection at Revision Arthroplasty by Immunofluorescence Microscopy and PCR Amplification of the Bacterial 16S rRNA Gene,&quot; J. Clin. Microbiol., Oct. 1999;37(10):3281-3290. cited by other . | Anderl et al., &quot;Role of Nutrient Limitation and Stationary-Phase Existence in Klebsiella pneumoniae Biofilm Resistance to Ampicillin and Ciprofloxacin,&quot; Antimicrob. Agents Chemother., Apr. 2003;47(4):1251-1256. cited by other . | Bergamini et al., &quot;Identification of Staphylococcus epidermidis vascular graft infections: A comparison of culture techniques,&quot; J. Vasc. Surg., May 1989;9(5):665-670. cited by other . | Costerton et al., &quot;Bacterial Biofilms: A Common Cause of Persistent Infections,&quot; Science, May 21, 1999;284:1318-1322. cited by other . | Trampuz et al., &quot;A Prospective Comparative Study of Culture of Joint Fluid, Periprosthetic Tissue and Explant Ultrasonicate for the Diagnosis of Total Knee Arthroplasty Infection,&quot; 40.sup.th Annual Meeting of IDSA, Oct. 24-27, 2002, Chicago, IL, Abstract No. 279, 1 pg. cited by other . | Qian et al., &quot;The Effect of Ultrasonic Frequency upon Enhanced Killing of P. aeruginosa Biofilms,&quot; Ann. Biomed. Eng., 1997;25:69-76. cited by other . | Gorman et al., &quot;Incidence and nature of peritoneal catheter biofilm determined by electron and confocal laser scanning microscopy,&quot; Epidemiol. Infect., 1994; 112:551-559. cited by other . | Kite et al., &quot;Evaluation of a novel endoluminal brush method for in situ diagnosis of catheter related sepsis,&quot; J. Clin. Pathol., 1997;50:278-282. cited by other . | Qian et al., &quot;Effect of low-intensity ultrasound upon biofilm structure from confocal scanning laser microscopy observation,&quot; Biomaterials, 1996;17:1975-1980. cited by other . | Cardo et al., &quot;Central Sterile Supply,&quot; Hospital Epidemiology and Infection Control 2e., 1999:1023-1030. cited by other . | &quot;Overview of Regulations,&quot; [online]. U.S. Food and Drug Administration, Center for Devices and Radiological Health [retrieved on Oct. 5, 2006]. Retrieved from the Internet&lt;fda.gov/cdrh/devadvice/overview.html&gt;; 4 pgs. cited by other . | Pitts et al., &quot;A microtiter-plate screening method for biofilm disinfection and removal,&quot; J. Microbiol. Methods, 2003;54:269-276. cited by other . | Jatzwauk et al., &quot;How to improve instrument disinfection by ultrasound,&quot; J. Hosp. Infect., 2001;48(Suppl. A):S80-S83. cited by other . | Donlan et al., &quot;Protocol for Detection of Biofilms on Needleless Connectors Attached to Central Venous Catheters,&quot; J. Clin. Microbiol., Feb. 2001;39(2):750-753. cited by other . | Yang et al., &quot;Quantifying biofilm structure using image analysis,&quot; J. Microbiol. Methods, 2000;39:109-119. cited by other . | Johansen et al., &quot;Enzymatic Removal and Disinfection of Bacterial Biofilms,&quot; Appl. Environ. Microbiol., Sep. 1997;63(9):3724-3728. cited by other . | Tenney et al., &quot;Adherent Microorganisms on Lumenal Surfaces of Long-term Intravenous Catheters. Importance of Staphylococcus epidermidis in Patients With Cancer,&quot; Arch. Intern. Med., Oct. 1986;146;1949-1954. cited by other . | Nguyen et al., &quot;Detecting Bacterial Colonization of Implanted Orthopaedic Devices by Ultrasonication,&quot; Clin. Orthop. Rel. Res., 2002;403:29-37. cited by other . | Tunney et al., &quot;Improved detection of infection in hip replacements. A currently underestimated problem,&quot; J. Bone Joint Surg., Jul. 1998;80-B(4):568-572. cited by other . | Sherertz et al., &quot;Three-Year Experience with Sonicated Vascular Catheter Cultures in a Clinical Microbiology Laboratory,&quot; J. Clin. Microbiol., Jan. 1990;28(1):76-82. cited by other . | Keane et al., &quot;Characterization of biofilm and encrustation on ureteric stents in vivo,&quot; Br. J. Urol., 1994;73:687-691. cited by other . | Trampuz et al., &quot;Comparison of Scraping, Sonication and Vortexing for Removal of Staphylococcus epidermidis Biofilms from Polycarbonate Coupons,&quot; American Society for Microbiology Conference on Biofilms 2003, Nov. 1-6, 2003, Victoria, B.C., Canada, Abstract, 1 pg. cited by other . | Rediske et al., &quot;Ultrasonic Enhancement of Antibiotic Action on Escherichia coli Biofilms: an in Vivo Model,&quot; Antimicrob. Agents Chemother., May 1999; 43(5):1211-1214. cited by other . | Jyoti et al., &quot;Hybrid cavitation methods for water disinfection: simultaneous use of chemicals with cavitation,&quot; Ultrasonics Sonochemistry, 2003;10:255-264. cited by other . | Wengrovitz et al., &quot;Sonication Provides Maximal Recovery of Staphylococcus epidermidis from Slime-Coated Vascular Prosthetics,&quot; Am. Surg., Mar. 1991; 57(3):161-164. cited by other . | &quot;OPTISON Product Description. The next generation of contrast technology&quot; datasheet [online]. General Electric Company, 1997-2006, [retrieved on Aug. 28, 2006]. Retrieved from the Internet&lt;URL:http://www.amershamhealth-us.com/optison/monograph/om03-0- 1.html&gt;; 2 pgs. cited by other . | Lindsay, et al., 1997, Food Microbiology, 14, 383-390. cited by examiner . | Johnson et al., &quot;Treatment of bacterial biofilms on polymeric biomaterials using antibiotics and ultrasound,&quot; J. Biomater. Sci., Polym. Edn., 1998;9(11):1177-1185. cited by other . | Padberg et al., &quot;Optimal Method for Culturing Vascular Prosthetic Grafts,&quot; J. Surg. Res., 1992;53:384-390. cited by other . | &quot;BioSurface Technologies CDC Biofilm Reactor with Stir Plate (120 VAC),&quot; datasheet [online]. Cytergy, LLC, 2003, [retrieved on Dec. 28, 2005]. Retrieved from the Internet:&lt;URL:http//www.cytergy.com/cgi-bin/cytergy/cdc.sub.--biofim.s- ub.--reactor.html; 2 pgs. cited by other . | Trampuz et al., &quot;A Prospective Comparative Study of Culture of Synovial Fluid, Periprosthetic Tissue and Explant Sonicate for the Diagnosis of Prosthetic Joint Infection,&quot; Nov. 26, 2003, 2 pgs. cited by other . | Dobbins et al., &quot;Bacterial Colonization of Orthopedic Fixation Devices in the Absence of Clinical Infection,&quot; J. Infect. Dis., Jul. 1988;158(1):203-205. cited by other . | Donlan, &quot;Biofilms and Device-Associated Infections,&quot; Emerg. Infect. Dis., Mar.-Apr. 2001;7(2):277-281. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		44
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US20020091424 | US5925257 | US6447718 | US20030104359 | US20030065292 | US6524827 | US5312813 | US5462644 | US5552133 | US6348186 | US4193818 | US4572203 | US6258249 | US6475434 | US6004438 | US6027572 | US5855865 | US5877243 | WO2002031184
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		19
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		MAYO FOUNDATION FOR MEDICAL EDUCATION &amp; RESEARCH
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		MAYO FOUNDATION FOR MEDICAL EDUCATION &amp; RESEARCH
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Rochester, MN
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Rochester, MN
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		TRAMPUZ, ANDREJ | PATEL, ROBIN | GREENLEAF, JAMES, F. | HANSSEN, ARLEN, D.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		TRAMPUZ, ANDREJ
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Basel, CH
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Basel, CH | Rochester, MN | Rochester, MN | Rochester, MN
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		MUETING, RAASCH &amp; GEBHARDT, P.A.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		DAVIS, RUTH A
	</str>
	<str name="Assistant Examiner">
		MACAULEY, SHERIDAN
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

