<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US8012077
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12126028
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Blood separating device
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A device for separating components of a composition according to density. The device includes a rotatable chamber and a plurality of buoys. The rotatable chamber has an axis of rotation. The plurality of buoys are positioned within the rotatable chamber and about the axis of rotation. The buoys are radially movable between an expanded position in which the buoys are at a first location relative to the axis of rotation and a contracted position in which the buoys are at a second location relative to the axis of rotation. The first location is further from the axis of rotation than the second location is. The buoys are movable in response to force generated during rotation of the rotatable chamber.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2008-05-23
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2008-05
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-09-06
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-09
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01D21/26
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01D21/26
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01D21
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		494/47 | 494/37 | 494/3 | 494/63 | 494/43 | 210/740
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		494/47
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		494
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		International Search Report and Written Opinion mailed Jul. 3, 2009 for PCT/US2009/035564 claiming benefit of U.S. Appl. No. 61/078,178, filed Jul. 3, 2008. cited by other . | Laryngoscope vol. 99, pp. 974-976, Sep. 1989, Kyosti Laitakari, M.D., et al., &quot;Autologous and Homologous Fibrinogen Sealants: Adhesive Strength&quot;. cited by other . | Edlich, Richard F., George T. Rodeheaver, and John G. Thacker. &quot;Surgical Devices in Wound Healing Management.&quot; In Wound Healing: Biochemical &amp; Clinical Aspects,ed. I. Kelman Cohen, Robert F. Diegelmann, and William J. Lindblad. 581-600. 1st ed., Vol. Philadelphia: W.B. Saunders Company, 1992). cited by other . | Sanal, M. &quot;Does fibrin glue cause foreign body reactions? [letter].&quot; Eur J Pediatr Surg 3 (3 1993): 190 (1 page). cited by other . | &quot;Frequently Asked Questions, 1. Kits, 2. Engzymes,&quot; (2003) 3 pages Worthington Biochemical Corp. cited by other . | Hennis, H. L., W. C. Stewart, and E. K. Jeter. &quot;Infectious disease risks of fibrin glue [letter].&quot; Ophthalmic Surg 23 (9 1992): 640. cited by other . | DelRossi, A. J., A. C. Cernaianu, R. A.Vertrees, C. J. Wacker, S. J. Fuller, J. Cilley Jr., and W. A. Baldino. &quot;Platelet-rich plasma reduces postoperative blood loss after cardiopulmonary bypass.&quot; J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg 100 (2 1990): 281-6. cited by other . | &quot;Sefar Solutions for the Healthcare Industry,&quot; brochure (2003) 9 pages Sefar Medifab.RTM.. cited by other . | Otolaryngologic Clinics of North America, vol. 27, No. 1, pp. 203-209, Feb. 1994, Dean M. Toriumi, M.D., et al., &quot;Surgical Tissue Adhesives in Otolaryngology-Head and Neck Surgery&quot;. cited by other . | Jackson, C. M. and Y. Nemerson. &quot;Blood coagulation.&quot; Annu Rev Biochem 49 (811 1980): 765-811. cited by other . | Journal of Biomaterials Applications, vol. 7, pp. 309-353, Apr. 1993, David H. Sierra, &quot;Fibrin Sealant Adhesive Systems: A review of their Chemistry, Material Properties and Clinical Appllications&quot;. cited by other . | Gimble, Jeffrey M., &quot;Adipose-Derived Stem Cells for Regenerative Medicine,&quot; Circulation Research (2007) pp. 1249-1260, American Heart Association, Inc. cited by other . | &quot;Cell Isolation Theory, Tissue Types,&quot; (2004) (5 pages) Worthington Biochemical Corp. cited by other . | Hattori, et al., &quot;Osteogenic Potential of Human Adipose Tissue-Derived Stromal Cells as an Alternative Stem Cell Source,&quot; Cells Tissues Organs (2004) 178:2-12 Karger. cited by other . | International Preliminary Report on Patentability mailed Feb. 12, 2009, for PCT/US2007/017055 filed Jul. 31, 2007, which claims benefit of U.S. Appl. No. 60/834,550, filed Jul. 31, 2006, based on U.S. Appl. No. 60/723,312, filed Oct. 4, 2005; U.S. Appl. No. 60/654,718, filed Feb. 17, 2005; and U.S. Appl. No. 60/651,050, filed Feb. 7, 2005. cited by other . | Ann Thorac Surg, vol. 56, pp. 387-389, 1993, Robert L. Quigley, M.D., et al., &quot;Intraoperative Procurement of Autologous Fibrin Glue&quot;. cited by other . | DiMuzio, Paul et al., &quot;Development of a Tissue-Engineered Bypass Graft Seeded with Stem Cells,&quot; Vasucular, vol. 14, No. 6, (2006) pp. 338-342, BC Decker, Inc. cited by other . | International Search Report and Written Opinion mailed Aug. 12, 2008 for PCT/US07/17055. cited by other . | Rigotti, M.D., et al, &quot;Clinical Treatment of Radiotherapy Tissue Damage by Lipoaspirate Transplant: A Healing Process Mediated by Adipose-Derived Adult Stem Cells,&quot; Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, Breast, PRS Journal vol. 119, No. 5, Stem Cell Therapy for Angiogenesis, (Pub. 2005) pp. 1409-1422. cited by other . | Collier, B.S. et al., &quot;The pH Dependence of Quantitative Ristocetin-induced Platelet Aggregation: Theoretical and Practical Implications--A New Device for Maintenance of Platelet-Rich Plasma pH&quot;, Hematology Service, Clinical Pathology Department, Clinical Center, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Md. 20014, Blood, vol. 47, No. 5 (May), 1976. cited by other . | Sanal, M., H. Dogruyol, A. Gurpinar, and O. Yerci. &quot;Does fibrin glue cause foreign body reactions?&quot; Eu r J Pediatr Surg 2 (5 1992): 285-6. cited by other . | International Preliminary Examination Report and Written Opinion issued Aug. 31, 2010 for PCT/US2009/035564 claiming benefit of U.S. Appl. No. 61/078,178, filed Jul. 3, 2008 of which U.S. Appl. No. 12/395,085, filed Feb. 27, 2009 claims benefit. cited by other . | Weis-Fogh, U. S. &quot;Fibrinogen prepared from small blood samples for autologous use in a tissue adhesive system.&quot; Eur Surg Res 20 (5-6 1988): 381-9. cited by other . | Laryngoscope, vol. 96, pp. 1062-1064, Oct. 1986, Karl H. Siedentop, M.D., et al., &quot;Extended Experimental and Preliminary Surgical Findings with Autologous Fibrin Tissue Adhesive Made from Patient's Own Blood&quot;. cited by other . | The American Journal of Surgery, vol. 168, pp. 120-122, Aug. 1994, Roy L. Tawes, Jr., M.D., et al., &quot;Autologous Fibrin Glue: The Last Step in Operative Hemostatis&quot;. cited by other . | Wiseman, David M., David T. Rovee, and Oscar M. Alverez. &quot;Wound Dressings: Design and Use.&quot; In Wound Healing: Biochemical &amp; Clinical Aspects,ed. I. Kelman Cohen, Robert F. Diegelmann, and William J. Lindblad. 562-580. 1st ed., Vol. Philadelphia: W. B. Saunders Company, 1992). cited by other . | Schaffler, Andreas, et al., &quot;Concise Review: Adipose Tissue-Derived Stromal Cells--Basic and Clinical Implications for Novel Cell-Based Therapies,&quot; Tissue-Specific Stem Cells, Stem Cells.RTM. (2007) pp. 818-827 AlphaMed Press. cited by other . | Biopolymers, vol. 27, pp. 763-774, 1988, Gerald Marx, &quot;Mechanism of Fibrin Coagulation Based on Selective, Cation-Driven, Protofibral Association&quot;. cited by other . | &quot;Cytori Celution Cell Concentrate Device,&quot; Exhibit 14, 510(k) Summary, FDA approval K060482 (Sep. 28, 2006). cited by other . | GPS.RTM. System, &quot;GPS.RTM. Platelet Concentrate System,&quot; Cell Factor Technologies, Inc., Biomet Orthopaedics, Inc., (2004) (9 pages). cited by other . | Epstein, G. H., R. A. Weisman, S. Zwillenberg, and A. D. Schreiber. &quot;A new autologous fibrinogen-based adhesive for otologic surgery.&quot; Ann Otol Rhinol Laryngol 95 (1 Pt 1 1986): 40-5. cited by other . | Office Action mailed Sep. 14, 2010 for Japanese Application No. 2007-554193 filed Aug. 23, 2007 has been provided including a partial translation thereof. Japanese Application No. 2007-554193 claims benefit of PCT/US2006/003599, filed Jan. 30, 2006; claiming priority from U.S. Appl. Nos. 60/651,050, filed Feb. 7, 2005; 60/654,718, filed Feb. 17, 2005; and 60/723,312, filed Oct. 04, 2005 of which U.S. Appl. No. 11/831,605 filed Jul. 31, 2007, and U.S. Appl. No. 12/772,497 filed May 3, 2010 claim benefit. cited by other . | Zhang, Duan-zhen, et al., &quot;Transplantation of autologous adipose-derived stem cells ameliorates cardiac function in rabbits with myocardial infarction,&quot; Chinese Medical Journal, vol. 120, No. 4 (2007) pp. 300-307 General Hospital of Shenyang Military Region, Shenyang, China. cited by other . | Drug Intelligence and Clinical Pharmacy, vol. 22, pp. 946-952, Dec. 1988, Dennis F. Thompson, et al., &quot;Fibrin Glue: A Review of Its Preparation, Efficacy, and Adverse Effects as a Topical Hemostat&quot;. cited by other . | &quot;Trypsinization of Adherent Cells,&quot; (undated) 2 pages. cited by other . | Berruyer, M., J. Amiral, P. Ffrench, J. Belleville, O. Bastien, J. Clerc, A. Kassir, S. Estanove, and M. Dechavanne. &quot;Immunization by bovine thrombin used with fibrin glue during cardiovascular operations. Development of thrombin and factor V inhibitors,&quot; J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg 105 (5 1993): 892-7. cited by other . | Ann Thorac Surg, vol. 53, pp. 530-531, 1992, Mehmet C. Oz, M.D., et al., &quot;Autologous Fibrin Glue From Intraoperatively Collected Platelet-Rich Plasma&quot;. cited by other . | Planat-Benard, V., et al., &quot;Spontaneous Cardiomyocyte Differentiation From Adipose Tissue Stroma Cells,&quot; Adipose-Derived Cell Cardiomyocyte (2004) pp. 223-229 American Heart Association, Inc. cited by other . | Rangappa, Sunil, M.D., &quot;Transformation of Adult Mesenchymal Stem Cells Isolated From the Fatty Tissue Into Cardiomyocytes,&quot; Adult Stem Cells Transformed into Cardiomyoctyes, (2003) pp. 775-779 Ann Thorac Surg. cited by other . | Office Action mailed Apr. 6, 2010 for Japanese Application No. 2007-554193 filed Aug. 23, 2007 has been provided including a partial translation thereof, which cites JP11-502502 and JP2001017540. Japanese Application No. 2007-554193 claims benefit of PCT/US2006/003599, filed Jan. 30, 2006; claiming priority from U.S. Appl. Nos. 60/651,050, filed Feb. 7, 2005; 60/654,718, filed Feb. 17, 2005; and 60/723,312, filed Oct. 4, 2005 of which U.S. Appl. No. 11/831,605 filed Jul. 31, 2007 and U.S. Appl. No. 12/772,497 filed May 3, 2010 claim benefit. cited by other . | Lerner, R. and N. S. Binur. &quot;Current status of surgical adhesives.&quot; J Surg Res 48 (2 1990): 165-81. cited by other . | GPS.RTM. II System, Gravitational Platelet Separation System, &quot;User Manual,&quot; Cell Factor Technologies, Inc., Biomet Europe [date unknown] 13 pages, http://www.cellfactortech.com/global.sub.--products.cfm, printed Sep. 16, 2005. cited by other . | Kjaergard, H. K., Fogh Us Weis, and J. J. Thiis. &quot;Preparation of autologous fibrin glue from pericardial blood.&quot; Ann Thorac Sur 55 (2 1993): 543-4. cited by other . | Nakagami, Hironori, et al., &quot;Novel Autologous Cell Tehrapy in Ischemic Limb Disease Through Growth Factor Secretion by Cultured Adipose Tissue-Derived Stromal Cells,&quot; Angiogenesis by Adipose Tissue-Derived Cells, (2005) pp. 2542-2547, American Heart Association, Inc. cited by other . | Parker, Anna M., et al., Adipose-derived stem cells for the regeneration of damaged tissues, Expert Opinion, Cell- &amp; Tissue-based Therapy, Expert Opin. Biol. Ther. (2006) pp. 567-578 Informa UK Ltd. cited by other . | Office Action mailed Sep. 14, 2010 for Japanese Application No. 2007554191 filed Aug. 7, 2007 has been provided including a partial translation thereof. Japanese Application No. 2007554191 claims benefit of PCT/US2006/003597, filed Jan. 30, 2006; claiming priority from U.S. Appl. Nos. 60/651,050, filed Feb. 7, 2005; 60/654,718, filed Feb. 17, 2005; and 60/723,312, filed Oct. 4, 2005 of which U.S. Appl. No. 11/831,605 filed Jul. 31, 2007 and U.S. Appl. No. 12/772,497 filed May 3, 2010 claim benefit. cited by other . | International Search Report and Written Opinion for PCT/US2006/003597 mailed Feb. 6, 2006. cited by other . | GPS.RTM. System, &quot;Shoulder Recovery with the GPS.RTM. Platelet Concentrate System, Rotator Cuff Surgical Techniques,&quot; brochure, Cell Factor Technologies, Inc., Biomet Orthopaedics, Inc., (2004) 6 pages. cited by other . | Frasier, John K., et al., &quot;Plasticity of human adipose stem cells toward endothelial cells and cardiomyocytes,&quot; Nature Clinical Practice Cardiovascular Medicine, vol. 3, Supplement 1 (Mar. 2006) pp. S33-S37. cited by other . | Kjaergard, H. K,, U. S. Weis-Fogh, H. Sorensen, J. Thiis, and I. Rygg. &quot;A simple method of preparation o.English Pound. autologous fibrin glue by means of ethanol.&quot; Surg Gynecol Obstet 175 (1 1992): 72-3. cited by other . | Harris, E.L.V. Concentration of the Extract. In. Protein Purification Methods: A Practical Approach Harris, E.L.V.; Angal, S.; Editors. (1989) Publisher: (IRL Press, Oxford, UK), pp. 67-69. cited by other . | DeUgarte, M.D., Daniel A., et al., &quot;Future of Fat as Raw Material for Tissue Regneration,&quot; (2007) pp. 215-219, Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, Inc. cited by other . | GPS.RTM. II System, Gravitational Platelet Separation System, &quot;Accelerating the Body's Natural Healing Process,&quot; Cell Factor Technologies, Inc., Biomet Europe (2005) 16 pages, http://www.cellfactortech.com/global.sub.--products.cfm, printed Sep. 16, 2005. cited by other . | First clinical results: Kuderma, H. and Helene Matras. &quot;Die klinische Anwendung der Klebung van Nervenanastomosen mit Gerinnungssubstanzen bei der Rekonstruction verletzter peripherer Nerven.&quot; Wein Klin Wochenschr 87 (15 1975): 495-501. cited by other . | Laryngoscope, vol. 95, pp. 1074-1076, Sep. 1985, Karl H. Siedentop, M.D., et al., &quot;Autologous Fibrin Tissue Adhesive&quot;. cited by other . | Gibble, J. W. and P. M. Ness. &quot;Fibrin glue: the perfect operative sealant?&quot; Transfusion 30 (8 1990): 741-7. cited by other . | Gomillion, Cheryl T., et al., &quot;Stem cells and adipose tissue engineering,&quot; Biomaterials 27, Science Direct (2006) pp. 6052-6063, Elsevier. cited by other . | GPS.RTM. III System, GPS.RTM. III Platelet Separation System, Leadership through Technology, brochure, Jul. 2007 (8 sheets) . cited by other . | Moretz, W., Jr., J Shea Jr., J. R. Emmett, and J Shea. &quot;A simple autologous fibrinogen glue for otologic surgery.&quot; Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 95 (1 1986): 122-4. cited by other . | Guilak, Frank, et al., &quot;Adipose-derived adult stem cells for cartilage tissue engineering,&quot; Biorheology 41 (2004) pp. 389-399, IOS Press. cited by other . | Sigma-Aldrich.RTM. Alkaline Phosphatase (Procedure No. 85), drug fact sheet, (2003) pp. 1-2, Sigma-Aldrich, Inc. cited by other . | Anesthesiology, vol. 81, No. 4, pp. 1074-1077, Oct. 1994, Hiromasa Mitsuhata, M.D., et al., &quot;An Anaphylactic Reaction to Topical Fibrin Glue&quot;. cited by other . | Casali, B., F. Rodeghiero, A. Tosetto, B. Palmieri, R. Immovilli, C. Ghedini, and P. Rivasi. &quot;Fibrin glue from single-donation autologous plasmapheresis.&quot; Transfusion 32 (Jul. 1992): 641-3. cited by other . | Journal of Oral Maxillofacial Surgery, vol. 43, pp. 605-611, 1985, Helene Matras, M.D., &quot;Fibrin Seal: The State of the Art&quot;. cited by other . | Vox Sanquinis, vol. 68: 82-89, 02/95, Boomgaard Et. al, Pooled Platelet Concentration Prepred by the . . . . cited by other . | &quot;Cell Isolation Techniques, Methods and Materials, Working with Enzymes,&quot; (2004) (9 pages) Worthington Biochemical Corp. cited by other . | Rubin, M.D., et al, &quot;Clinical Treatment of Radiotherapy Tissue Damage by Lipoaspirate Transplant: A Healing Process Mediated by Adipose-Derived Adult Stem Cells,&quot; Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, Discussion vol. 119, No. 5, Stem Cell Therapy for Angiogenesis, (2007) pp. 1423-1424. cited by other . | Takahashi, Kazutoshi et al., &quot;Induction of Pluripotent Stem Cells from Adult Human Fibroblasts by Defined Factors,&quot; Cell, (2007) pp. 1-12, Elsevier Inc. cited by other . | GPS.RTM. System, &quot;Shoulder Recovery with the GPS.RTM. Platelet Concentrate System, Rotator Cuff Surgical Techniques,&quot; Cell Factor Technologies, Inc., Biomet Orthopaedics, Inc., (2004) 3 pages, http://www.cellfactortech.com/global.sub.--products.cfm, printed Sep. 16, 2005. cited by other . | Yoon, Eulsik, M.D., Ph.D., et al., &quot;In Vivo Osteogenic Potential of Human Adipose-Derived Stem Cells/Poly Lactide-Co-Glycolic Acid Constructs for Bone Regneration in a Rat Critical-Sized Calvarial Defect Model,&quot; Tissue Engineering, vol. 13, No. 3 (2007) pp. 619-627 Mary Ann Liebert, Inc. cited by other . | Marrowstim.TM. Concentration System, (2008) 20 pages Biomet Biologics, Inc. cited by other . | International Search Report and Written Opinion for PCT/US2006/003599 mailed Aug. 21, 2006. cited by other . | Zuk, Patricia A., Ph.D., &quot;Multilineage Cells from Human Adipose Tissue: Implications for Cell-Based Therapies,&quot; Tissue Engineering, vol. 7, No. 2, (2001) pp. 211-228 Mary Ann Liebert, Inc. cited by other. | Lendeckel, Stefan, et al., &quot;Autologous stem cells (adipose) and fibrin glue used to treat widespread traumatic calvarial defects: case report,&quot; Journal of Cranio-Maxillofacial Surgery (2004) European Association for Cranio-Maxillofacial Surgery. cited by other . | Hartman, A. R., D. K. Galanakis, M. P. Honig, F. C. Seifert, and C. E. Anagnostopoulos. &quot;Autologous whole plasma fibrin gel. Intraoperative procurement.&quot; Arch Surg 127 (3 1992): 357-9. cited by other . | The American Surgeon, vol. 55, pp. 166-168, Mar. 1989, William D. Spotnitz, M.D., et al., &quot;Successful Use of Fibrin Glue During 2 Years of Surgery at a University Medical Center&quot;. cited by other . | Berguer, R., R. L. Staerkel, E. E. Moore, F. A. Moore, W. B. Galloway, and M. B. Mockus. &quot;Warning: fatal reaction to the use of fibrin glue in deep hepatic wounds. Case reports.&quot; J Trauma 31 (3 1991): 408-11. cited by other . | Plasmax.TM. Plasma Concentrate, brochure (2006) 5 pages Biomet Biologics, Inc. cited by other . | Matras, Helene, H. P. Dinges, H. Lassmann, and B. Mamoli. &quot;Zur nahtlosen interfaszikularen Nerventransplantation im Tierexperinnent.&quot; Wein Med Woschtr 122 (37 1972): 517-523. cited by other . | Office Action mailed Apr. 6, 2010 for Japanese Application No. 2007554191 filed Aug. 7, 2007 has been provided including a partial translation thereof, which also cites JP2001017540. Japanese Application No. 2007554191 claims benefit of PCT/US2006/003597, filed Jan. 30, 2006; claiming priority from U.S. Appl. Nos. 60/651,050, filed Feb. 7, 2005; 60/654,718, filed Feb. 17, 2005; and 60/723,312, filed Oct. 4, 2005 of which U.S. Appl. No. 11/831,605 filed Jul. 31, 2007 and U.S. Appl. No. 12/772,497 filed May 3, 2010 claim benefit. cited by other . | Vortech.TM. Concentration System, &quot;Do you want a sticky gel to improve the handling of your bone graft?, Platelet Rich Plasma Concentrate, High Volume in 5 Minutes,&quot; Biomet Biologics, Inc., Aug. 2005. cited by other . | Nathan, Suresh et al., &quot;Cell-Based Therapy in the Repair of Osteochondral Defects: A Novel Use for Adipose Tissue,&quot; Tissue Engineering, vol. 9, No. 4 (2003) pp. 733-744 Mary Ann Liebert, Inc. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		82
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6054122 | US3894952 | US7011644 | US4957638 | US4933291 | US5924972 | US6758978 | US20060083720 | US4537767 | US4427651 | US4427650 | US4943273 | US5918622 | US6296602 | US20100206798 | US3508653 | US4414976 | US4950220 | US4617009 | US20070075016 | US5443481 | US6563953 | US5795571 | US4322298 | US3785549 | US5147290 | US4639316 | US5071570 | US4627879 | US4631055 | US4055501 | US5788662 | US5393674 | US20100226909 | US4650678 | US20050076396 | US5219328 | US5298171 | US4362567 | US3935113 | US3879295 | US4269718 | US3909419 | US5165938 | US5420250 | US5112490 | US3779383 | US6629919 | US3850369 | US5131907 | US20060175242 | US4417981 | US5454958 | US6051146 | US5889584 | US6676629 | US6090793 | US20030191429 | US5156613 | US5269927 | US5185001 | US4929242 | US20060175244 | US3814248 | US5577513 | US4879031 | US6117425 | US5736033 | US4294707 | US5190057 | US5505685 | US5236604 | US4722790 | US5030215 | US5053127 | US4818291 | US6011490 | US4446021 | US5171456 | US4632761 | US5601727 | US5234608 | US5456693 | US6368298 | US5290552 | US5321126 | US5643193 | US5643192 | US20060243676 | US5370802 | US4818386 | US5271852 | US4675117 | US6905612 | US5281342 | US5152905 | US5456885 | US4853137 | US5585007 | US5330974 | US5344752 | US4985153 | US6342157 | US4229298 | US5853600 | US6214338 | US20070036768 | US6063297 | US3420374 | US5137832 | US5279825 | US4828710 | US4874368 | US5795489 | US4680025 | US4001122 | US6096309 | US4046699 | US4902281 | US5206023 | US4846780 | US6022306 | US5173295 | US5104375 | US5674173 | US5100564 | US4464167 | US6516953 | US4928603 | US5019243 | US5190759 | US3453364 | US4159896 | US5141645 | US5395923 | US7077273 | US3897343 | US5510102 | US4225580 | US5000970 | US4303193 | US6025201 | US6777231 | US3982691 | US6322785 | US4298598 | US5860937 | US5980757 | US5322620 | US5632905 | US6102843 | US4442655 | US6153113 | US4900453 | US20020032112 | US20050247715 | US6464624 | US4738655 | US5217426 | US20050153441 | US20050153442 | US20050084961 | US5318524 | US4846974 | US5494578 | US6196987 | US5002571 | US5217627 | US6200287 | US20040251217 | US5934803 | US6053856 | US6334842 | US6197325 | US4377572 | US4839058 | US6071423 | US5290918 | US20040171146 | US5607579 | US5641622 | US4877520 | US6979307 | US20050109716 | US5030341 | US4059108 | US5318782 | US4300717 | US5405607 | US5417650 | US3593915 | US20040182795 | US5260420 | US5494592 | US4416654 | US3469369 | US5376263 | US20050260174 | US3972812 | US4314823 | US20060196885 | US20050260175 | US4453939 | US3441143 | US3647070 | US4983157 | US4152270 | US4983158 | US20040182788 | US6280400 | US5226877 | US20080283474 | USR32089 | US5112484 | US4735726 | US3929646 | US5484383 | US5589462 | US2553004 | US5411885 | US7179391 | US20020076400 | US5304372 | US4946601 | US6245900 | US4187979 | US5560830 | US5733545 | US5316674 | US5188583 | US20030082152 | US4204537 | US3141846 | US6544162 | US4424132 | US4332351 | US6764531 | US4672969 | US5204537 | US4844818 | US4655211 | US4364832 | US5403272 | US4832851 | US5614106 | US4871462 | US6277961 | US4834890 | US20080011684 | US3931018 | US3409165 | US5258126 | US20050282275 | US6472162 | US4714457 | US4770779 | US4735616 | US4724317 | US4755300 | US4755301 | US4610656 | US4077396 | US5387187 | US5533518 | US6316247 | US3941699 | US3931010 | US20050196874 | US5045048 | US4776964 | EP1467746 | EP0295771 | AU696278 | EP0109374 | CA1321138 | WO20042004009207 | EP1670315 | JP1985250014 | WO19939308904 | WO19848400905 | MX246078 | JP1992500170 | JP1997509432 | WO19969616714 | CN1074709 | WO19898901827 | WO200303090839 | DE56103 | JP1990036872 | WO200303015800 | EP0417818 | EP1005910 | JP2129224 | EP0253198 | WO20042004037427 | WO20020224107 | CA2182862 | WO19888802259 | WO20010183068 | JP1985053845 | JP2000117150 | JP1990071747 | WO20072007142908 | EP0534178 | JP1988182055 | DE4202667 | EP0592242 | WO19949407548 | WO19969617871 | GB854715 | WO19989848938 | WO200303092894 | WO19909010031 | EP0142339 | WO20042004104553 | JP2001017540 | WO19939305067 | WO20010103756 | JP1997187504 | JP1999502502 | EP0090997 | EP0272915 | WO20062006081699 | WO200303053362 | BR9103724 | DE1443359 | WO200303024215 | EP0102773 | EP1716901 | EP0285891 | JP2005523128 | WO20052005034843 | JP1994250014 | WO19929222312 | JP1989454256 | EP1427279
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		336
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		BIOMET BIOLOGICS, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		BIOMET BIOLOGICS, LLC
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Warsaw, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Warsaw, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		HOEPPNER, JACY, C.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		HOEPPNER, JACY, C.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Warsaw, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Warsaw, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		HARNESS, DICKEY
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		GRIFFIN, WALTER D
	</str>
	<str name="Assistant Examiner">
		CLEVELAND, TIMOTHY
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

