<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US8021551
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12383755
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Eco-treatment system
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A system and method of treating wastewater from an animal confinement operation. The system including at least a first lagoon receiving water from the confinement operation. The system further including a free surface water wetland, a subsurface flow wetland and a vertical flow recirculating media filter. The first artificial wetland including a pipe such that water from the lagoon flows into the first artificial wetland through an inlet of the pipe and is contained within the wetland. The first wetland further including a plurality of wetland plants. A second subsurface flow wetland and a vertical flow recirculating media filter on top of the subsurface flow wetland and wetland plants contained within a first pea gravel bed on top of a coarse gravel bed of the subsurface flow media filter such that water from the lagoon is received by the first wetland. A recirculation pump receiving water from the horizontal coarse gravel bed and the pump recirculating water to the wetland plants of the vertical flow recirculation media filter such that ammonia in the water is converted to nitrate and water as it falls vertically through roots of the wetland plants and the nitrate is converted to nitrogen and water as the water flows horizontally through the subsurface flow wetland.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2009-03-27
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2009
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2009-03
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-09-20
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-09
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F3/32
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F3/32
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F3
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/170.08 | 210/602 | 210/617 | 210/906
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/170.08
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Chen et al., Application of a constructed wetland for industrial wastewater treatment: A pilot-scale study, Chemosphere, vol. 64, pp. 497-502 (2006). cited by examiner . | Nordin, Leachate Treatment Using Constructed Wetland with Magnetic Field, Universiti Teknologi Malaysia, http://eprints.utm.my/3595/1/NoorldaAmalinaAhamadNordinMAD2006TTT.pdf, pp. 1-21 (2006). cited by examiner.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US8187461
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US6652743 | US5690827 | US6830688 | US20030024874 | US7361268 | US5156741
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		6
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		HARRISON, MARK
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		HARRISON, MARK
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Indianapolis, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Indianapolis, IN
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		PRICE, GARY K.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		PRINCE, FRED
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

