<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		US8048015
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US12054162
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		B2
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Methods and apparatus for creating particle derivatives of HDL with reduced lipid content
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		The present invention is directed to systems, apparatus and methods for creating derivatives of at least one form of HDL without substantially affecting LDL. These derivatives of HDL are particles with reduced lipid content, particularly reduced cholesterol content. These particles have the capacity to bind cholesterol and are administered to a patient to enhance cellular cholesterol efflux and reduce cholesterol levels in cells, tissues, organs, and blood vessels. The present method is useful for treating atherogenic vascular disease and may be combined with other therapies such as statins, inhibitors of cholesterol absorption, niacin, anti-inflammatories, exercise and dietary restriction.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2008-03-24
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2008-03
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-11-01
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-11
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01D11/00 | A61M1/38 | A61K9/14 | A61K38/17
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01D11/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01D11
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		530/359 | 210/749 | 424/491 | 604/5.03
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		530/359
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		530
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Segrest et al., A Detailed Molecular Belt Model for Apolipoprotein A-I in Discoidal High Density Lipoprotein, The Journal of Biological Chemistry, v. 274(45), 31755-31758, (Nov. 5, 1999). cited by other . | Bloom et al., Quantitation of lipid profiles from isolated serum lipoproteins using small volumes of human serum, Clin. Biochem., v. 14, 119-125 (abstract only) (Jun. 1981). cited by other . | Zhang et al., Characterization of Phospholipids in pre-.alpha. HDL: Selective Phospholipid Efflux with Apolipoprotein A-I, Journal of Lipid Research, v. 39, 1601-1607 (1998). cited by other. | Ladu et al., Association of Human, Rat, and Rabbit Apolipoprotein E with Beta-Amyloid, Journal of Neuroscience Research, v. 49(1), 9-18, (1997). cited by other . | Ryan et al., An Improved Extraction Procedure for the Determination of Triglycerides and Cholesterol in Plasma or Serum, Clinical Chemistry,. v. 13, 769-772 (1967). cited by other . | Koudinov et al., Cholesterol s Role in Synapse Formation, Science, v. 294, 2213 (Nov. 9, 2001). cited by other . | Badimon et al., Regression of Atherosclerotic Lesions by High Density Lipoprotein Plasma Fraction in the Cholesterol-Fed Rabbit, J. Clinical Investigation, v. 85, 1234-1241 (1990). cited by other . | Jackson et al., Isolation and Characterization of the Major Apolipoprotein from Chicken High Density Lipoproteins, Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, v. 420, 342-349 (1976). cited by other . | Refolo et al., Cholesterol Metabolism: A Potential Target for Alzheimer s Disease Therapy, Soc. Neuroscience Abstracts, v. 27(2), 1518 (abstract only) (2001). cited by other . | Burns et al., Use of In Vivo Models to Study the Role of Cholesterol in the Etiology of Alzheimer's Disease, Neurochem. Res., v. 28, 979-86 (abstract only) (Jul. 2003). cited by other . | Agnese et al., Evaluation of Four Reagents for Delipidation of Serum, Clinical Biochemistry, v. 16, 98-100 (1983). cited by other . | Yokoyama et al., Selective Removal of Low Density Lipoprotein by Plasmapheresis in Familial Hypercholesterolemia, Arteriosclerosis, v. 5, 613-622 (1985). cited by other . | Gauthier et al., Alzheimer s Disease: Current Kowledge, Management and Research, Can. Med.Assoc. J., v. 157(8), 1047-1052 (1997). cited by other . | Cham, Nature of the Interaction Between Low-Density Lipoproteins and Polyanions and Metal as Exemplified by Heparin and Ca.sup.2+, Clinical Chemistry,. v. 22, 1812-1816 (1976). cited by other . | Dwivedy, 18th Australian Atherosclerosis Society Conference, Gold Coast, Australia, Increase of Reverse Cholesterol Transport by Cholesterol Apheresis Regression of Atherosclerosis, (1992). cited by other . | Cham et al., In Vitro Partial Relipidation of Apolipoproteins in Plasma, J. Biol. Chem., v. 251, 6367-6371. (abstract only) (1976). cited by other . | Barres et al., Cholesterol--Making or Breaking the Synapse, Science, v. 294, 1296-1297 (1996). cited by other . | Cham et al., Heterogeneity of Lipoprotein B, Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, v. 103, 196-206 (1981). cited by other . | Sviridov et al., Dynamics of Reverse Cholesterol Transport: Protection against Atherosclerosis, Atherosclerosis, v. 161(2), 245-254 (Apr. 2002). cited by other . | Lipid Sciences, http://wwwlipidsciencescom/technologyhtml, Lipid Technology, 1-4 (Aug. 25, 2001). cited by other . | Cham et al., Lipid Apheresis, An In Vivo Application of Plasma Delipidation with Organic Solvents Resulting in Acute Transient Reduction of Circulating Plasma Lipids in Animals, J. Clin. Apheresis, v. 10,61-69. (1995). cited by other . | Eisenhauer et al., Selective Removal of Density Lipoproteins (LDL) by Precipitation at Low pH: First Clinical Application of the HELP System, Klin Wochenschr (KWH), v. 65, 161-168. (1987). cited by other . | Gasparini et al., Peripheral Markers in Testing Pathophysiological Hypotheses and Diagnosing Alzheimer s Disease, FASEB J., v. 12, 17-34 (1998). cited by other . | Cham et al., a Solvent System for Delipidation of Plasma or Serum Without Protein Precipitation, J. of Lipid Research, v. 17, 176-181. (1976). cited by other . | Slater et al., A Comparison of Delipidated Sera Used in Studies of Sterol Synthesis by Human Mononuclear Leukocytes, J. of Lipid Research, v. 20, 413-416 (1979). cited by other . | Golde et al., Cholesterol Modulation as an Emerging Strategy for the Treatment of Alzheimer s Disease, Drug Discovery Today, v. 6(20), 1049-1055 (abstract only) (Oct. 15, 2001). cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/203,551, filed Sep. 3, 2008, Zhu et al. cited by examiner . | Ngu, Human Cancers and Viruses: A Hypothesis for Immune Destruction of Tumours Caused by Certain Enveloped Viruses Using Modified Viral Antigens, Medical Hypotheses, v. 39, 17-21 (1992). cited by other . | Fang et al., 18th Australian Atherosclerosis Society Conference, Gold Coast, Australia, In Vivo Rapid Mobilization of Adipose Tissue by Lipid Apheresis--A Newly Developed Technique, (1992). cited by other . | Moya et al., A Cell Culture System for Screening Human Serum for Ability to Promote Cellular Cholesterol Efflux, Arteriosclerosis and Thrombosis, v. 14(7), 1056-1065 (Jul. 1994). cited by other . | Asztalos et al., Role of Free Apolipoprotein A-I in Cholesterol Efflux, Arteriosclerosis, Thrombosis, and Vascular Biology, v. 17, 1630-1636, (1997). cited by other . | Koudinov et al., Alzheimer s Amyloid Beta Interaction with Normal Human Plasma High Density Lipoprotein: Association with Apolipoprotein and Lipids, Clin. Chim. Acta, v. 270(2), 75-84 (abstract only) (Feb. 23, 1999). cited by other . | Robern, The Application of Sodium Deoxycholate and Sephacryl-200 for the Delipidation and Separation of High Density Lipoprotein, Experientia, v. 38, 437-439 (1982). cited by other . | Mauch et al., CNS Synaptogenesis Promoted by Glia-Derived Cholesterol, Science, v. 294, 1354-1357 (Nov. 9, 2001). cited by other . | Barrans et al., Pre-.beta. HDL, Structure and Metabolism, Biochimica et Biophysica Acta--Lipids and Lipid Metabolism, v. 1300, 73-85 (1996). cited by other . | U.S. Appl. No. 12/054,088, filed Mar. 24, 2008, Bellotti et al. cited by examiner . | Nissen et al., Effect of Recombinant ApoA-1 Milano on Coronary Atherosclerosis in Patients with Acute Coronary syndromes, Journal of American Medical Association, v. 290, 2292-2300 (2003). cited by other . | Koudinova et al., Amyloid Beta, Neural Lipids, Cholesterol and Alzheimer s Disease--Abstract No. 2110, Soc. Neuroscience. Abstract Viewer and Itinerary Planner, (2002). cited by other . | Simons et al., Cholesterol and Alzheimer s Disease: Is There a Link? Neurology, v. 57, 1089-1093 (2001). cited by other . | Kunitake et al., Interconversion between Apolipoprotein A-I-containing Lipoproteins of Pre-beta and Alpha Electrophoretic Mobilities, J. Lipid Res., v. 33(12), 1807-1816 (1992). cited by other . | Matz et al., Reaction of Human Lecithin Cholesterol Acyltransferase with Synthetic Micellar Complexes of Apolipoprotein A-1, Phosphatidylcholine, and Cholesterol, The Journal of Biological Chemistry, v. 257, 4541-4546 (1982). cited by other . | Slater et al., The Effect of Delipidated High Density Lipoprotein on Human Leukocyte Sterol Synthesis, Atherosclerosis, v. 35, 41-49 (1980). cited by other . | Feinstone et al., Inactivation of Hepatits B Virus and Non-A, Non-B Hepatitis by Chloroform, Infection and Immunity, v. 41, 816-821 (Aug. 1983). cited by other . | Koudinov et al., Biochemical Characterization of Alzheimer s Soluble Amyloid Beta Protein in Human Cerebrospinal Fluid: Association with High Density Lipoproteins, Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun., v. 223(3), 592-7 (abstract only) (Jun. 25, 1999). cited by other . | Ngu, Chronic Infections from the Perspective of Evolution: a Hypothesis, Medical Hypotheses, v. 42, 81-88 (1994). cited by other . | Horowitz et al., Viral safety of solvent/detergent-treated blood products, Blood Coagulation and Fibrinolysis, v. 5, S21-S28 (1994). cited by other . | Patern et al., Reconstituted High-Density Lipoprotein Exhibits Neuroprotection in Two Rat Models of Stroke, Cerebrovascular Diseases, v. 17, 204-211 (2004). cited by other . | Walker et al., Escape from Immune System, Nature, v. 407, 313-314 (2000). cited by other . | Ngu, The viral envelope in the evolution of HIV: a hypothetical approach to inducing an effective immune response to the virus, Medical Hypotheses, v. 48, 517-521 (1997). cited by other . | US. Appl. No. 12/042,881, filed Mar. 5, 2008, Bellotti et al. cited by examiner . | Thompson et al., Plasma Exchange in the Management of Homozygous Familial Hypercholesterolaemia, Lancet, v. 305(7918), 1208-1211 (1975). cited by other . | Hatch et al., Practical Methods for Plasma Lipoprotein Analysis, Advances in Lipid Research, v. 6, 61-68 (1968). cited by other . | Koizumi et al., Behavior of Human Apolipoprotein A-1: Phospho-Lipid and apoHDL: Phospholipid Complexes In Vitro and After Injection into Rabbits, J. Lipid Research, v. 29, 1405-1415 (1988). cited by other . | Cham et al., Lipid Apheresis in an Animal Model Causes Acute Reduction in plasma Lipid Concentrations and Mobilisation of Lipid from Liver and Aorta, Pharmacol. (Life Sci. Adv.), v. 13, 25-32 (1994). cited by other . | Andre et al., Characterization of Low- and Very-Low-Density Hepatitis C Virus RNA-Containing Particles, Journal of Virology, v. 76, 6919-6928 (Jul. 2002). cited by other . | Collet et al., Differential Effects of Lecithin and Cholesterol on the Immunoreactivity and Confirmation of Apolipoprotein A-I in High Density Lipoproteins, Journal of Biological Chemistry, v. 266(14), 9145-9152 (May 15, 1991). cited by other . | Osborne et al., Delipidation of Plasma Lipoproteins, Methods in Enzymology, v. 128, 213-222. (1986). cited by other . | Tadey et al., Chromatographic Techniques for the Isolation and Purification of Lipoproteins, Journal of Chromatography B, v. 671, 237-253 (1995). cited by other . | Williams et al., Low Density Lipoprotein Receptor-Independent Hepatic Uptake of a Synthetic, Cholesterol-Scavenging Lipoprotein: Implications for the Treatment of Receptor-Deficient Atherosclerosis, Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA, v. 85, 242-246 (1988). cited by other . | Cooper, Dietary Lipids in the Aetiology of Alzheimer s Disease: Implications for Therapy , Drugs Aging, v. 20(6), 399-418 (abstract only) (2003). cited by other . | Albouz et al., Extraction of Plasma Lipids Preserving Antigenic Properties of Proteins and Allowing Quantitation of Gangliosides by Neuraminic Acid Determination, Ann. Biol. Clin., v. 37, 287-290 (abstract only) (1979). cited by other . | Cham et al., Clinical Chemistry, Phospholipids in EDTA--Treated Plasma and Serum, v. 39, 2347-2348. (1993). cited by other . | Greicius et al., Presenile Dementia Syndrome: An Update on Taxonomy and Diagnosis, Journal of Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. v. 72, 691-700 (2002). cited by other . | Deva et al., Establishment of an in-use testing method for evaluating disinfection of surgical instruments using the duck hepatitis B model , J. Hosp. Infect., v. 22, 119-130. (abstract only) (Jun. 1996). cited by other . | Yoshidome et al. Serum Amyloid A and P Protein Levels are Lowered by Dextran Sulfate Cellulose Low-Density Lipoprotein Apheresis, Artif. Organs, v. 22(2), 144-148 (1998). cited by other . | Cham et al., Rapid, Sensitive Method for the Separation of Free Cholesterol from Ester Cholesterol, Clinica Chimica Acta, v. 49, 109-113 (1973). cited by other . | Asztalos et al., Distribution of Apo A-I-Containing HDL Subpopulations in Patients with Coronary Heart Disease, Arteriosclerosis, Thrombosis, and Vascular Biology, v. 20, 2670-2676 (Dec. 2000). cited by other . | Clay, et. al., Formation of apolipoprotein-specific high-density lipoprotein particles from lipid-free apolipoproteins A-I and A-II, Biochem. J., 337, 445-451 (1999). cited by other . | Rye et al., Changes in the Size of Reconstituted High Density Lipoproteins during Incubation with Cholesteryl Ester transfer protein: the Role of Apolipoproteins, Journal of Lipid Research, v. 33, 215-224 (1992). cited by other . | Durbin et al., The Effect of Apolipoprotein A-II on the Structure and Function of Apolipoprotein A-I in a Homogeneous Reconstituted High Density Lipoprotein Particle, The Journal of Biological Chemistry, v. 272(50), 31333-31339. cited by other . | Blanche et al., Characterization of Complexes of Egg Yolk Phosphatidylcholine and Apolipoprotein A-II Prepared in Absence and Presence of Sodium Cholate, Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, v. 958, 143-152 (1988). cited by other . | Cham et al., 59th Congress European Atherosclerosis Society, Nice, France, Rapid Regression of Atherosclerosis by Cholesterol Apheresis--A Newly Developed Technique, 17-21. (abstract only) (May 1992). cited by other . | Barrans et al., Hepatic Lipase Induces the formation of pre-beta 1 high density lipoprotein (HDL) from triacylglycerol-rich HDL2 A study comparing liver perfusion to in vitro incubation with lipases, J. Biol. Chem., v. 269, 11572-11577 (1994). cited by other . | Koudinov et al., Cell Biol Int, Alzheimer s Soluble Amyloid Beta Protein is Secreted by HepG2 Cells as an Apolipoprotein, v. 21(5), 265-71 (abstract only) (May 1997). cited by other . | Calero et al., Functional and Structural Properties of Lipid-Associated Apolipoprotein J (Clusterin), Biochemical Journal, v. 344, 375-383 (1999. cited by other . | Dass et al., Apolipoprotein A-1, Phospholipid Vesicles, and Cyclodextrins as Potential Anti-Atherosclerotic Drugs: Delivery, Pharmacokinetics, and Efficacy, Drug Delivery, v. 7, 161-182, (2000). cited by other . | Kostner et al., Lecithin-cholesterol acyltransferase activity in Normocholesterolaemic and Hypercholesterolaemic Roosters: Modulation by Lipid Apheresis, European Journal of Clinical Investigation, v. 27, 212-218 (May 7, 1997). cited by other . | Lupien et al., A New Approach to the Management of Familial Hypercholesterolaemia: Removal of Plasma-Cholesterol Based on the Principle of Affinity Chromatography, Lancet, v. 307(7972), 1261-1265, (1976). cited by other . | Cruzado et al., Characterization and Quantitation of the Apoproteins of High-Density Lipoprotein by Capillary Electrophoresis, Analytical Biochemistry, v. 243, Article No. 0487, pp. 100-109 (1996). cited by other . | Klimov et al., Extraction of Lipids from Blood Plasma and Subsequent Introduction of Autologous Delipidized Plasma into the Body as a Possible Means to Treat Atherosclerosis [translation], Kardologiia, v. 18, 23-29 (1978). cited by other . | Durbin et. al, Lipid-free apolipoproteins A-I and A-II Promote Remodeling of Reconstituted High Density Lipoproteins and Altar their Reactivity with Lecithin: Cholesterol Acyltransferase, Journal of Lipid Research, v. 40(12), 2293-302 (1999). cited by other . | Cham et al., Importance of Apolipoproteins in Lipid Metabolism, Chem. Biol. Interactions, v. 20, 263-277 (1978). cited by other . | Scanu et al., Solubility in Aqueous Solutions of Ethanol of the Small Molecular Weight Peptides of the Serum Very Low Density and High Density Lipoproteins: Relevance to the Recovery Problem During Delipidation of Serum Lipoproteins, Analytical Biochemistry,. v. 44, 576-588 (1971). cited by other . | Innerarity et al., Enhanced Binding by Cultured Human Fibroblasts of Apo-E-Containing Lipoproteins as Compared with Low Density Lipoproteins, Biochemistry, v. 17, 1440-1447 (1978). cited by other . | Zetia, http://wwwzetiacom/ezetimibe/zetiahcp/mechanism.sub.--of.sub.--acti- on/indexjsp, Zetia: Compliments Statin with a Unique Mechanism, 1-2 (Aug. 18, 2003). cited by other . | Wong et al., Retention of gangliosides in serum delipidated by diisopropyl ether-1-butanol extraction, Journal of Lipid Research, v. 24, 666-669 (1983). cited by other . | Badimon et al., High Density Lipoprotein Plasma Fractions Inhibit Aortic Fatty Streaks in Cholesterol-Fed Rabbits, Laboratory Investigation, v. 60, 455-461 (1989). cited by other . | Kostner, Beyond LDL-Cholesterol or Enhancing Reverse Cholesterol Transport, Journal fur Kardiologie, No. 7-8, 328-331 (2002). cited by other . | Williams et al., Uptake of Endogenous Cholesterol by a Synthetic Lipoprotein, Biochim Biophys Acta, v. 875(2), 183-194 (Feb. 12, 1986). cited by other . | Zetia, http://wwwzetiacom/ezetimbe/zetia/hcp/product.sub.--highlights/inde- xjsp, Zetia (ezetimibe), 1-2 (Aug. 18, 2003). cited by other . | Parker et al., Plasma High Density Lipoprotein is Increased in Man When Low Density Lipoprotein (LDL) is Lowered by LDL-Pheresis, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, v. 83, 777-781 (1986). cited by other . | Kostner et al., XI Internet Symp. on Drugs Affecting Lipid Metabolism, Italy, Increase of APO A1 Concentration in Hypercholesteraemic Chickens after Treatment with a Newly Developed Extracorpreal Lipid Elimination (May 13, 1992). cited by other . | Haas et al., Apolipoprotein E Forms Stable Complexes with Recombinant Alzheimer s Disease Beta-Amyloid Precursor Protein, Biochemical Journal, v. 325, 169-175 (1997). cited by other . | Cham et al., Lipid Apheresis in an Animal Model Causes In Vivo Changes in Lipoprotein Electrophoretic Patterns, J. Clin. Apheresis, v. 11, 61-70. (1996). cited by other . | Ito et al., Cholesterol-Sphingomyelin Interaction in Membrane and Apolipoprotein-Mediated Cellular Cholesterol Efflux, Journal of Lipid Research, v. 41, 894-904 (2001). cited by other . | Cham et al., Changes in Electrophoretic Mobilities of .alpha.- and .beta.-Lipoproteins as a Result of Plasma Delipidation, Clinical Chemistry, v. 22, 305-309. (1976). cited by other . | Okazaki et al., Improved High-Performance Liquid Chromatographic Method for the Determination of Apolipoproteins in Serum High-Density Lipoproteins, Journal of Chromatography, Biomedical Applications, v. 430, 135-142 (1988). cited by other . | Nakawatase et al., Alzheimer s Disease and Related Dementias , Cecil's Textbook of Medicine (Twenty-First Edition, vol. 1) WB Saunders Company, 2042-2045 (2000). cited by other . | Tricerri et al., Interaction of Apolipoprotein A-1 in Three Different Conformations with Palmitoyl Oleoyl Phosphatidylcholine Vesicles, Journal of Lipid Research, v 43, 187-197 (2002). cited by other . | Asztalos et al., Presence and Formation of Free Apolipoprotein A-I-Like Particles in Human Plasma, Arteriosclerosis, Thrombosis, and Vascular Biology, v. 15, 1419-1423, (1995). cited by other . | Wormser, Henry, Lipids, Slide Presentation--PSC 3110, Fall Semester 2002. cited by other .
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		101
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US8268787
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US5679260 | US5948441 | US6039946 | US4668398 | US4895558 | US20040106556 | US5885578 | US4435289 | US5211850 | US5080796 | US4970144 | US5855782 | US4677057 | US5401466 | US4540401 | US6193891 | US4350156 | US4696670 | US5187010 | US20020081263 | US5698432 | US6046166 | US5911698 | US4540573 | US5256767 | US5916806 | US6022333 | US5116307 | US4613501 | US6337368 | US5391143 | US4391711 | US4909942 | US5529933 | US5928930 | US4909940 | US5418061 | USR39498 | US5853725 | US4311586 | US6472421 | US6080778 | US6136321 | US7375191 | US7393826 | US4402940 | US5258149 | US20080214438 | US20020107173 | US5279540 | US4591505 | US4463988 | US5424068 | US5858238 | US4879037 | US6127370 | US6037458 | US5354262 | US5980478 | US4103685 | US5089602 | US5026479 | US4648974 | US5152743 | US20080234621 | US6156727 | US20020183379 | US4522809 | US4908354 | US5744038 | US5637224 | US4025423 | US4676905 | US4234317 | US3983008 | US6139746 | US6004925 | US5877005 | US4832034 | US4258010 | USR37584 | US6264623 | US5203778 | US6440387 | US3958939 | US6605588 | US5919369 | US4645512 | US5419759 | US5496637 | US5301694 | US20030018013 | US4966709 | US4671909 | US4643718 | US4775483 | US4935204 | US6017543 | US3647624 | US5753227 | US5401415 | US5484396 | US6706008 | US4481189 | US4615886 | US5652339 | US4680320 | US4647280 | US20020055529 | US5055396 | US4124509 | US5707673 | US5393429 | US3989466 | US5895650 | US4923439 | US5523096 | US5126240 | US6309550 | US5236644 | US5634893 | US7361739 | US5128318 | US4836928 | US4399217 | US4235602 | US20010028895 | US5476715 | US20020128581 | US5112956 | US20030127390 | US6037323 | US5719194 | US6171373 | US5962322 | US20020188012 | DE2944138 | WO1988009345 | WO1999038498 | WO2003000372 | WO2003000373 | SU1204224 | WO2002000266 | SU1752187 | WO2001056579 | JP1980127104 | EP0036283 | SU1116396 | EP0267471 | WO1995003840 | CA1271708 | DE3310263 | DE3213390 | CN1189378 | WO2002062824 | WO2002030863 | DE3118072 | FR2571971 | JP1993277303 | WO2002010768 | WO2001045718
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		161
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		HDL THERAPEUTICS
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		HDL THERAPEUTICS
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Shorthills, NJ
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Shorthills, NJ
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		BELLOTTI, MARC | BREWER, JR., H., BRYAN | AKEEFE, HASSIBULLAH | CONNER, ADAM, PAUL | PERLMAN, TIMOTHY, JON
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		BELLOTTI, MARC
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		5
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Coto, de, Caza, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Coto, de, Caza, CA | Potomac, MD | San, Ramon, CA | Livermore, CA | Pleasanton, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		KILPATRICK TOWNSEND &amp; STOCKTON LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		KAM, CHIH-MIN
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

