<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		USR42669
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US09/621234
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Vertical cylindrical skein of hollow fiber membranes and method of maintaining clean fiber surfaces
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A gas-scrubbed vertical cylindrical skein of &quot;fibers&quot; has their opposed terminal portions held in headers unconfined in a modular shell, and aerated with a cleansing gas supplied by a gas-distribution means which produces a mass of bubbles serving the function of a scrub-brush for the outer surfaces of the fibers. The skein is surprisingly effective with relatively little cleansing gas, the specific flux through the membranes reaching an essentially constant relatively high value because the vertical deployment of fibers allows bubbles to rise upwards along the outer surfaces of the fibers. The effectiveness is critically dependent upon the length of each fiber in the skein. That length is in the range from at least 0.1% more than the fixed distance between opposed faces of the skein's headers, but less than 5% greater than the fixed distance. Lack of tension allows the fibers to sway in bubbles flowing along their outer surfaces making them surprisingly resistant to being fouled by buildup of deposits of inanimate particles or microorganisms in the substrate. For use in a large reservoir, a bank of skeins is used with a gas distributor means which has fibers preferably &gt;0.5 meter long, which together provide a surface area &gt;10 m.sup.2. The terminal end portions of fibers in each header are kept free from fiber-to-fiber contact with a novel method of forming a header.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2000-07-20
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2000
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2000-07
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2011-09-06
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2011
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2011-09
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B01D65/02 | B01D61/00 | B01D63/00 | C02F9/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B01D65/02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B01
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B01D
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B01D65
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/636 | 210/257.2 | 210/321.69 | 210/321.8 | 210/321.89 | 210/500.23 | 210/650
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/636
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		&quot;Organic Stabilization and Nitrogen Removal in Membrane Separation Bioreactor for Domestic Wastewater Treatment&quot; by Chiemchaisiri, C. et al, presented at Membrane Technology in Wastewater Management, Cape Town Mar. 2-5, 1992. cited by other | Declaration for Reissue Application executed Jun. 14, 1999 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Amendment dated Jan. 8, 1998 in file history of U.S. Patent No. 5,783,083, incorporated by reference in Declaration for Reissue Application executed Jun. 14, 1999 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Declaration Under 37 CFR 1.132 of Steven Pedersen executed Jan. 5, 1998 in file history of U.S. Patent No. 5,783,083, incorporated by reference in Declaration for Reissue Application executed Jun. 14, 1999 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Declaration Under 37 CFR 1.132 of Kenneth Goodboy executed Dec. 27, 1997 in file history of U.S. Patent No. 5,783,083, incorporated by reference in Declaration for Reissue Application executed Jun. 14, 1999 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Office Action mailed Nov. 5, 1999 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Supplemental Declaration for Reissue Application executed Mar. 3, 2000 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Amendment dated Mar. 4, 2000in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Supplemental Amendment dated Mar. 20, 2000 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Office Action mailed Mar. 31, 2000 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Amendment dated May 9, 2000 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Third Supplemental Declaration for Reissue Application executed May 8, 2000 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Notice of Allowability dated Jun. 1, 2000 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Supplemental Declaration for Reissue Application executed Nov. 7, 2000 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Preliminary Amendment dated Nov. 6, 2000 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Office Action mailed Feb. 6, 2001 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Amendment dated May 4, 2001 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Notice of Allowability dated May 29, 2001 in File history of U.S. Patent No. Re. 37,549. cited by other | Kaiya et al., &quot;Water Purification Using Hollow Fiber Microfiltration Membranes&quot;, 6.sup.th World Filtration Congress, Nagoya, 1993, pp. 813-816. cited by other | &quot;Direct Solid-Liquid Separation Using Hollow Fiber Membrane in an Activated Sludge Aeration Tank&quot; by K. Yamamoto; M. Hiasa; T. Mahmood and T. Matsuo; Wat. Sci. Tech. vol. 21, Brighton, pp. 43-54 (1989). cited by other | &quot;Organic Stabilization And Nitrogen Removal In Membrane Separation Bioreactor For Domestic Wastewater Treatment&quot; by C. Chiemchaisri, Y.K. Wong, T. Urase and K. Yamamoto, presented at Membrane Technology in Wastewater Management, Cape Town, Mar. 2-5, 1992. cited by other | &quot;Optimal fiber spacing in externally pressurized hollow fiber module for solid liquid separation&quot;, by Kiat, Yamoto et al., Water Science Technology vol. 26, pp. 1245-1254, (1992). cited by other | &quot;Household membrane bioreactor in domestic wastewater treatment&quot;, by Chiemchaisri et al. Water Science Technology vol. 27, No. 1, pp. 171-178, (1993). cited by other | &quot;Organic wastewater treatment by activated sludge process using integrated type membrane separation&quot;, by Futamura et al. Proceedings IDA and WRPC World Conference on Desalination and Water Treatment, Nov. 1993, vol. 1, pp. 223-230. cited by other | &quot;Integrated membrane-filtration activated-sludge wastewater treatment system&quot;, by Onishi and FutamuraProceedings 1994 MIE International Forum and Symposium on Global Environment and Friendly energy Technology, pp. 365-368. cited by other | &quot;Integrated membrane filtration activated sludge wastewater treatment system&quot;, International Symposium on Fibre Science and Technology (ISF'94), Yokohama, Oct. 1994. cited by other | Nitto Denko Corp, English Abstract of JP 07227526, Aug. 29, 1995. cited by other | Hitachi Plant Eng &amp; Constr Co Ltd, English Abstract of JP 2003205287, Jul. 22, 2003. cited by other | Shin Etsu Chem Co Ltd., English Abstract of JP 05125543, May 21, 1993. cited by other | Mitsubishi Rayon Co Ltd, English Abstract of JP 3283008, May 20, 2002. cited by other | Mitsui Constr, English Abstract of JP 6246264, Sep. 6, 1994. cited by other | Mitsubishi Rayon Co, English Abstract of JP 7024264, Jan. 27, 1995. cited by other | Mitsubishi Rayon Co Ltd, English Abstract of JP 07178321, Jul. 18, 1995. cited by other | Nitto Denko Corp, English Abstract of JP 07031853, Feb. 3, 1995. cited by other | Toshiba Corp, English Abstract of JP 05015892, Jan. 26, 1993. cited by other | Mitsubishi Rayon Eng Co Ltd, English Abstract of JP 62155906, Jul. 10, 1987. cited by other | Kubota Corp, English Abstract of JP 05123540, May 21, 1993. cited by other | Nippon Electric Co, English Abstract of JP 3131092, Jun. 4, 1991. cited by other | Mitsubishi Rayon Co Ltd, English Abstract of JP 07024267, Jan. 27, 1995. cited by other | Mitsubishi Rayon Co, English Abstract of JP 7178320, Jul. 18, 1995. cited by other | Aqua Renaissance Gijutsu, English Abstract of JP 2095422, Apr. 6, 1990. cited by other | Kubota KK, English Abstract of JP 5123543, May 21, 1993. cited by other | Sanki Eng Co Ltd, English of JP 5220357, Aug. 31, 1993. cited by other | Kubota Corp, English Abstract of JP 0306846, Mar. 25, 1991. cited by other | United States District Court, Southern District of California, CV No. 03-CV-1996W-JFS, &quot;Complaint for Patent Infringement; Demand for Jury Trial&quot;, Oct. 8, 2003. cited by other | United States District Court, Southern District of California, CV No. 03-CV-1996B-AJB, &quot;Defendant United States Filter Corporation's First Amended Answer To Complaint and Counterclaims&quot;, Jan. 12, 2005. cited by other | United States District Court, Southern District of California, CV No. 03-CV-1996B-(AJB), &quot;Order Construing Claims For U.S. Patent No. 6,620,319&quot;, Nov. 8, 2004. cited by other | United States District Court, Southern District of California, CV No. 03-CV-1996B-(AJB), &quot;Decision on Bifurcated Trial of Issue of Invalidity of U.S. Patent No. 6,620,319&quot;, May 3, 2005. cited by other | Opinions in United States Court of Appeal for the Federal Circuit 2006, 1266-1267, Decided Nov. 7, 2007. cited by other | C. Chiemchaisri et al. &quot;Effect of Temperature on Nitrogen Removal in Membrane Separation Bioreactor&quot;, International Membrane Science and Technology Conference, Nov. 10-12, 1992. cited by other | S. Vigneswaran, et al., &quot;Membrane Bioreactor in Domestic Wastewater Treatment a Benchscale Study&quot;, International Membrane Science and Technology Conference, Nov. 10-12, 1992. cited by other | S. Vigneswaran, et al., &quot;Application of Microfiltration for Water and Wastewater Treatment&quot;, Environmental Sanitation Information Center, Asian Institute of Technology, Jun. 1991. cited by other | J.A. Howell, et al., &quot;Yeast Cell Microfiltration: Flux Enhancement in Baffled and Pulsatile Flow Systems&quot;, Journal of Membrane Science, 80 (1993) 59-71. cited by other | C.D. Bertram, et al., &quot;Flux Enhancement in Crossflow Microfiltraction Using a Collapsible-tube Pulsation Generator&quot;, Journal of Membrane Science, 84 (1993) 279-292. cited by other | Osamu Futamura, Masuo Katoh, Joyosi Takeuchi, Organic Waste Water Treatment by Activated Sludge Process Using Integrated Type Membrane Separation, (Desalination), Issue. 98, 1994, pp. 17-25. cited by other | Richard G. Sudak, William R. Dunivin. Pilot Plant Testing of Direct Filtration, Microfiltration, and Reverse Osmosis at Water Factory 21. National Water Research Institute: Microfiltration for Water Treatment Symposium. Aug. 25 and 26, 1994. Irvine, California. cited by other | Yoshio Taniguchi. State of the Art of Microfiltration Technology for Drinking Water and Waste Water Treatment in Japan. Aug. 1994, pp. 13-22. Japan. cited by other | Takaaki Tanaka, Hiroshi Itoh, Kazutaka Itoh, Kazuhiro Nakanishi, Takaaki Kume, Ryuichi Matsuno, Crossflow Filtration of Baker's Yeast with Periodical Stopping of Permeation Flow and Bubbling Biotechnology and Engineering, vol. 47, No. 3, pp. 401-404 (Aug. 5, 1995). cited by other.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		58
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US2570132 | US3551331 | US3637079 | US3704223 | US3708071 | US3730959 | US3794169 | US3853756 | US3992301 | US4002567 | US4075100 | US4176063 | US4184963 | US4206055 | US4253962 | US4401567 | US4411785 | US4414113 | US4466888 | US4537740 | US4540490 | US4605500 | US4610792 | US4647377 | US4655927 | US4668401 | US4707268 | US4746433 | US4755305 | US4756875 | US4765915 | US4767539 | US4775471 | US4842724 | US4876006 | US4880545 | US4886601 | US4915833 | US4931186 | US4935143 | US4980066 | US5024762 | US5034125 | US5035799 | US5043071 | US5053143 | US5104535 | US5141031 | US5151191 | US5182019 | US5192456 | US5202023 | US5209852 | US5227076 | US5232593 | US5248424 | US5366625 | US5380437 | US5403479 | US5409609 | US5451317 | US5468397 | US5472607 | US5480533 | US5484528 | US5584997 | US5607593 | US5639373 | US5643455 | US5647988 | US5690830 | US5695702 | US5783083 | US5910250 | US5922201 | US5932099 | US5944997 | US6042677 | US6045698 | US6156200 | US6193890 | US6214226 | US6214231 | US6280626 | US6284135 | US6294039 | US6303035 | US6319411 | US6325928 | US6325938 | USR37549 | US6402955 | US6555005 | US6589426 | US6620319 | US6627082 | US6630069 | US6706189 | US6969465 | US7087173 | USR39294 | US20020195390 | DE19502516 | DE10045227 | EP0388546 | EP0427376 | EP0598909 | EP0734758 | EP1213048 | GB2120952 | JP38884S63 | JP1986107905 | JP1986157306 | JP1986167407 | JP1986192309 | JP1986197005 | JP1986242607 | JP1986263605 | JP1986291007 | JP1986293504 | JP1987004408 | JP1987114609 | JP1987144712 | JP1987155906 | JP1987201610 | JP1987250908 | JP1988143905 | JP1988175605 | JP1990293093 | JP1989293103 | JP1990095422 | JP1990164423 | JP1991000114 | JP1991068426 | JP1991131092 | JP1991131324 | JP1991284397 | JP1992126528 | JP1992131182 | JP1992180821 | JP1992197487 | JP1992247295 | JP1992250898 | JP1993015892 | JP1993285348 | JP1993123540 | JP1993123543 | JP1993125543 | JP1993154362 | JP1993154476 | JP1993184884 | JP1993220357 | JP1993285349 | JP1995136470 | JP1994023245 | JP1994218237 | JP1994218238 | JP1994218361 | JP1994246264 | JP1994277664 | JP1994285496 | JP1994343837 | JP1995000770 | JP1995024264 | JP1995024267 | JP1995024272 | JP1995031853 | JP1995047245 | JP1995116482 | JP1995132213 | JP1995136471 | JP1995178320 | JP1995178321 | JP1995185268 | JP1995227526 | JP1995275665 | JP1995289860 | JP1996010585 | JP1996131785 | JP1996206472 | JP1996215548 | JP1996252438 | JP1996257372 | JP1996281082 | JP1996318141 | JP1997075689 | JP1997138298 | JP1997141063 | JP1997220569 | JP1997239246 | JP1997248432 | JP1997290261 | JP1997308882 | JP1998015365 | JP1998118470 | JP1998277599 | JP1999047562 | JP1999090190 | JP1999156166 | JP2000237548 | JP2000288575 | JP2000300965 | JP2002066269 | JP3283008 | JP2003053159 | JP2003053160 | JP2003205287 | JP2003251158 | JP2003320400 | JP2003340497 | SU1692626 | WO1985001449 | WO1986005116 | WO1986005697 | WO1986005997 | WO1988000494 | WO1990011120 | WO1993002779 | WO1993023152 | WO1994011094 | WO1996007470 | WO1997006880 | WO1997045193 | WO1998028066 | WO2001021531
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		225
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		ZENON TECHNOLOGY PARTNERSHIP
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		ZENON TECHNOLOGY PARTNERSHIP
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Wilmington, DE
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Wilmington, DE
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		HENSHAW, WAYNE, JERALD | MAHENDRAN, MAILVAGANAM | BEHMANN, HENRY
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		HENSHAW, WAYNE, JERALD
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Burlington, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Burlington, CA | Mississauga, CA | Puslinch, CA
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		PUNDSACK, SCOTT BORDEN LADNER GERVAIS LLP
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		FORTUNA, ANA M
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

