<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		USR40448
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		US10/862126
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		E1
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		Method for remediation of aquifers
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A method for remediating aquifers and groundwater contaminated, for example by toxic halogenated organic compounds, certain inorganic compounds, and oxidized heavy metals and radionuclides, using the introduction of an innocuous oil, preferably an edible, food grade oil such as soybean oil, formulated into a microemulsion preferably by mixing with a natural food-grade emulsifier (such as lecithin) and water.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		US | USB | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2004-06-04
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2004
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2004-06
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2008-08-05
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2008-08
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		C02F1/26 | C02F3/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		C02F1/26
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		C
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		C02
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		C02F
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		C02F1
	</str>
	<str name="All UPC">
		210/610 | 166/296 | 166/305.1 | 166/310 | 210/747.7 | 405/128.45 | 405/128.5 | 405/129.45 | 435/262.5
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Primary">
		210/610
	</str>
	<str name="UPC Class">
		210
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		EP1315675A1 | CA2394068A1 | CA2394068C | AU1662702A | DE60119549D1 | ES2259340T3 | AU782548B2 | AU782548C | USR40734 | USR40448 | EP1315675A4 | DE60119549T2 | DE60119549T4 | EP1315675B1 | WO2002036498A1 | US6398960 | AT325779T | DK1315675T3 | DK1315675T5
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		19
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		18
	</str>
	<str name="Other References">
		Susan M. Froud et al. &quot;Sequential Treatment Using Abiotic Reductive Dechlorination and Enhanced Bioremediation&quot;. Accelerated Bioremediation Using Slow Release Compounds, Selected Battelle Conference Papers, 1993-1999, pp. 47-52. cited by other | Ronald L. Lewis, et al. &quot;Sequential Anaerobic/Aerobic Biodegradation of Chlorinated Solvents: Pilot-Scale Filed Demonstration&quot;. Accelerated Bioremediation Using Slow Release Compounds, Selected Battelle Conference Papers, 1993-1999, pp. 75-81. cited by other | R.E. Beeman, J.E. Howell, S.H. Shoemaker, E.A. Salazar and J.R. Butram. &quot;A Field Evaluation of in Situ Microbial Reductive Dehalogenation By the Biotransformation of Chlorinated Ethenes&quot; Bioremediation of Chlorinated and PAH Compounds pp. 14-27. cited by other | Kent J. Boulicault, Robert E. Hinchee, Todd H. Wiedemeir, Scott W. Hoxworth, Todd P. Swingle, Ed Carver and Patrick E. Haas &quot;Vegoil: A Novel Approach for Stimulating Reductive Dechlorination&quot; Bioremediation and Phytoremediation pp. 1-7. cited by other | Michael J. Dybas, Gregory M. Tatara, Michael E. Witt and Craig S. Criddle. &quot;Slow-Release Substrates for Transformation of Carbon Tetrachloride by Pseudomonas Strain KC&quot; Anaerobic Degradation of Chlorinated Solvents p. 59. cited by other | Mark R. Harkness &quot;Economic Considerations in Enhanced Anaerobic Biodegradation&quot; Bioremediation and Phytoremediation, Battelle Press, 2000, pp. 9-14. cited by other | S. Kallur and S. Koenigsberg &quot;Enhanced Bioremediation of Chlorinated Solvents--A Single Well Pilot Study&quot; pp. 123-126.. IN: A. Leeson &amp; B.C. Alleman (eds.), Engineered Approaches for In Situ Bioremediation of Chlorinated Solvent Contamination. 1999 Batelle Press. cited by other | Stephen S. Koenigsberg, William A. Farone, and Craig A. Sandefur. &quot;Time-Release Electron Donor Technology for Accelerated Biological Reductive Dechlorination&quot; Bioremediation and Phytoremediation pp 39-46 Battelle Press, 2000. cited by other | M.D. Lee, J.M. Thomas, R.C. Borden, P.B. Bedient, C.H. Ward, and J.T. Wilson. &quot;Biorestoration of Aquifers Contaminated with Organic Compounds&quot; CRC Critical Reviews in Environmental Control vol. 18, Issue 1 (1988) pp. 29-89. cited by other | Michael D. Lee, Bob Borden, Tony Lieberman, Walt Beckwith, Terry Crotwell and Patrick E. Haas &quot;Effective Distribution of Edible Oils--Results from Five Field Applications&quot;. Accelerated Bioremediation Using Slow Release Commands. Selected Battelle Conference Papers (2001). cited by other | Michael D. Lee and John W. Davis. &quot;Natural Remediation of Chlorinated Organic Compounds&quot; 2000 Society of Environmental Toxicology and Chemistry (SETAC) pp. 199-245. cited by other | M.D. Lee, G.E. Quinton, R.E. Beeman, A.A. Biehle, R.I. Liddle, E.E. Ellis, and R.J. Buchanan, Jr. &quot;Scale-Up Issues for in situ Anaerobic Tetrachloroethene Bioremediation&quot; Journal of Industrial Microbiology and Biotechnology (1997) 18, pp. 106-115. cited by other | Clayton D. McAuliffe. &quot;Oil-In-Waste Emulsions and Their Flow Properties in Porous Media&quot;, Journal of Petroleum Technology. Jun. 1973, pp. 727-733. cited by other | David D. Nelson and Bryan Burkingstock. &quot;Enhanced Bioremediation Treatment Treatability Study at the Memphis Depot, Memphis, Tennessee: Comparison of Two Electron Donors in a Fluvial Aquifer&quot;. US Army Corps of Engineers. (2003). cited by other | Ying Ouyang, Robert S. Mansell and R. Dean Rhue. &quot;Flow of Gasoline-In-Water Microemulsion Through Water-Saturated Soil Columns&quot; Florida Agric.Exp. Stn. Journal No. R-04129 pp. 399-406. (Feb. 1994). cited by other | Thea T. Schuhmacher, William A. Bow and John P. Chitwood &quot;A Field Demonstration Showing Enhanced Reductive Dechlorination Using Polymer Injection&quot; Bioremediation and Phytoremediation pp. 15-23. cited by other | H. Soo and C.J. Radke. &quot;Velocity Effects in Emulsion Flow Through Porous Media&quot;. Journal of Colloid and Interface Science, vol. 102, No. 2, Dec. 1984, pp. 462-476. cited by other | H. Soo, M.C. Williams and C.J. Radke. &quot;A Filtration Model for the Flow of Dilute, Stable Emulsions in Porous Media--II. Paramater Evaluation and Estimation&quot;. Chemical Engineering Science, vol. 41, No. 2, pp. 263-272, Pergamon Press, Ltd. 1986. cited by other | H. Soo and C.J. Radke. &quot;Flow of Dilute, Stable Liquid and Solid Dispersions in Underground Porous Media&quot; AlChE Journal. (vol. 31, No. 11) pp. 1926-1928. Nov. 1985. cited by other | Hawalli Soo and Clayton J. Radke. &quot;The Flow Mechanism of Dilute, Stable Emulsions in Porous Media&quot;. Ind.Eng.Chem.Fundam. 1984, 23, pp. 342-347. cited by other | Matthew J. Zenker, Robert C. Borden, Morton A. Barlaz, M. Tony Lieberman, and Michael D. Lee. &quot;Insoluble Substrates for Reductive Dehalogenation in Permeable Reactive Barriers&quot; Bioremediation and Phytoremediation. pp. 47-53, Batelle Press, 2000. cited by other | Michael D. Lee, Ron J. Buchanan, Jr., and David E. Ellis. &quot;Laboratory Studies Using Edible Oils to Support Reductive Dechlorinaton&quot;. Bioremediation and Phytoremediation. pp. 77-85 Battelle Press, 2000. cited by other | Hawaili Soo. &quot;Flow of Dilute, Stable Emulsions in Porous Media&quot; 1974 Thesis, Tunghai University. Dissertation for PhD in Chemical Engineering, Graduate Division of the University Of California, Berkley. cited by other | Stephen Koenigsberg, et al. &quot;Using Soled (sic) Peroxygen in the Bioremediation of Chlorinated Hydrocarbons and Fuel Oxygenates&quot;. Accelerated Bioremediation Using Slow Release Compounds. Selected Battelle Conference Papers 1993-1999, p. 85. cited by other | Maureen A. Dooley, et al. &quot;Passively Enhanced In Situ Biodegradation of Chlorinated Solvents&quot;. Accelerated Bioremediation Using Slow Release Compounds. Selected Battelle Conference Papers 1993-1999, pp. 111-117. cited by other | Perry L. McCarty, et al. &quot;Ground-Water Treatment for Chlorinated Solvents&quot;. Handbook of Bioremediation. Lewis Publishers, 1994, CRC Press, Inc. pp. 87-116. cited by other | David C. Herman, et al. &quot;Microbial-Mediated Reduction of Perchlorate in Groundwater&quot;. Journal of Environmental Quality 27 No. 4, pp. 750-754. Jul./Aug. 1998. cited by other | Christof Holliger. &quot;The Anaerobic Microbiology and Biotreatment of Chlorinated Ethenes&quot;. Current Opinion in Biotechnology. 1995, 6:347-351. cited by other | Article entitled &quot;Enhanced Bioremediation Of Chlorinated Solvents--A Single Well Pilot Study&quot;, by s. Kallur et al., published in &quot;Accelerated Bioremediation Using Slow Release Compounds&quot;, Selected Battelle Conference Papers 1993-1999, pp. 123-126. cited by examiner | Article entitled &quot;The Anaerobic Microbiology And Biotreatment Of Chlorinated Ethenes&quot;, by Christof Holliger, published in &quot;Environmental Biotechnology&quot;, (1995) 6:347-351. cited by examiner | Article entitled &quot;Using Soled Peroxygen In The Bioremediation Of Chlorinated Hydrocarbons And Fuel Oxygenates&quot;, by Stephen Koenigsberg et al., published in &quot;Accelerated Bioremediation Using Slow Release Compounds&quot;, Selected Battelle Conference Papers 1993-1999, p. 85. cited by examiner | Article entitled &quot;Passively Enhanced In Situ Biodegradation Of Chlorinated Solvents&quot;, by Maureen A. Dooley, et al. published in &quot;Accelerated Bioremediation Using Slow Release Compounds&quot;, Selected Battelle Conference Papers 1993-1999, pp. 111-117. cited by examiner | Article entitled &quot;Insoluble Substrates For Reductive Dehalogenation In Permeable Reactive Barriers&quot;, by Matthew J. Zenker et al., pubished in &quot;Bioremediation And Phytoremediation Of Chlorinated And Recalcirant Compounds&quot;, May 22-25, 2000, Battelle Press, pp. 47-53. cited by examiner | Article &quot;Vegoil: A Novel Approach For Stimulating Reductive Dechlorinbation&quot;, by Kent J. Boulicault et al., published in &quot;Bioremediation And Phytoremediation Of Chlorinated And Recalcitrant Compounds&quot;, May 22-25, 2000, Battelle Press pp. 1-7. cited by examiner | Article &quot;Laboratory Studies Using Edible Oils To Support Reductive Dechlorination&quot;, by Michael D. Lee et al, published in Bioremediation And Phytoremediation Of Chlorinated And Recalcitrate Compounds, May 22-25, 2000, Battelle Press, pp. 77-85. cited by examiner | Article &quot;A Field Demonstration Showing Enhanced Reductive Dechlorination Using Polymer Injection&quot;, by Thea T. Schuhmacher et al., published in &quot;Bioremediation And Phytoremediation Of Chlorinated And Recalcitrate Recalcitrate Compounds&quot;, May 22-25, 2000, Battelle Press, pp. 15-23. cited by examiner | Article &quot;Time-Release Electron Donor Technology For Accelerated Biological Reductive Dechlorination&quot;, by Stephen s. Koenigsberg et al., published in &quot;Bioremediation And Phytoremediation Of Chlorinated And Recalcitrant Compounds&quot;, May 22-25, 2000, Battelle Press, pp. 39-46. cited by examiner | Article entitled &quot;Economic Considerations In Enhanced Anaerobic Biodegradation&quot;, by Mark R. Harkness, published in &quot;Bioremediation And Phytoremediation Of Chlorinated And Recalcitrant Compounds&quot;, May 22-25, 2000 Battelle Press, pp. 9-14. cited by examiner | Article entitled &quot;Ground--Water Treatment For Chlorinated Solvents&quot;, by Perry L. McCarty et al., published in &quot;Handbook Of Bioremediation&quot;, Lewis Publishers, 1994, CRC Press, Inc, pp. 87-116. cited by examiner | Article entitled &quot;A Field Evaluation Of In Sity Microbial Reductive Dehalogenation By The Biotransformation Of Chlorinated Ethenes&quot;, by R.E. Beeman et al., published in &quot;Bioremediation Of Chlorinated And Polycyclic Aromatic Hydrocarbon Compounds&quot;, by Lewis Publishers, 1994, CRC Press, Inc., pp.14-27. cited by examiner | Article entitled &quot;Slow-Release Substrates For Transformation Of Carbon Tetrachloride By Pseudomonas Strain KC&quot;, by Michael J. Dybas et al., published in In Situ And On-Site Bioremediation: vol. 3, Apr. 28-May 1, 1997, Battelle Press, p. 59. cited by examiner | Article entitled &quot;Microbial-Mediated Reduction Of Perchlorate In Groundwater&quot;, by David C. Herman et al., published in &quot;Journal Of Environmental Quality&quot;, 27:750-754 (1998). cited by examiner | Article entitled &quot;Scale-Up Issues For In Situ Anaerobic Tetrachloreathene Bioremediation&quot;, by M. D. Lee et al., published in &quot;Journal Of Industrial Microbiology &amp; Biotechnology&quot;, (1997) 18, pp. 106-115. cited by examiner.
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		43
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By">
		US7785468
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		US3628607 | US3846290 | US4401569 | US4755304 | US4997313 | US5265674 | US5277815 | US5531895 | US5554290 | US5632715 | US5710361 | US5725470 | US5840571 | US5888396 | US5993660 | US6001252 | US6059973 | US6110372 | US6143177 | US6150157 | US6196765 | US6267888 | US6280533 | US6420594
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		24
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		US | US
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		70253300 | 86212604
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2000-10-31 | 2004-06-04
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		SOLUTIONS-IES, INC. (RALEIGH, NC) TERRA SYSTEMS, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		SOLUTIONS-IES, INC. (RALEIGH, NC) TERRA SYSTEMS, INC.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Wilmington, DE
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Wilmington, DE
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s)">
		BORDEN, ROBERT, C. | LEE, MICHAEL, D.
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor">
		BORDEN, ROBERT, C.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Inventors">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Inventor Address">
		Raleigh, NC
	</str>
	<str name="Inventor(s) Address">
		Raleigh, NC | Wilmington, DE
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		OLIVE &amp; OLIVE, P.A.
	</str>
	<str name="Primary Examiner">
		UPTON, CHRISTOPHER
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

