<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		WO2008038763A1
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		PCT/JP2007/068959
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		A1
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		SWIRLING FLOW PRODUCING APPARATUS, METHOD OF PRODUCING SWIRLING FLOW, VAPOR PHASE GENERATING APPARATUS, MICROBUBBLE GENERATING APPARATUS, FLUID MIXER AND FLUID INJECTION NOZZLE
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A swirling flow producing apparatus and method of producing a swirling flow that are applicable to all types of fluids and can realize efficient generation of high-velocity swirling flow; and a relevant vapor phase generating apparatus, microbubble generating apparatus, fluid mixer and fluid injection nozzle. The swirling flow producing apparatus comprises a housing provided with a cylindrical space area having at least its one end portion open and with a fluid introduction channel open at the inner circumferential surface of the cylindrical space area; and a cylindrical member provided with a cylindrical space area disposed in the cylindrical space area of the housing and having at least its end portion in the direction agreeing with the opening direction of the cylindrical space area open and with a hole portion open at the circumferential wall of the cylindrical space area, so that any liquid fluid introduced from the fluid introduction channel is caused to flow through the hole portion into the cylindrical space area of the cylindrical member to thereby generate a swirling flow and flow out from the housing and the cylindrical member.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		WO | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2007-09-28
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2007
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2007-09
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2008-04-03
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2008
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2008-04
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		B05B1/34 | B01F5/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		B05B1/34
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		B05
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		B05B
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		B05B1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		KR1020090028835A | WO2008038763A1 | CN101505859A | US20090201761A1 | EP2067524A1
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		5
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		1
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		JP60041565A | US4474477 | US4390284 | JP2001187326A | JP4227836A | JP53016911U | WO0197958A1 | JP2002143658A | JP53096268A | JP11028389A | JP2006122813A | JP2006116365A | JP2006159187A
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		13
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		JP
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		2006264652
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2006-09-28
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		NAKATA COATING CO. LTD. | MATSUNO, TAKEMI | NAKATA, AKIO
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		NAKATA COATING CO. LTD.
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		3
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		2400041, 2400041, JP
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		2400041, 2400041, JP | 2400041, 2400041, JP | 2400041, 2400041, JP
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		EMORI, KENJI
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>

