<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		WO2010140775A3
	</str>

	<str name="Application Number">
		PCT/KR2010/002811
	</str>

	<str name="Kind Code">
		A3
	</str>

	<str name="Title">
		MICROBUBBLE-GENERATING SHOWER
	</str>

	<str name="Abstract">
		The present invention relates to a microbubble-generating shower. The present invention provides a microbubble-generating shower comprising a showerhead, a bubble nozzle, and a spray nozzle. The shower head is integrally formed with an upper portion of a shower body in which a tap water flow channel is formed, and has an insertion portion which penetrates through the shower head and which is connected to the water flow channel. The insertion portion has one surface on which an inclined guide portion is formed to raise the pressure of the tap water. The insertion portion has a front end on which a threaded coupling portion is formed. The bubble nozzle is inserted and fixed in the insertion portion of the showerhead, and generates microbubbles consisting of micrometer-sized ultra-micro-sized air bubbles from the dissolved oxygen in the tap water using the pressure of the tap water, pressure resistance, and friction resistance to maximize tap water purifying and sterilizing effects. The spray nozzle is coupled to the coupling portion of the showerhead, and has a plurality of spray ports coupled to the bubble nozzle to spray tap water containing the microbubbles generated by the bubble nozzle. The bubble nozzle of the present invention generates microbubbles using the friction resistance and pressure resistance resulting from the variations in the pressure of the tap water, the expansion of water, and dissolved oxygen, etc., thereby maximizing tap water purifying and sterilizing effects, and thus preventing various skin diseases such as pruritus, allergies, atopies and the like caused by the harmful bacteria contained in tap water.
	</str>

	<str name="Document Types">
		WO
	</str>

	<str name="Application Date">
		2010-05-03
	</str>

	<str name="Application Year">
		2010
	</str>

	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2010-05
	</str>

	<str name="Publication Date">
		2010-12-09
	</str>

	<str name="Publication Year">
		2010
	</str>

	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2010-12
	</str>

	<str name="All IPC">
		A47K3/28 | B01F3/04 | B01F5/00 | B05B1/18
	</str>

	<str name="IPC Primary">
		A47K3/28
	</str>

	<str name="IPC Section">
		A
	</str>

	<str name="IPC Class">
		A47
	</str>

	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		A47K
	</str>

	<str name="IPC Group">
		A47K3
	</str>

	<str name="Family Member Count">
		0
	</str>

	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>

	<str name="Other References Count">
		0
	</str>

	<str name="Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>

	<str name="Priority Country">
		KR
	</str>

	<str name="Priority Number">
		1020090048725
	</str>

	<str name="Priority Date">
		2009-06-02
	</str>

	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		(&#51452;)&#50656;&#51060;&#50472; | &#44608;&#54788;&#50864;
	</str>

	<str name="1st Assignee">
		(&#51452;)&#50656;&#51060;&#50472;
	</str>

	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		2
	</str>

	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		&#51064;&#52380; &#45224;&#46041;&#44396; &#44256;&#51092;&#46041; 718-12 143&#48660;&#47085;14&#47215;&#53944;, 405-819 Incheon 405-819 KR
	</str>

	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		(&#51452;)&#50656;&#51060;&#50472; | &#44608;&#54788;&#50864;
	</str>

	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>

	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>
