<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<doc>
	<str name="Patent Number">
		WO2004055738A1
	</str>
	<str name="Application Number">
		PCT/NO2003/000421
	</str>
	<str name="Kind Code">
		A1
	</str>
	<str name="Title">
		DEVICES FOR COMBINED ACCESS AND INPUT
	</str>
	<str name="Abstract">
		A portable or embedded access device is provided for being coupled to, and for allowing only authorized users access to, an access-limited apparatus, device, network or system, e.g. a computer terminal, an internet bank or a corporate or government intranet. The access device comprises an integrated circuit (IC) (1) providing increased security by bridging the functionality of fingerprint input from a user and, upon positive authentication of the user&amp;apos;s fingerprint to provide secure communication with the said access-limited apparatus, device, network or system. A corresponding method of using the portable device the embedded device is disclosed for providing a bridge from biometrics input to a computer, into secure communication protocol responses to a non-biometrics network.An embedded access control and user input device or apparatus for being a built-in part of stand alone appliances with some form of access control, e.g. hotel safes, medicine cabinet or the like, and for providing increased security, is also provided. Further, a method of providing secured access control and user input in stand-alone appliances having an embedded access control or user input device according to the invention is also explained.
	</str>
	<str name="Document Types">
		WO | DOCDB
	</str>
	<str name="Application Date">
		2003-12-17
	</str>
	<str name="Application Year">
		2003
	</str>
	<str name="Application(Year/Month)">
		2003-12
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Date">
		2004-07-01
	</str>
	<str name="Publication Year">
		2004
	</str>
	<str name="Publication(Year/Month)">
		2004-07
	</str>
	<str name="All IPC">
		G06K9/00 | G07C9/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Primary">
		G06K9/00
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Section">
		G
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Class">
		G06
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Subclass">
		G06K
	</str>
	<str name="IPC Group">
		G06K9
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members">
		NO318168B1 | AU2003291779A1 | WO2004055738A1 | NO20026097D0
	</str>
	<str name="Family Member Count">
		4
	</str>
	<str name="Family Members Cited By Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Other References Count">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="Cites">
		EP1168137A1 | US6484260 | EP0924656A2 | WO0201328A2 | EP1241553A1
	</str>
	<str name="Cites Count">
		5
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Country">
		NO
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Number">
		20026097
	</str>
	<str name="Priority Date">
		2002-12-18
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s)">
		MATHIASSEN, SVEIN | MATHIASSEN, IVAR
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee">
		MATHIASSEN, SVEIN
	</str>
	<str name="Number of Assignees">
		2
	</str>
	<str name="1st Assignee Address">
		Homansbyveien 4, N-1389 Heggedal, NO
	</str>
	<str name="Assignee(s) Address">
		Homansbyveien 4, N-1389 Heggedal, NO | Gaupeveien 21, N-8515 Narvik, NO
	</str>
	<str name="Agent/Attorney">
		ABC-PATENT, SIVILING. ROLF CHR. B. LARSEN A.S, POSTBOKS 6150 ETTERSTAD, N-0602 OSLO, NO
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 3 years">
		0
	</str>
	<str name="cited by within 5 years">
		0
	</str>
</doc>
